<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482</link>
    <description>Every now and then, among the struggles and the giggles, axoman manages to shock the community by looking a heck of a lot more intelligent on the forum than he could ever manage in the flesh.  Today is such a momentous occasion, for today, axoman talks about FPGAs, something which axoman believes the ideal Axoloti should be based around.

As a user, ask yourself, how many times have you wanted to do something but are quickly brought down to earth when you realise that your expectations greatly exceed the physical capabilities of the hardware?  And how many times, I wonder, has @johannes sat there scratching his head thinking, hey ARM, that was a really dumbass way to design a processor, cause it would have been so much better if you had dedicated this to more outputs and that to something else.

Well, the answer to all these problems appears to be FPGA technology.  FPGA stands for Field Programmable Gate Array, which for those of you not as intelligent as axoman, basically means it&#39;s a completely programmable chip architecture.  It&#39;s an IC that becomes whatever you program it to become, be it a processor, amplifier, anything, absolutely anything you want it to be.  It&#39;s kinda like being AMD, ARM, ATMEL or INTEL, you get to completely design what the IC does!

So it arrives completely dumb, it doesn&#39;t do anything until programmed to _be_ something, and that means you get to decide which pins are input pins, which pins are output pins, and _everything_ that sits between those pins.  And because FPGAs are effectively realtime, they don&#39;t have the burden of working like a standard processor that processes intructions one at a time in a serial fashion.  FPGAs can do processing in parallel, in realtime, at truly _insane_ frequencies if you design them that way.

So what I&#39;m getting at here is that rather than settle for off-the-shelf components and designing Axoloti around a STM32F427, you could program your entire system into a custom microprocessor chip, where the very architecture of the chip is designed by yourself to do exactly what _you_ want it to do.  I think that&#39;s amazing, really amazing, and apparently the only thing you need to learn in order to design and use an FPGA, is to learn the Varilog/HDL language, which is basically special language used for programming your custom structure into the FPGA.

I honestly recommend everyone watch this video, even those of you with no interest in the actual electronics side of things, because I think his enthusiasm alone will make you realise why devices such as these are the future even though they&#39;re already with us, and have been for some time:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gUsHwi4M4xE</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:26:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This thread reminded me of an excellent project for those interested in the basics of logic design and low-level programming: <a href="http://www.nand2tetris.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.nand2tetris.org/</a></p>

<p>The project has a corresponding book: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elements-Computing-Systems-Building-Principles/dp/0262640686/ref=ed_oe_p" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.amazon.com/Elements-Computing-Systems-Building-Principles/dp/0262640686/ref=ed_oe_p</a></p>

<p>It basically walks you up the stack building up a basic computer architecture at the gate level, assembler and high-level language all from first principles. The toolchain is all custom to the project, but the concepts are very general. At the end you have a full computing system stack all emulated in software that you can write games for, somewhat like a Gameboy.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/39</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-39</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So as it has been at least 6 months since I have thought about seeing if I would be interested in learning FPGA, I decided to use your links to see if it would change anything, the video is good, but boy does he talk a lot...</p>

<p>Anyhow, unfortunately the outcome is the same, when I look into what is involved with simulating signal paths and problem solving, added with the fact that a lot of coding can be done much simpler with a microcontroller, it does create an overwhelming sensation of a very steep learning curve, and as before becomes something maybe for a later date.</p>

<p>One example I looked at was a 4 in 1 out mux, for a beginner I guess the code would appear quite complex, but over time I could get familiar with it, but then when I saw the simulation and tried to compare it to the code, I thought WTF !, I just could match it up, I think due to it appearing to be very complex, and I may have just talked myself out if it, but still, not for me.</p>

<p><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/38</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 22:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-38</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@reaganry reaganry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/reaganry">@reaganry</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>intro to VHDL (programming hardware) <a href="http://freerangefactory.org/pdf/df344hdh4h8kjfh3500ft2/free_range_vhdl.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">http://freerangefactory.org/pdf/df344hdh4h8kjfh3500ft2/free_range_vhdl.pdf</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/37</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 02:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-37</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@reaganry reaganry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/reaganry">@reaganry</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>a new intro to FPGA.  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BZUHr3J217c" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BZUHr3J217c</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/36</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 21:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-36</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>With these high frequencies, aliasing won't be a problem.<br>It may be also possible do make DCO (analog osc synch'd by digital signals) à la Roland Jupiter/Juno.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 19:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-34</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DrJustice]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/drjustice">@DrJustice</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="31" data-topic="4482"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/smashedtransistors/40/3147_1.png" class="avatar">SmashedTransistors:</div>
<blockquote><p>What is the switching frequency of the switched capacitors ?</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I think it's max 4 MHz for the AN231E04 (the chip variant used in the Paradigm synth).</p>

<p>BTW, the AN2xxxxx family is called not FPAA, but dpASPs (dynamically programmed Analog Signal Processors), since they can be (re)configured at any time, not just on start up.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 18:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-33</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@reaganry reaganry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/reaganry">@reaganry</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>an Axoloti-style environment that makes the FPGA accessible would be revolutionary! </p>

<p>Arm/STM32 does seem to be recently established (axo, gecho, bastl, organelle, etc) as the production-worthy step-up from Arduino/Atmel, thoguh, and the boards are available and cheap and constantly being improved.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/32</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 18:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-32</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Wow, just like the good old MF10 filters !...</p>

<p>What is the switching frequency of the switched capacitors ?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/31</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 17:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-31</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DrJustice]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/drjustice">@DrJustice</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Anadigm FPAAs use switched capacitor technology. E.g. a switched capacitor filter uses the ratio of smaller capacitors (on the chip), so no large (external) capacitors are needed, at least for that. It's worth noting that with switched capacitor circuits, the sampling theorem applies and anti-aliasing filters must be applied accordingly. To this end the Anadigm chips have programmable 2nd order anti-aliasing/reconstruction filters on board.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/30</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 15:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-30</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It seams from some documentation, the built in components are somewhat part of an attempt to mimic the real life components, not sure if all FPAA devices are the exact same, but one document describes use of a transistor, a single generic capacitor, and op-amp to achieve the required outcome, so would expect it could contain many multiples of this group within the FPAA itself. It doesn't state it as an accurate result, but a close enough result in terms of how it operates. Documentation also highlights very high dependancy on software like "Scanalog" to make good use of all this.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/29</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 11:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-29</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="4482"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/smashedtransistors/40/3147_1.png" class="avatar">SmashedTransistors:</div>
<blockquote><p>About FPAA... you cannot miniaturize capacitors in the range we use in the audio (nF uF). These are condemn to be external components. FPAA will be of limited use. So, don't expect a one chip Prophet V.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>How would it work in Scanalog though, surely the miniaturisation is no obstacle due to the ability to interconnect the built-in components.  Wouldn't any such limits be overcome by simply programming the connections between resistors, capacitors etc, in series or parallel configuration depending on how much capacitance or resistance is required?</p>

<p>In analogue, you increase or decrease resistance or capacitance through their arrangement.  Don't forget they're working with ready-made component blocks, so that probably means that if the capacitance or resistance you wanted is not physically possible with a single component, it would silently connect two or more in the required configuration in order to achieve the same task.</p>

<p>I'm hoping it must work something like that, otherwise that Scanalog project would not be much use at all.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/28</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 10:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-28</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>With a FPGA you need digital <strong>electronics</strong> skills along with programming skills (to program cores) and DSP skills (to design audio algorithms).</p>

<p>As you state, the main interest is that even if some embedded cores have a sequential internal behaviour, the main interest and <strong>difficulty</strong> is that everything in a FPGA runs in parallel. You have to deal with synchronisations and build yourself such things as pipelines...</p>

<p>About FPAA... you cannot miniaturize capacitors in the range we use in the audio (nF uF). These are condemn to be external components. FPAA will be of limited use. So, don't expect a one chip Prophet V. </p>

<p>I think that the right way (low cost, efficient way, easily programmable) is an array of ARM processors.</p>

<p>But i don't think that <a class="mention" href="/u/johannes">@johannes</a> plans to make Axolotis SPI-communicate-and-synchronize (which is complex and difficult for a "one man army") any time soon <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/disappointed.png?v=5" title=":disappointed:" class="emoji" alt=":disappointed:"> .</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/27</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 07:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-27</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I've heard many stories how many seasoned programmers cannot even get through the basics of FPGA, not saying don't learn it, but its a different concept.<br>FPGA's have been around since the 1980's, but it is only more recent years, and the advancement of many chip technologies that options have become available for hobby programmers. Comparing systems from the 1980's to now, if I have researched correctly, they have more logic gates, blocks and clock domains, added with more cores for parallel logic.<br>A way of just using lots more "or, nor, and, xand, xor" etc.. to acieve the required outcome.<br>One thing to remember, FPGA is not sequential programming, its not like in the Axo object where you put your code line by line, knowing it gets executed line by line.<br>FPGA's don't work this way.<br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/26</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 07:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-26</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My sense is that FPGA programming is not at the right abstraction level for users wanting to write extensions. I don't see regular users programming effectively in terms of logic gates. This is basically what you get working in hardware description languages (VHDL, verilog, etc.); you're writing a description of digital logic circuits. There would need to be a higher level library that compiled down to something useful on the FPGA. There are probably higher level libraries like this out there that help with DSP applications. But then we're sort of back to where we started. A C style library for doing DSP programming. I'm a bit skeptical that this would end up being more efficient or effective somehow just because we were running everything on an FPGA. I don't know the details off the top of my head, but my gut feeling is that it wouldn't buy us much. Ultimately in the digital domain all we're trying to do is execute all the math we want to do fast enough and then send everything out to the DAC.</p>

<p>FPAAs are fundamentally different. You are programming in terms of pretty high-level analog modules like oscillators, filters, comparators and gain stages, etc.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/25</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 16:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-25</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaffasplaffa Mr. Grimm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/urklang">@urklang</a></p>

<p>Sounds like you have som experience with programming FPGA's:</p>

<p>How hard is it to program these, compared to what we are doing on Axoloti now? It sounds very low level, which I could imagine is a bit hard to get started on.</p>

<p>I understand its completely different languages used, VDHL and Verilog. Which I never even heard of before <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>

<p>Wow, this FPGA organ is really impressive:)<br></p><div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="OOmVIg0raWo" data-youtube-title="FPGA emulates Hammond organ" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/24</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 09:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-24</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="20" data-topic="4482" data-full="true"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/drjustice/40/1430_1.png" class="avatar">DrJustice:</div>
<blockquote><p>Regarding FPAAs, the Paradigm Synthesizer uses 4 Anadigm FPAAs. GS thread here. There isn't a vast amount of resources on those chips, but they can be reconfigured to cover different voice modes.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Very nice, and that "reconfigurable" part of it isn't something I even thought about, despite the benefits of FPGA technology.  Axoloti can do that as well, just in a different way, cause you can save various sketches to an SD card, and select between them using the hardware buttons once Axoloti is in standalone mode, therefore allowing you to completely reconfigure Axoloti on the fly.</p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="4482"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/urklang/40/2326_1.png" class="avatar">urklang:</div>
<blockquote><p><a class="mention" href="/u/axoman">@axoman</a> Maybe this will melt your brain more ...</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>No maybe about it, consider it melted mate <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"> <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sunglasses.png?v=5" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p>

<p>That sounds completely awesome, and it's especially comforting to know that it's being designd by someone who works for an FPAA manufacturer.  I'd like to second what Jaffa said, please keep us updated on it, just be careful I don't rip your freaking arm off when you finally bring it to market <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>

<p>Of course, what this means in real terms is that once we have the FPAA board, between that and the Axoloti, we'd have a complete Analogue/Digital development system driven completely by a visual building-block interface.  Now more than ever, I wish Johannes would release a completely unpopulated version of Axoloti, cause that way it could be connected to your PFAA board using whatever connection design the designer chooses (assuming that your board is unpopulated).  If it's going to be populated, then please release an unpopulated version as well, cause being prepopulated with connectors, power jacks, storage mechanisms, leds, switches etc, dramatically lessens the boards viability for bulk commercial purchsers.  Some commercial users might accept prepopulation, but the majority won't.  It's like with Arduino, they got it right because although the boards are prepopulated, it is extremely easy to "breadboard" an Arduino core and add to it only the parts you need, so you can test a custom board before production.</p>

<p>Try breadboarding an Axoloti core that would work with minimal components <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grimacing.png?v=5" title=":grimacing:" class="emoji" alt=":grimacing:"></p>

<p>If your board design is prepopulated, it should be easy enough to have some boards made using the same FPAA that you use by following its schematic, so it could be done that way, but again, I think the key for sucess with any product is it's viability in a commercial environment, not just a consumer accessible one, because ultimately, commercial users buy in bulk, and that's not something to take lightly.  I doubt the schematic for your board would be too complicated due to being an add-on, but I wish there was a Fritzing-format schematic for both Axoloti and your board when released, cause that would completely work as a professional development system.  It means we'd be able to incorporate both the Axoloti and the FPAA into the same board of any design, once the users designs had been worked-out using an actual Axoloti board and your actual FPAA board.  In a nutshell, breadboarding a custom PCB is the only alternative if the board isn't available in unpopulated form.</p>

<p>Other than the on-board SD card-holder, USB socket, LED, and Switch, the Teensy 3.6 is s good example of a commercially-viable development board:</p>

          <a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1004/5324/products/Teensy_3.6_bc969e48-eb13-4526-af6c-c6403622752a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1476343810" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
            <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1004/5324/products/Teensy_3.6_bc969e48-eb13-4526-af6c-c6403622752a_1024x1024.jpg?v=1476343810" width="500" height="500">
          </a>


<p>It's not <em>completely</em> viable, but from a commercial standpoint it is far more viable than Axoloti, because there is far too much prepopulation on the Axoloti, and very little on the Teensy.  There should be a version of Axoloti with the core and all necessary interconnection components, but that is all, absolutely <em>nothing</em> else, not even an LED unless it can be disabled.</p>

<p>So I'm seriously looking forward to your product, but please release it in unpopulated form, or at least relase two versions where one is unpopulated <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/heart_eyes.png?v=5" title=":heart_eyes:" class="emoji" alt=":heart_eyes:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 10:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-23</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaffasplaffa Mr. Grimm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/urklang">@urklang</a></p>

<p>Yes please keep us updated on that. Sounds awesome!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 05:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-22</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/axoman">@axoman</a> Maybe this will melt your brain more:</p>

<p>I've been working on integrating Axoloti and FPAAs for the past year or so. I'm planning to ship an expansion board and complete firmware and object library. The idea is to support pretty much exactly what you've described: to be able to have an Axoloti patch that compiles down to some arbitrary analog signal processing that happens on the expansion board. This will allow you to run whatever analog designs you want like classic filters etc. and to control everything with the usual Axoloti interface and libraries. Hopefully the community will then share many such analog designs just like we currently share digital objects.</p>

<p>There's a lot of challenging engineering necessary to make that all work smoothly and currently I'm working by myself in my spare time, so I don't have a specific timetable for when it will be available. I'm involved directly with a company that produces FPAA chips as much of the software for the project is actually applicable to many other applications. I'll keep the community posted on my progress.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 01:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-21</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DrJustice]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/drjustice">@DrJustice</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Regarding FPAAs, the <a href="http://www.fabuloussilicon.com/blog/2017/01/11/paradigm/" rel="nofollow noopener">Paradigm Synthesizer</a> uses 4 Anadigm FPAAs. <a href="https://www.gearslutz.com/board/electronic-music-instruments-and-electronic-music-production/1134260-fabulous-silicon-paradigm.html" rel="nofollow noopener">GS thread here.</a> There isn't a vast amount of resources on those chips, but they can be reconfigured to cover different voice modes.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 22:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-20</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="4482"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/jaffasplaffa/40/5145_1.png" class="avatar">jaffasplaffa:</div>
<blockquote><p>I guess that's all a matter of perspective <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slightly_smiling_face.png?v=5" title=":slightly_smiling_face:" class="emoji" alt=":slightly_smiling_face:"></p></blockquote></aside>

<p>No no, it's just a matter of real-world physics <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/yum.png?v=5" title=":yum:" class="emoji" alt=":yum:"></p>

<p>Anyway, no point getting into that stuff, especially not right now while I'm currently reveling in the wonders of digital logic and stuff.  It's amazing how, even with the internet, it's taken me so long to stumble across this stuff, and now that I have, even more of it is coming thick and fast!</p>

<p>Yup, interesting stuff <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slightly_smiling_face.png?v=5" title=":slightly_smiling_face:" class="emoji" alt=":slightly_smiling_face:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 20:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-19</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaffasplaffa Mr. Grimm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="15" data-topic="4482"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/a/848f3c/40.png" class="avatar">axoman:</div>
<blockquote><p><a class="mention" href="/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> Hey, you know me, I have no fear of analogue/digital warfare, simply because you all got owned by axoman last time there was such a discussion,</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I guess that's all a matter of perspective <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p>Anyway, we have good things coming for us <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> Lets see what the clever people can come up with, this is a bit over my head, but non the less interesting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/18</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 20:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-18</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/jls">@JLS</a> Wow, this just gets better, thanks for posting that!!!</p>

<p>Just took a quick look, and while I have my doubts about the analogue side of it, it still looks to be an amazing product and the price is incredibly good, lol, just $10 for all that.  Damn, lot of documetation for it so I'll look for a few videos on YouTube about it first, see if I can get a better understanding of what they mean by "Analogue".  I get the slightest feeling that they are talking about analogue in the same way the Arduino peeps do, that being PWM.  You can use PWM to generate an anlogue signal by connecting components, and I think perhaps that's what they mean by analogue.  If not, and the blocks inside are <em>actual</em> analogue as they are in the Scanalog system, then all I can say is double-wow, that's bloody amazing!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 20:22:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-17</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JLS]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/jls">@JLS</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This simple chip combine FPGA FPAA MCU and DSP. Little resources but low price and big fun <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"><br><a href="http://www.cypress.com/documentation/development-kitsboards/cy8ckit-059-psoc-5lp-prototyping-kit-onboard-programmer-and" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.cypress.com/documentation/development-kitsboards/cy8ckit-059-psoc-5lp-prototyping-kit-onboard-programmer-and</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 19:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-16</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/hwk">@hwk</a> I'm going to enjoy looking into that in more depth.  Took a quick look at various areas of the website and it does indeed look as if an FPGA would be perfect for such projects as that!</p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> Hey, you know me, I have no fear of analogue/digital warfare, simply because you all got owned by axoman last time there was such a discussion, and as far as I'm aware, the laws of physics have not changed since then, so axoman still owns (and analogue is still the daddy) <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>

<p>Actually though, you'll notice that in the very first video posted in this thread, Dave points out that you cannot do analogue with these devices.  Well technically that's true, you cannot do analogue with an FPGA. However, there is currently a product under development called Scanalog, which is a device known as an FPAA (Field Programmable Analogue Array).  It's not available yet, but man, can you imagine, you'd be able to program the most enourmous analogue modular synthesizers into a chip (real analogue)!</p>

<p>Wouldn't stop there, either, cause it means you could program analogue parametric EQs, analogue compressors, analogue mixers, basically a complete analogue studio (real analogue), all inside a chip!</p>

<p>Here's a few videos I found on what's being developed, basically the analogue equivelent of an FPGA:</p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="D43a-r5M9ys" data-youtube-title="Scanalog: Interactive Design and Debugging of Analog Circuits with Programmable Analog Hardware" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>

<p>And a more in-depth discussion on the FPAA-based product that is being developed:</p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="lqij-V6NxT0" data-youtube-title="Scanalog: Interactive Design and Debugging of Analog Circuits with Programmable Hardware" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/drjustice">@DrJustice</a>  Thanks for the encouragement, and yup, you bet I'll be playing with this stuff.  Just imagining what would be possible by combining an FPGA and FPAA on a single circuit board is absolutely insane, man, the stuff that can be done with it.  And taking, for example, an FPAA and interfacing it with Axoloti would enable the production of real analogue synthesizers controlled by Axoloti logic and MIDI etc.</p>

<p>My brain is in overdrive, and is rapidly reaching meltdown just thinking about it <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/heart_eyes.png?v=5" title=":heart_eyes:" class="emoji" alt=":heart_eyes:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 19:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-15</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>FPGA-Based Axoloti</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaffasplaffa Mr. Grimm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/drjustice">@DrJustice</a></p>

<p> Ahh Yes i see now, didnt read through it all.</p>

<p>Yeah its very impressive. The quality seems pretty up there <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p>Man, I LOVE all the new digital technology we are getting these days. All the extra power we get, means better quality, "warmer" sound, etc....... Whats not to love about it? <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p> I remember reading a post by the guys from Make Noise, that they posted from Namm. Mr. Buchla himself visited their booth and they said that he had no interest in all the analog stuff they made, but he was a lot more fascinated by the digital stuff. </p>

<p>And he even stated that with the technology we have now a days, he dont see any point in making analog devices anymore. Anyway, just loving new techologies, like FPGA and whatever we have coming, not trying to start a digital/analog warfare.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 16:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4482-14</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fpga-based-axoloti/4482.rss">FPGA-Based Axoloti</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
