<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>About the Community Library category</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/about-the-community-library-category/1005</link>
    <description>Category for the community library

**( you need Axoloti 1.0.10 installed to use the community library , see [this post](/t/axoloti-test-release-1-0-10) )** 

## About the community library
The community library is a way to share object and patches with the community. Sharing is done by a simple synchronisation feature available with the Axoloti UI, providing an easy way to both contribute and use contributions without having to download files manually. 
This category is used to allow contributors to provide more information about their objects and patches in the library, and for other users to comment/ask questions etc.
This feature is new, so there will be more coming, to allow better management and also for better browsing of the library especially for patches.

Note: please do not post files directly on the forum, its much easier to for everyone to access and maintain if they are store in the online library.

##Accessing the library 
Since 1.0.7 all users can access all community library objects directly from the Object Search dialog, just like the factory objects. Patches can be found the subdirectory axoloti-contrib/patches in your axoloti home directory. (a patch browser is planned for a future release)

to keep you library up to date, you will need to use the &#39;synchronise libraries&#39; option found in the File menu.

alternatively, you can turn on auto-sync in the library preferences, found in the preferences dialog, once enable this will automatically synchronise your libraries each time you start axoloti.

Note: objects can either be AXO or AXS files, however they should be &#39;generic&#39; objects, i.e. objects that can be reused by other patches. 
AXS files which are specific to a patch, should be stored in the same directory as the AXP (within the patches sections)

##Contributor topics
**Each contributor is allowed one topic** only, the first post will be used to list their contributions, and references to further details about their objects/patches etc. 

If other users have questions or issues about these contributions they should post on that same thread.

an example for how I (@thetechnobear) organise mine is linked [here](https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/thetecnnobear-library/1006/2?u=thetechnobear) 

The idea behind this organisation is:
- few topics, so easy to browse
- contributor can monitor their own topic, to support their own contributions.

(we will move and combine posts/topics to keep these goals)
in particular, this is NOT the place to make request for objects etc, or other discussions.

## Contributing to the community library

anyone can access the community library from the Axoloti UI, no user account etc is necessary

However, to contribute to the community library you will need to do the following:

- create an account on [github.com](http://github.com)
- be added as a contributor to the user library, see [this post](https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/contributor-access/1039)
- create a contributor post , see my example [here](https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/thetecnnobear-library/1006/2?u=thetechnobear)

## adding/updating objects/patches to the user library
- simply put your new object in the appropriate place in the directory, 
this is [objects/patches]/[your prefix]/[category]/object or patch
e.g. axoloti-contrib/object/tb/midi/out/mymidi.axo
- synchronise the library to upload the new objects
- update your contributor post here, so that users know about it, and you can supply details of how to use etc.

It is **highly** recommended contributors use the latest released version of Axoloti for contributing.

Its a good idea to follow a similar heirarchy for objects (e.g. midi/in , env , osc, lfo) since in the future, the object browser may compress these into a single hierarchy, or we may use as a &#39;seed&#39; for tag creations.



Important note:  you should only add and update objects/patches **under your own prefix** do NOT attempt to update other users objects, as this can lead to conflict errors, which may require &#39;support intervention&#39; to resolve.

removing entries or more advanced file operations e.g. rename are possible using git tools directly, please only do this if you are experience with such tools, if not PM us.  users **must not** do any git operations that affect any objects/patches outside their own prefix.
if in doubt PM either @johannes or I (@thetechnobear)  

(this restricted workflow is intended to minimise the chance of git issues, which are difficult for users with little git experience to resolve... and obviously we cannot expect (or want) users to need to know the complexity of version control systems)


##Contributors upgrading Axoloti##
Before you upgrade axoloti to a new version, it is recommend you commit your changes to the community library i.e. do one last sync before you upgrade.
note: when you commit changes, they are available immediately to all user using the version you are using. If you are using an old version of axoloti, then this changes will be copied to newer versions periodically... so you do not (and should not) do this yourself, but this may mean that its not available in the latest versions for a day or so. This is why we recommend contributors use the latest version of Axoloti.

##Videos
Ive created a series of videos which show how libraries are used in general and also particular the community library

(please note: some changes have occurred since these were made, but the contents is generally correct still)

[Introduction to libraries](http://youtu.be/cE0kOfTCqmc) 

[Contributing to the community library](http://youtu.be/BbwRlavGSQw)

[Using your own libraries](http://youtu.be/PUMeb_tOTnY)

[Obtaining the factory library without internet connection](http://youtu.be/NP9YcWE4xRM)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 16:50:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community Library</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/about-the-community-library-category/1005.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>About the Community Library category</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Category for the community library</p>

<p><strong>( you need Axoloti 1.0.10 installed to use the community library , see <a href="/t/axoloti-test-release-1-0-10">this post</a>)</strong> </p>

<h2>About the community library</h2>

<p>The community library is a way to share object and patches with the community. Sharing is done by a simple synchronisation feature available with the Axoloti UI, providing an easy way to both contribute and use contributions without having to download files manually. <br>This category is used to allow contributors to provide more information about their objects and patches in the library, and for other users to comment/ask questions etc.<br>This feature is new, so there will be more coming, to allow better management and also for better browsing of the library especially for patches.</p>

<p>Note: please do not post files directly on the forum, its much easier to for everyone to access and maintain if they are store in the online library.</p>

<h2>Accessing the library</h2>

<p>Since 1.0.7 all users can access all community library objects directly from the Object Search dialog, just like the factory objects. Patches can be found the subdirectory axoloti-contrib/patches in your axoloti home directory. (a patch browser is planned for a future release)</p>

<p>to keep you library up to date, you will need to use the 'synchronise libraries' option found in the File menu.</p>

<p>alternatively, you can turn on auto-sync in the library preferences, found in the preferences dialog, once enable this will automatically synchronise your libraries each time you start axoloti.</p>

<p>Note: objects can either be AXO or AXS files, however they should be 'generic' objects, i.e. objects that can be reused by other patches. <br>AXS files which are specific to a patch, should be stored in the same directory as the AXP (within the patches sections)</p>

<h2>Contributor topics</h2>

<p><strong>Each contributor is allowed one topic</strong> only, the first post will be used to list their contributions, and references to further details about their objects/patches etc. </p>

<p>If other users have questions or issues about these contributions they should post on that same thread.</p>

<p>an example for how I (<a class="mention" href="/users/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a>) organise mine is linked <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/thetecnnobear-library/1006/2?u=thetechnobear">here</a> </p>

<p>The idea behind this organisation is:<br>- few topics, so easy to browse<br>- contributor can monitor their own topic, to support their own contributions.</p>

<p>(we will move and combine posts/topics to keep these goals)<br>in particular, this is NOT the place to make request for objects etc, or other discussions.</p>

<h2>Contributing to the community library</h2>

<p>anyone can access the community library from the Axoloti UI, no user account etc is necessary</p>

<p>However, to contribute to the community library you will need to do the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>create an account on <a href="http://github.com" rel="nofollow">github.com</a>
</li>
<li>be added as a contributor to the user library, see <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/contributor-access/1039">this post</a>
</li>
<li>create a contributor post , see my example <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/thetecnnobear-library/1006/2?u=thetechnobear">here</a>
</li>
</ul>

<h2>adding/updating objects/patches to the user library</h2>

<ul>
<li>simply put your new object in the appropriate place in the directory, <br>this is [objects/patches]/[your prefix]/[category]/object or patch<br>e.g. axoloti-contrib/object/tb/midi/out/mymidi.axo</li>
<li>synchronise the library to upload the new objects</li>
<li>update your contributor post here, so that users know about it, and you can supply details of how to use etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>It is <strong>highly</strong> recommended contributors use the latest released version of Axoloti for contributing.</p>

<p>Its a good idea to follow a similar heirarchy for objects (e.g. midi/in , env , osc, lfo) since in the future, the object browser may compress these into a single hierarchy, or we may use as a 'seed' for tag creations.</p>

<p>Important note:  you should only add and update objects/patches <strong>under your own prefix</strong> do NOT attempt to update other users objects, as this can lead to conflict errors, which may require 'support intervention' to resolve.</p>

<p>removing entries or more advanced file operations e.g. rename are possible using git tools directly, please only do this if you are experience with such tools, if not PM us.  users <strong>must not</strong> do any git operations that affect any objects/patches outside their own prefix.<br>if in doubt PM either <a class="mention" href="/users/johannes">@johannes</a> or I (<a class="mention" href="/users/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a>)  </p>

<p>(this restricted workflow is intended to minimise the chance of git issues, which are difficult for users with little git experience to resolve... and obviously we cannot expect (or want) users to need to know the complexity of version control systems)</p>

<h2>Contributors upgrading Axoloti</h2>

<p>Before you upgrade axoloti to a new version, it is recommend you commit your changes to the community library i.e. do one last sync before you upgrade.<br>note: when you commit changes, they are available immediately to all user using the version you are using. If you are using an old version of axoloti, then this changes will be copied to newer versions periodically... so you do not (and should not) do this yourself, but this may mean that its not available in the latest versions for a day or so. This is why we recommend contributors use the latest version of Axoloti.</p>

<h2>Videos</h2>

<p>Ive created a series of videos which show how libraries are used in general and also particular the community library</p>

<p>(please note: some changes have occurred since these were made, but the contents is generally correct still)</p>

<p><a href="http://youtu.be/cE0kOfTCqmc" rel="nofollow">Introduction to libraries</a> </p>

<p><a href="http://youtu.be/BbwRlavGSQw" rel="nofollow">Contributing to the community library</a></p>

<p><a href="http://youtu.be/PUMeb_tOTnY" rel="nofollow">Using your own libraries</a></p>

<p><a href="http://youtu.be/NP9YcWE4xRM" rel="nofollow">Obtaining the factory library without internet connection</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/about-the-community-library-category/1005/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/about-the-community-library-category/1005/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 15:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-1005-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/about-the-community-library-category/1005.rss">About the Community Library category</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
