<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937</link>
    <description>Hello everybody,

first post here in the forum after looking around for some weeks and reading lots of articles. 
Loving the Forum, loving Axoloti!! Great job Johannes!

Anyways, I was wondering what the best way would be to protect the analogue ins from high currents.
I am currently in the process of building an enclosure with pots and some IO jacks. The plan is to use Axoloti as a standalone instrument as well as with my Eurorack system. I want to send CV back an forth between the modular and Axoloti. 
I found lots of schematics for op amp circuits to convert the voltages. However I have quite a few Eurorack utility modules already where I can amplify, scale, offset and invert CV signals in every possible way in order to get something useful.  So I don&#39;t feel the need to build another op amp circuit.
However I&#39;d like to protect my GPIOs and Axoloti from accidentally sending in an unscaled signal like +10V or +/-5V. From my understanding that could really damage the Axoloti Core board, right?
Would a simple circuit with an input resistor and a couple of shottky diodes (bat 48 for example?) be able to protect the board? Like this one:&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/default/original/2X/e/edffaaf55603a9f5123e9f0743a2d3ca36696de1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;570&quot; height=&quot;256&quot;&gt;

If yes: Do I need to connect the +3V3 to the VDDA, VDDC or VDD?

Last question: Is it possible/ necessary to protect an analogue GPIO output as well?

Thanks in advance for any help and comments.
Happy Monday to you all!!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 02:47:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@haK Norbert Wuertz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/hak">@haK</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the detailed reply. Really useful infos for an electronic-noob like me.</p>

<p>For the moment I use a 10KOhm resistor and bat48 shottky diodes. VDD as 3.3V net.</p>

<p> I tested the circuit on breadboard without having any GPIO connected. When I feed it +10V I get about 3.6V coming out on the other end and around -0.4V when I send in -5V. <br>However, I don't intend to send 10V CV to the Axoloti anyway. The idea is to attenuate any CV signals with a passive attenuator (10KOhm Pot) coming from the modular prior to sending it through the protection circuit into the GPIOs. The resistor and diode clamp is just a safety precaution in case I make a mistake. The maximum CV inputs will be 4.</p>

<p>If I use the same circuit for the analogue outs, do I need the resistor as well as the diodes? If yes, in which order?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 02:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2937-3</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937.rss">Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@johannes johannes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/johannes">@johannes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What value do you have in mind for R3?</p>

<p>If R3 would be 1kOhm, and you feed +10V into CVin, it injects 6.5mA into the +3.3V supply. If you 'd do this on 15 analog gpio inputs, this adds up to almost 100mA in the worst case of feeding them all with +10V. If there is no consumption of 100mA on the 3.3V supply, the linear regulator will not be effective anymore, but the +3.3V supply will lift up, and this can certainly cause damage...<br>So I suggest to use VDD (not VDDC) as the 3.3V net, VDDC has much less consumption.<br>And use more than 1kOhm for R3, say, 4.7kOhm.</p>

<p>You can use exactly the same circuit to protect the analogue GPIO outputs.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 19:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2937-2</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937.rss">Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@haK Norbert Wuertz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/hak">@haK</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello everybody,</p>

<p>first post here in the forum after looking around for some weeks and reading lots of articles. <br>Loving the Forum, loving Axoloti!! Great job Johannes!</p>

<p>Anyways, I was wondering what the best way would be to protect the analogue ins from high currents.<br>I am currently in the process of building an enclosure with pots and some IO jacks. The plan is to use Axoloti as a standalone instrument as well as with my Eurorack system. I want to send CV back an forth between the modular and Axoloti. <br>I found lots of schematics for op amp circuits to convert the voltages. However I have quite a few Eurorack utility modules already where I can amplify, scale, offset and invert CV signals in every possible way in order to get something useful.  So I don't feel the need to build another op amp circuit.<br>However I'd like to protect my GPIOs and Axoloti from accidentally sending in an unscaled signal like +10V or +/-5V. From my understanding that could really damage the Axoloti Core board, right?<br>Would a simple circuit with an input resistor and a couple of shottky diodes (bat 48 for example?) be able to protect the board? Like this one:<img src="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/original/2X/e/edffaaf55603a9f5123e9f0743a2d3ca36696de1.jpg" width="570" height="256"></p>

<p>If yes: Do I need to connect the +3V3 to the VDDA, VDDC or VDD?</p>

<p>Last question: Is it possible/ necessary to protect an analogue GPIO output as well?</p>

<p>Thanks in advance for any help and comments.<br>Happy Monday to you all!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2937-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/protecting-axolotis-io-from-high-currents/2937.rss">Protecting Axolotis IO from high currents</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
