<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Replace green LED</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659</link>
    <description>Hi, 
i had a litte unfortunate situation, where my axoloti fell from a table.
It was right before a concert, and first it was quite a terrible shock to see only three red blinks and then the axoloti went dark. However all patches and hardware turned out to be working. So what happened, that with my luck, I only damaged (as in: broke off an lost) the GREEN LED. 
Now, I can probably live without it, but could you perhaps suggest a replacement part? 
Also the component right behind the green LED was a bit dislocated (orange yellow housing, 50E23 475A), which I managet to solder back kinda solid later, but maybe can you help me out, what it is, and if I can expect SOME trouble?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 17:26:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Helpdesk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Replace green LED</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Csefalva]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/csefalva">@Csefalva</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you! You helped me out a lot.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 17:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5659-3</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659.rss">Replace green LED</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Replace green LED</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@UHF]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/uhf">@UHF</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>According to page 3 of the <a href="http://www.axoloti.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/axoloti-core-sch-v12.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">schematic</a>, it's a side-view green LED with a 2.2V forward voltage (Vf) and it's very, very small. Anything similar with same Vf will do, but it's designed to be seen from the side. A not-so-small smd LED could be soldered on it's side (rather than flat as normal) to achieve the same thing probably, the pads look wide enough to accommodate something bigger. I don't know where you live and might order from, but cheap smd LEDs are available from eBay (<a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/50-pcs-SMD-SMT-0603-Super-bright-GREEN-LED-lamp-Bulb-GOOD-QUALITY/181847007394?epid=2213365186&amp;hash=item2a56ed20a2:g:L5MAAOSw3oBTyPPa" rel="nofollow noopener">example</a>). You could order from a proper distributor like Digikey, Mouser, RS... but there are minimum order quantities and shipping costs.</p>

<p>The orange thing that also got bashed is a capacitor (looking at my board I think it's C65 and the working of the Axoloti should be ok.) Otherwise, don't worry if everything else is working!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 01:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5659-2</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659.rss">Replace green LED</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Replace green LED</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Csefalva]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/csefalva">@Csefalva</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi, <br>i had a litte unfortunate situation, where my axoloti fell from a table.<br>It was right before a concert, and first it was quite a terrible shock to see only three red blinks and then the axoloti went dark. However all patches and hardware turned out to be working. So what happened, that with my luck, I only damaged (as in: broke off an lost) the GREEN LED. <br>Now, I can probably live without it, but could you perhaps suggest a replacement part? <br>Also the component right behind the green LED was a bit dislocated (orange yellow housing, 50E23 475A), which I managet to solder back kinda solid later, but maybe can you help me out, what it is, and if I can expect SOME trouble?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 14:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5659-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/replace-green-led/5659.rss">Replace green LED</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
