<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326</link>
    <description>Was poking around the github repo with the idea of a DSL targeting various popular languages like javascript, python, clojure, etc. that could be used as an alternative to the GUI Patcher -- how difficult would be be to plug in a different &quot;front end&quot; allowing folks to &quot;code&quot; their patches instead of drawing them? One could use their favorite IDE&#39;s -- even browser-based alternatives (e.g. cloud9, codebender, etc.). Thoughts?

Once the mechanics were figured out, it might be possible to use introspection on the default codebase to generate portions of the DSL code for various patcher objects to keep the DSL up to date as the new objects/functionality is added.

It might also be helpful to put together a wiki reference the magic between the patcher and running firmware (sorry if I missed it should it already exist).

Any insights on the concept and/or directions into the repo would be appreciated.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 13:52:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Software</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dirk Dirk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/dirk">@dirk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the insights and advice -- just what I was looking for to start this personal quest!!! Rolling up sleeves and digging in...</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 13:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-1326-5</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326.rss">DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ive actually considered something 'similar' to this a few times, as its not that hard to implement.<br>(depending on exactly what you want, as the topic is very 'general') <br>but I will point out the number of users interested in it, is probably very low ....<br>(for a similar reason I think the chances of getting documentation in this area is low priority, this is more likely 'roll your sleeves up' open source development <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=0" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> )</p>

<p>there are a few (compatible) approaches.</p>

<p>i) write a compatible binary<br>assumes you don't want to use axo objects, because the DSL already has a code base (e.g oscillators, filters), <br>this is relatively simple , just look at what is generated by patch.java, to create xpatch.cpp<br>(examples, I've been considering are gen~/heavy (pd)/ faust) </p>

<p>ii) use an interfacing axo object<br>actually pretty much the same as (i) , but rather than generate an xpatch.cpp to compile, create an interfacing object. same usage as (i) . advantage is more resilient to changes in axoloti, and few disadvantages.</p>

<p>(this approach could also be done at the object level, e.g. to generate object that could be combined in the patcher. something id been considering for gen~)  </p>

<p>iii) generate a patch  (axp) <br>as <a class="mention" href="/users/rvense">@rvense</a> said, you could generate a patch easy enough, is just a bunch of object instances and connections really. ok, it also allows embedded objects and patches now, so that complicates things a little, but not much.<br>would be reasonable compatible with future updates, as long as the patch format doesn't change.<br>real advantage is you can use all the objects that currently exist as axo objects, and of course its compatible with the axoloti UI for editing/debugging.</p>

<p>the disadvantage is really its just a wrapper around the axoloti patching, so your still following the same rules as the patcher (e.g. execution order) , but for a DSL wrapper thats probably no big thing... and if you need this, then i &amp; ii are likely to be more suitable anyway.</p>

<p>none of its really hard, but probably only useful to a few users, and I suspect something we should not distract <a class="mention" href="/users/johannes">@johannes</a> with, the Axoloti UI is excellent, and the concept of a graphical patching environment is a corner stone  of Axoloti ... and what has attracted many users.<br>(this is my opinion only!)</p>

<p>one thing, I will probably do is make patches compile from the command line (and uploads), we already have a mode which kind of does this for testing purposes . just needs to be make it a bit more generic.<br>(its in Axoloti.java/Mainframe.java if your interested)</p>

<p>starting points, Id suggest:</p>

<ul>
<li>look at structure of AXP files</li>
<li>look at/understand xpatch.cpp</li>
<li>check patch.java, it generates xpatch.cpp</li>
</ul>

<p>there are some other 'side' issues, related to how you might integrate things like parameters, but these are 'advanced' topics, which we can go into if you have the basics doing something interesting. (and are probably subject to change) </p>

<p>anyway, as I said, this is roll your sleeves up development, if someone gets part of it working, then I might have (limited) time to help out on issues encountered - but Ive not alot of time, as I'm busy on other things at the moment.<br>(though I admit, i loathe python... so your on your own if its in python <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=0" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> )</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 10:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-1326-4</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326.rss">DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rvense]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/rvense">@rvense</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>To avoid reinventing the wheel, I'd probably look at writing something that generates a normal .axp, which looks like a fairly self-explanatory XML-based format.</p>

<p>This way you'd not have to duplicate any of the work that goes into transforming patches into firmware.</p>

<p>If it's not already possible to run a headless "compile and upload" cycle using the existing Axoloti binary, you could add that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 09:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-1326-3</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326.rss">DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@20after4 Mukunda Modell]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/20after4">@20after4</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don't have much experience yet with the low level details of the axoloti software, but this does sound like a really cool idea. A python-based DSL would be excellent and maybe not that hard to build.</p>

<p>If I learn enough about the way the GUI patcher works to actually start working on something like this I will let you know, in the meantime hopefully someone else will have more ideas about how this might be accomplished.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 20:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-1326-2</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326.rss">DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dirk Dirk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/dirk">@dirk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Was poking around the github repo with the idea of a DSL targeting various popular languages like javascript, python, clojure, etc. that could be used as an alternative to the GUI Patcher -- how difficult would be be to plug in a different "front end" allowing folks to "code" their patches instead of drawing them? One could use their favorite IDE's -- even browser-based alternatives (e.g. cloud9, codebender, etc.). Thoughts?</p>

<p>Once the mechanics were figured out, it might be possible to use introspection on the default codebase to generate portions of the DSL code for various patcher objects to keep the DSL up to date as the new objects/functionality is added.</p>

<p>It might also be helpful to put together a wiki reference the magic between the patcher and running firmware (sorry if I missed it should it already exist).</p>

<p>Any insights on the concept and/or directions into the repo would be appreciated.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 14:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-1326-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/dsl-alternative-to-gui-patcher/1326.rss">DSL Alternative to GUI Patcher?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
