<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Noob: Note-changing sequencer</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188</link>
    <description>Hi community new user here, I have a basic knowledge of modular systems and i&#39;m decent with synthesisers. I&#39;ve been experimenting with Axoloti for a bit and i Love it! I&#39;ve already managed to make many good sounds! 
But i was wondering, how do you make a sequencer change note, to play given melody, in the sequence such as a sequencer on a hardware synthesiser would do?
I mean, how can you assign a certain note to a certain step and a different one to the step after?
Would you use a sequencer? how would you trigger it or program it? Would you use some kind of pitch modulation?
Please modular mentors and masters of coding , I ask for your help
(The note should be assigned ideally without a keyboard, possible with a dedicated object but i have no idea which one)
cheers
Matt</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 18:59:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Patching</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Noob: Note-changing sequencer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OrlandoDoom]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/orlandodoom">@OrlandoDoom</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/axoman">@axoman</a> that was a great input thanks! i will try the patch tomorrow. before I've used a feedback sequencer with harmony/note, and i managed to get different notes on the same scale (i think) modulating the tonic of the harmoniser wit the output of another harmony/note object. Some kind of melodic effect came out tweaking the offset a bit and i was quite happy with it.<br>do you have any other tips for other generated melodic pattern similar to the one i have used?<br>And also what could i use in the sequencer to create legato, glide,accent and the other classical sequencer parameters?<br>sorry for jumping from a topic to another but you have been very helpful in the previous post</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 03:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4188-3</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188.rss">Noob: Note-changing sequencer</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Noob: Note-changing sequencer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don't have an exact patch, but one I demonstrated to trigger different samples might give you a good idea of one way to do it.  If you look at the patch you'll see a selector button in the top left, and each time you press it, it triggers a different sample by moving to the next step, <strong>and you have a pitch knobs for each step</strong> (which is pretty much what you're getting at I think).</p>

<p>It demonstrates a manually built 4-step sequnencer, so to adapt it all you would need to do is change the trigger button for a clock, and replace the sample-based with whatever synth stuff you have.  It's far from ideal, it's not what you want, but it should give you an idea of how it can be done.</p>

<p>To adapt it from 4-step to more steps, simply replicate, and adjust the value in the counter to match how many steps you have.  There's other ways you can do it, using other objects but I never really got round to playing with that enough to advise you.</p>

<p>Here's the patch:<br><a href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/original/2X/5/5a741e4218f013da03f4caf2cd9887a9f971e16f.axp" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/uploads/default/original/2X/5/5a741e4218f013da03f4caf2cd9887a9f971e16f.axp</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 13:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4188-2</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188.rss">Noob: Note-changing sequencer</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Noob: Note-changing sequencer</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OrlandoDoom]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/orlandodoom">@OrlandoDoom</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi community new user here, I have a basic knowledge of modular systems and i'm decent with synthesisers. I've been experimenting with Axoloti for a bit and i Love it! I've already managed to make many good sounds! <br>But i was wondering, how do you make a sequencer change note, to play given melody, in the sequence such as a sequencer on a hardware synthesiser would do?<br>I mean, how can you assign a certain note to a certain step and a different one to the step after?<br>Would you use a sequencer? how would you trigger it or program it? Would you use some kind of pitch modulation?<br>Please modular mentors and masters of coding , I ask for your help<br>(The note should be assigned ideally without a keyboard, possible with a dedicated object but i have no idea which one)<br>cheers<br>Matt</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4188-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/noob-note-changing-sequencer/4188.rss">Noob: Note-changing sequencer</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
