<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760</link>
    <description>Hello!!!. On March 20, I bought an Axoloti on your website. It worked correctly until a week ago. In the morning I connected it to my PC to continue programming a patch and it no longer started (no lights were on) and the computer did not recognize the device (&quot;No available USB device found with matching PID / VID&quot;).
I read in the forum and try to load the &quot;Rescue Firmware&quot; and it does not recognize me. I have tested 5 cables usb (some I use to program industrial applications on devices Android) and on three computers (two Windows 10 and one Mac) and it does not boot. I have also tried a adapter and does not start. I do not know what to do... Please... heeeeeelp!!!

thanks!!!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 05:57:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Helpdesk</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pocajoke Juanma]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/pocajoke">@pocajoke</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello thetechnobear !!! </p>

<p>Thank you very much for answering again.</p>

<p>The LEDs do not work when I turn on the Axoloti (it is not in DFU mode). I tried switching it on with a power adapter and it has not worked either.</p>

<p>I will write to <a class="mention" href="/u/johannes">@johannes</a> to know if any hardware test can be performed or if I can send the axoloti to repair it.</p>

<p>Thank you very much!!!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 05:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4760-5</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760.rss">Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>the leds should come on if there is power (assuming your not putting in dfu mode) , though i suspect technically only once the bootloader/firmware starts running (<a class="mention" href="/u/johannes">@johannes</a> could confirm)</p>

<p>have you tried powering thru the DC jack? (just to see if its any difference)</p>

<p>its odd it worked fine for a while, then stopped... that, along with leds stopped blinking,  does possibly indicate some sort of hardware issue.<br>there were some issues with the very early boards, and some errant usb power, but i thought that was fixed in the newer boards (which you will have)</p>

<p>I think you should shoot <a class="mention" href="/u/johannes">@johannes</a> a private message (click on his profile, then message)  to discuss it, he'll know for sure if its a hardware issue.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 11:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4760-4</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760.rss">Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pocajoke Juanma]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/pocajoke">@pocajoke</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello thetechnobear!!!!</p>

<p>I have tried on a mac with High Sierra. The problem is that they do not turn on LEDs, it's as if I had no power. I tried to do the "rescue flash" and it does not work. At no time does the device appear in the list of DFU boards. How would you know if power is coming to the board?</p>

<p>Thank you very much!!!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4760-3</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760.rss">Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>hmm, ok, Id first focus on using one computer.. just so we can get full details.</p>

<p>id recommend the mac, as that requires no extra software to be installed. (so cannot have conflicts with old software installed) , once you have it working there, then you know the hardware is ok, and try again on windows.</p>

<p>what version of macOS are you using?<br>also make sure you do not have anything connected to the axoloti, via usb or soldered to its gpio,  whilst testing.</p>

<p>did you try the following:<br></p>

<p><aside class="quote"><blockquote><p>Could you try a "rescue flash": remove power from Axoloti Core, and then connect the micro-USB port to your computer while holding button S1. The LEDs will stay off when in DFU mode.<br>Then select in the Board menu -&gt; Firmware -&gt; Flash (Rescue)...</p></blockquote></aside></p>

<p>you need to be very sure you are holding S1 whilst you power up the axoloti  0 if you do this, and the leds flash, its likely you didn't keep it down. (it can be tricky as its a small button <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> ) </p>

<p>when you do this , if you go to the menu, board-&gt;select device, you should see a DFU board listed.</p>

<p>if not, then try another usb cable - this has been the issue for a lot of new users. <br>(esp. on mac where software doesn't really come into play) </p>

<hr>

<p>Id say its unlikely theres a hardware fault with the Axoloti, as <a class="mention" href="/u/johannes">@johannes</a> has a test rig to test before shipping, but also has to install the firmware before shipping ... and i dont think many have been damaged in transit. <br>(that said, Im only a user, that has helped on the forum - Johannes is the only one who knows the full support history) </p>

<p>(also the so called 'DFU' mode is not actually axoloti software, its part of the STM32F4 boot code, hence its impossible to 'accidentally' make it unavailable - hence why its the 'fallback route')</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4760-2</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760.rss">Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pocajoke Juanma]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/pocajoke">@pocajoke</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello!!!. On March 20, I bought an Axoloti on your website. It worked correctly until a week ago. In the morning I connected it to my PC to continue programming a patch and it no longer started (no lights were on) and the computer did not recognize the device ("No available USB device found with matching PID / VID").<br>I read in the forum and try to load the "Rescue Firmware" and it does not recognize me. I have tested 5 cables usb (some I use to program industrial applications on devices Android) and on three computers (two Windows 10 and one Mac) and it does not boot. I have also tried a adapter and does not start. I do not know what to do... Please... heeeeeelp!!!</p>

<p>thanks!!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 08:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4760-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-doesnt-work/4760.rss">Axoloti doesn&#39;t work</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
