<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>TX81Z inspired delay and midi effect patch</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/tx81z-inspired-delay-and-midi-effect-patch/6554</link>
    <description>Hey guys, I finally took the time to finish one of the first project I started with my Axoloti. 
This video is a jam / demo (with the Shruthi as a demo synth) of the different functions, the description of which is below:

https://www.facebook.com/PPaulusmusic/videos/698576777546645/

I started this patch with a fairly faithful reproduction of the MIDI delay of the Yamaha TX81Z FM Synth which I ended up customizing.

The Midi Mangler collects midi signals, here from the LXR and transform and repeat them.
The velocity of each note received subordinates the amount of note repeated, this amount is also controlled by a pot.
Main functions:
-Time: speed of the delay, synchronizable in midday (several divisions of the clock possible)
-Pitch: each repeated note is increased or subtracted by one octave successively
-Feedback: amount of note repeated
-Bend: amount of pitch bend

I also added more versatile functions:
-Random: at the press of the button concerned, each pitch and velocity is randomized
-Octave: the starting octave of the note can be changed
-CC random: at each trigger of a note, the program will apply an arbitrary change of value to a CC chosen at random
-PC random: at each trigger of a note, the program will send an arbitrary Program Change signal (basically, we change presets on the target Synth)

And two utility options:
-Midi channel: you can choose the midi channel of the target Synth
-CutOff CC: with each repeated note, a CC signal is sent with a decreasing value. We can therefore choose here to which Control Change we send these values. It can be used to simulate the drop in volume of a delay with the CC of the frequency of a filter, but also to other destinations such as resonance of a filter, VCA, waveform etc ...

I will probably add more and more bizarre randomization options and perhaps LFOs applicable to CC.

At the moment, it is a monophonic patch, I first have to clean it and try if it would work polyphonically.
It is also why i&#39;m not sharing it yet, I think it is too messy. I also believe a lot of functions I created could be done more effectively via patching or even coding, but it is beyond my reach at the moment.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 12:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Your Music/Projects</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/tx81z-inspired-delay-and-midi-effect-patch/6554.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>TX81Z inspired delay and midi effect patch</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paulus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/paulus">@Paulus</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey guys, I finally took the time to finish one of the first project I started with my Axoloti. <br>This video is a jam / demo (with the Shruthi as a demo synth) of the different functions, the description of which is below:</p>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
    <a href="https://www.facebook.com/PPaulusmusic/videos/698576777546645/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">facebook.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://scontent-amt2-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t15.5256-10/p200x200/92996610_698589854212004_6479255068515237888_n.jpg?_nc_cat=102&amp;_nc_sid=ad6a45&amp;_nc_ohc=mUptHPTRxuMAX_R-nJF&amp;_nc_ht=scontent-amt2-1.xx&amp;_nc_tp=6&amp;oh=a94044142735ceb27b1d188fe5bdb1cd&amp;oe=5EB46885" width="" height="" class="thumbnail">

<h3><a href="https://www.facebook.com/PPaulusmusic/videos/698576777546645/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Midi Mangler</a></h3>

<p>🐦 Avec les sessions studio, les concerts et les tournées annulés, j’ai pu trouver le temps de finir quelques projets que j’avais démarré sur la...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>


<p>I started this patch with a fairly faithful reproduction of the MIDI delay of the Yamaha TX81Z FM Synth which I ended up customizing.</p>

<p>The Midi Mangler collects midi signals, here from the LXR and transform and repeat them.<br>The velocity of each note received subordinates the amount of note repeated, this amount is also controlled by a pot.<br>Main functions:<br>-Time: speed of the delay, synchronizable in midday (several divisions of the clock possible)<br>-Pitch: each repeated note is increased or subtracted by one octave successively<br>-Feedback: amount of note repeated<br>-Bend: amount of pitch bend</p>

<p>I also added more versatile functions:<br>-Random: at the press of the button concerned, each pitch and velocity is randomized<br>-Octave: the starting octave of the note can be changed<br>-CC random: at each trigger of a note, the program will apply an arbitrary change of value to a CC chosen at random<br>-PC random: at each trigger of a note, the program will send an arbitrary Program Change signal (basically, we change presets on the target Synth)</p>

<p>And two utility options:<br>-Midi channel: you can choose the midi channel of the target Synth<br>-CutOff CC: with each repeated note, a CC signal is sent with a decreasing value. We can therefore choose here to which Control Change we send these values. It can be used to simulate the drop in volume of a delay with the CC of the frequency of a filter, but also to other destinations such as resonance of a filter, VCA, waveform etc ...</p>

<p>I will probably add more and more bizarre randomization options and perhaps LFOs applicable to CC.</p>

<p>At the moment, it is a monophonic patch, I first have to clean it and try if it would work polyphonically.<br>It is also why i'm not sharing it yet, I think it is too messy. I also believe a lot of functions I created could be done more effectively via patching or even coding, but it is beyond my reach at the moment.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/tx81z-inspired-delay-and-midi-effect-patch/6554/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/tx81z-inspired-delay-and-midi-effect-patch/6554/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 12:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6554-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/tx81z-inspired-delay-and-midi-effect-patch/6554.rss">TX81Z inspired delay and midi effect patch</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
