<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Missing Objects?</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423</link>
    <description>Starting about 2 weeks ago, using the Axo Patcher at home I am noticing some objects have gone missing and I can&#39;t seem to figure out why - specifically the sss/clock2timing but it seems there are a few more missing as well (not at home to have a full list) but even ones that I&#39;ve embedded in the patch because of some changes.  I&#39;ve tried uninstalling and reinstalling the patcher, resyncing libraries, reloading objects and still having the same issues.  Things that worked great in the patches before are just missing on my home computer.  I thought maybe it was the computer so I switched from my tower to my laptop (both of which had no problems until recently) and same issue there.

I opened the patches on my work computer today and there are no red objects and everything is fine - any idea what could be causing this mismatch on my home computers?  Was there some kind of change in the libraries that for some reason were not updated for me on those computers?

Thanks!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 23:55:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Helpdesk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dontjudgedave David]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dontjudgedave">@dontjudgedave</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Don't know if it'd be related but I will also note that all the patches that contained patches with missing objects seem to be the ones I am having issues with volume from the input.  like 3 of my 8 patches I have in my bank all randomly dropped like 60% of the guitar volume.  No change on the sounds generated in the axo (synth/keys/drums/etc) but my guitar going through cannot be heard unless I crank the volume after it.  Again, did not do any changes on the axo prior to this happening just turned it on one day and thought I had no volume at all and trouble shot until I found it was just not coming through the axo.  Checked all cables and everything and they all work fine.  This was the reason I went back to the patcher in the first place to try and fix the volume issue.</p>

<p>Can't imagine theyre related issues but thought it was worth noting...really a bummer.  I assume if I got the patcher working right I could redo the patches and fix the volume issue</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/8</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 23:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-8</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dontjudgedave David]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dontjudgedave">@dontjudgedave</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Its weird, everything works completely fine for me on my office computer - no missing objects or anything which leads me to believe its something with my computer on my end </p>

<p>The reset all at home said it completed successfully, did not see any errors but would still see when I loaded my patch that the clock2timing was red in the patcher, same with the fuzzysync missing the sixsync object.  </p>

<p>Can't imagine what could be causing the error as the patcher and those objects were running find on both home computers before and I had not made any changes besides moving to a new apartment with new internet.  Definitely strange but since I got it to work with an embedded object I may just do that as needed - seems the Clock2Timing was the main object I was missing that I use in a lot of patches.  Planning to build a new computer very soon so may just chalk it up to something just being fucky with my current old garbage computers</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 21:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-7</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I only looked at the one patch that you gave any details for... "Tiar FuzzySync" , and that worked fine for me once id sync'd properly.<br>does that patch not work for you?</p>

<p>did the reset all report any errors?</p>

<p>really this is a failsafe, since it deletes the community library and redownloads it, so it should be the same for everyone once this is done... unless for some reason it fails, but then it would report an error.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 21:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-6</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dontjudgedave David]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dontjudgedave">@dontjudgedave</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Tried a "reset all" and still having the same issues</p>

<p>I was able to embed the clock2timing in a patch at work and that ended up working for me at home but still unsure why some objects would be missing.  For the most part it seems like only a few are missing so I guess I can make a list and copy them like I did with the clock2timing but still doesn't explain the problem.  Im assuming its something with my computer, its really low on memory maybe its trying to reload objects and just cant?  (its a like 5yr old netbook) Going to try to restore it this weekend if I get a chance maybe that will help</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 14:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-5</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dontjudgedave David]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dontjudgedave">@dontjudgedave</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I've tried "sync library" quite a few times with the same result.  I'll try to reset all when I get home later tonight, didn't know that option was there - thanks!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 20:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-4</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>you need to sync your library...</p>

<p>if that's not working then you need to reset your libraries (make sure you back up your own patches/objects first)<br>file-&gt;preferences-&gt;reset all</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 19:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-3</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dontjudgedave David]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dontjudgedave">@dontjudgedave</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Bump - was looking through other patches last night and it seems like things are missing all over the place, even from patches in the community library (Think it was the Tiar FuzzySync patch and it was missing the tiar/osc/steps/sixsync).  Again, all these objects are working fine on my work computer.  </p>

<p>Any ideas what could be causing this or what I may need to update?  My tower at home was recently reformatted and updated to Windows 10 and have had a bunch of problems installing the patcher but my laptop has had no changes and had all the objects previously so I can't imagine what got messed up to cause this.  Again, I've tried reinstalling multiple times with no success </p>

<p>Another side issue, I hadn't used the patcher in a month or two as I've had a few patches in my Axo that were working great until the other day, my guitar input has dropped signifigantly for no reason - synth sounds and everything else patched in work as they should at normal volume but just the guitar through dropped - this is why I went back to the patcher with plans to find/resolve that issue</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 15:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-2</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Missing Objects?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dontjudgedave David]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dontjudgedave">@dontjudgedave</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Starting about 2 weeks ago, using the Axo Patcher at home I am noticing some objects have gone missing and I can't seem to figure out why - specifically the sss/clock2timing but it seems there are a few more missing as well (not at home to have a full list) but even ones that I've embedded in the patch because of some changes.  I've tried uninstalling and reinstalling the patcher, resyncing libraries, reloading objects and still having the same issues.  Things that worked great in the patches before are just missing on my home computer.  I thought maybe it was the computer so I switched from my tower to my laptop (both of which had no problems until recently) and same issue there.</p>

<p>I opened the patches on my work computer today and there are no red objects and everything is fine - any idea what could be causing this mismatch on my home computers?  Was there some kind of change in the libraries that for some reason were not updated for me on those computers?</p>

<p>Thanks!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 14:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5423-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/missing-objects/5423.rss">Missing Objects?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
