<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Playing midi files</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/playing-midi-files/6694</link>
    <description>I was playing around with my axoloti and I was surprised at I can be used as MIDI interface. 
With a simple MIDI thru object you can have a din IN/OUT for your DAW. 
So, I connected my microkorg and volca, and I patched a DX7 synth and one drum every instrument at different MIDI channels and I can route midi tracks from Reaper to each instrument separated, all with cc control, and also fx from the axo. Working. Cool feature.
Ok, now, I want to take this set without a computer for live instances, having all the machines playing live, so I save the midi file in Reaper, upload it to the Axoloti and play it from the &quot;jt/midi/play&quot; object. Not having the same output. Strange things happen.
@lysander, are all messages (ch, cc) suported? (Great job, anyway!) 
Have someone idea of what&#39;s happening?

I make this topic also to discuss this matters.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 20:12:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/playing-midi-files/6694.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Playing midi files</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@PabloEnelotromundo PabloEnelotromundo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/pabloenelotromundo">@PabloEnelotromundo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was playing around with my axoloti and I was surprised at I can be used as MIDI interface. <br>With a simple MIDI thru object you can have a din IN/OUT for your DAW. <br>So, I connected my microkorg and volca, and I patched a DX7 synth and one drum every instrument at different MIDI channels and I can route midi tracks from Reaper to each instrument separated, all with cc control, and also fx from the axo. Working. Cool feature.<br>Ok, now, I want to take this set without a computer for live instances, having all the machines playing live, so I save the midi file in Reaper, upload it to the Axoloti and play it from the "jt/midi/play" object. Not having the same output. Strange things happen.<br><a class="mention" href="/u/lysander">@lysander</a>, are all messages (ch, cc) suported? (Great job, anyway!) <br>Have someone idea of what's happening?</p>

<p>I make this topic also to discuss this matters.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/playing-midi-files/6694/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/playing-midi-files/6694/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 20:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6694-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/playing-midi-files/6694.rss">Playing midi files</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
