<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037</link>
    <description>hi, 

any ideas on how to add more MIDI DIN ins/out to Axoloti?

I can see there is an additional RX/TX not the back connections... so presumably this could add one more in and out?   (need a +5v out for din) ... but Id really want more.

presumably for more, we could turn to the digital I/O pins, and link to some kind of  UART to create a serial link?
is this viable? or very complex? 

does anyone know of any example circuits, perhaps produced for another board (ardiuno etc) 

ideal scenario, would perhaps be putting 4 - 8 (!) IO din on a separate expansion board with the dins + any other required electronics. (uarts), circuits I&#39;ve seen so far, seem within my (limited) build abilities, just Ive no idea on how to design such a thing :) 


what sparked this idea was a review on sonicstate of the Sipario. see [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6ZmS5lt5anM), which is basically an intelligent midi router

... and I thought, thats cool, but I could do that easily with Axoloti... and actually better in some ways due to having both usb midi device and host. BUT as pointed out, lack of midi din is an issue...
(the Sipario has 2x i/o,  but really something like 4x io would be ideal for an intelligent midi mangler)

of course, what I like about axoloti, is it can go much further, not just mapping midi, but also sequencing, and also &#39;midi effects&#39;...  downside (aside from the midi din i/o) is UI, but Ive ideas for that :) 

note: yeah, I could to this with multiple axoloti boards, but seems a little excessive for this use.

funny, Ive a few axoloti boards, but just keep finding so many uses for them... and nice to be able to have them have &#39;dedicated&#39; (but programmable) functions littered around my studio.

anyway, any thoughts on more midi din i/o?
thanks
Mark</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 18:58:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@squeedee Rasheed Abdul-Aziz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/squeedee">@squeedee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="30" data-topic="2037"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/thetechnobear/40/6_1.png" class="avatar">thetechnobear:</div>
<blockquote><p>iConnectMidi4+</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Which if you just want this kind of functionality (vs making the axo do it), is a great piece of kit, especially because it has a virtual audio interface for the USB devices attached.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 18:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-33</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/users/mongrol">@mongrol</a> t was because of the teensy 3.2 that I ended up getting an axoloti, to follow on from that, as I've got an stm32F4-Disco board sitting here, it looks like this thread and the axoloti is going to finally make me take a look at midibox and build a mhbp_core board, I've got most of the stuff here, I just need a couple of ICs.</p>

<p>I bought the teensy 3.2 to play with the audio lib, I figured if I can't build something myself (probably due to lack of coding skill) I can use the 3.2 in one of the many eurorack modules it's been used in.</p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/users/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> it'll be interesting to see what you come up with <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/smile.png?v=2" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-32</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mongrol]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mongrol">@mongrol</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree that the arduino platform is easier to developer of. I personally find Teensy 3.2 just awesome. The Midibox platform though already has Midi IIC boards developed and integrated that supports up to 4 boards with 8 ports. All of them can be individually configured to be in or out on the fly.</p>

<p><a href="http://ucapps.de/mbhp_iic_midi.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">http://ucapps.de/mbhp_iic_midi.html</a></p>

<p>Theoretically, since the boards are i2c, you could attach them onto a Teensy (or arduino).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 11:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-31</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="29" data-topic="2037"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/r/13edae/40.png" class="avatar">Reggie:</div>
<blockquote><p>I'm intrigued what <a class="mention" href="/users/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wants to make as well?</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>basically, something that act as a router for midi, with a fair amount of configurability in routing  and mapping midi messages.... that can then be saved and recalled. (either as patches, presets /data files) .</p>

<p>don't get me wrong, i know exactly how to do this... and I also have multiple axolotis, which I can chain... I could also potentially you a BBB/Bela as a 'hub' - also of course, I could just go buy a iConnectMidi4+</p>

<p>so really this started, see first post, as more a simplification of this...<br>could i do it with one axoloti board?, with a simple 'daughter board' that plugged in. a cheap and cheerful solution... with just a bit of coding on the axoloti.</p>

<p>(as by-product , i also thought it might be interesting to other axoloti users.... again a reason for simplicity) </p>

<p>the reason I've hesitated in USB connection, as i mentioned, is I do have USB class compliant midi devices, so i need at least one usb port for that.<br>I will admit, the lack of USB hub support on axoloti, is a minor 'issue', which actually makes the USB shield quite interesting.  (also it seems to support USB 2.0 which is useful)<br>(btw: <a class="mention" href="/users/johannes">@johannes</a> the usb shield 2.0 , is another good source for looking at usb drivers,  especially for inspiration for the usb hub support.  when my 'desk' clears a bit, I may take a look... though its still a non-trivial task)</p>

<p>Midibox, yup very familiar with this, and really if I had time to build one, id be tempted, as much for the build experience as anything else... but really I don't need much of what it provides, and having checked the manual, the software, does go in a direction I'm interested in. (Im much more interested in the Squarp <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=2" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:">) yes, I know its open source... but I don't have time for coding another platform <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> <br>(also, I don't think its supports usb hubs)<br>... that said, the code base is awesome, Ive checked it a few times when doing things on the axoloti usb midi implementation.</p>

<p>upshot is... when I'm placing my next order for electrical components, I'll make a call... try to find a balance on something thats not too coding intensive. </p>

<p>but for now I'm tempted to use Bela, and then use axoloti as daughter boards... its a bit 'heavy' for a simple midi router, but is in line with my 'main project' anyway, but it'll only become an issue when I need to use the other axoloti's for synthesis and fx. </p>

<p>this thread has really opened my eyes up to arduino and teensy options. I knew of there existence etc, but never really looked into what they could do, they do provide some nice small package options. Im sure at some point I will do something with them. so thanks for the ideas and information.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/30</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 09:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-30</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I looked at midi-box in the past, it looks really well done but for my smaller needs so far the arduino platform has handled it all really well, it's great to have options!!</p>

<p>What extras can the midi-box do mongrol?  I'm intrigued what <a class="mention" href="/users/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wants to make as well?  </p>

<p>I've got a few more bits of midi gear here that I haven't mentioned that I think would make some really nice control surfaces, like a behringer cmd pl-1, lots of buttons, rotary encoders, platter, banks.  </p>

<p>I haven't had a chance to play with the axoloti properly yet but ultimately I'd like to see a comprehensive set of functions to deal with all of the different midi data-types for rotary encoders, hi-res pitch/nrpns pots/faders etc.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/29</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 23:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-29</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mongrol]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mongrol">@mongrol</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ah. To me the obvious platform to get multi-IO and intelligence is the Midibox platform. They have very flexible IO options and MIOS32 already contains high level functions for doing all of this stuff.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 23:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-28</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I'm torn between using the gear I've got and making something, I've got an arturia minilab (25 keys, 16 rotary encoders, 8 pads, across 8 or 16 banks), emu xboard (49 key, 16 pots).  Ultimately I think I'd like at least a bunch of pots/encoders and buttons on a panel hardwired to the axoloti.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/27</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 20:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-27</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>as always, many ways to get to a similar place...<br>from reading the alternatives (and there are I'm sure many more), it will come down to how much extra hardware you want to buy, how much soldering you want to do, and how much coding...<br>so solution will be different for different people.</p>

<p>I'll have to think a bit, as I'm currently coding for not only axoloti, but also now bela (beaglebone), so do I want to add arduino too <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> <br>... and I think i was kind of hoping for more of a hardware diy project, rather than another software one, but hey i guess everything comes down to software these days.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-26</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mnskll Måns Kärnekull]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mnskll">@mnskll</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="24" data-topic="2037"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/r/13edae/40.png" class="avatar">Reggie:</div>
<blockquote><p>If you want 7 ports then 2 mega boards + onboard would do that and you wouldn't really need any host shields or to involve usb at all.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>my point is then you take advantage of the factory axo midi handling that is already there in the firmware, you don't need to write any additional midi code (on the axo, you'll have to do it on the arduinos naturally) using an extra uart for midi takes additional processing <br>I don't know if there is anything actual to gain here, but it's just a though, and, it could possibly give you 10 midi ports<br>but it's probabely total overkill <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/grin.png?v=2" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/25</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-25</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It seems like you're overly complicating things?  Outline exactly what you want <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/smile.png?v=2" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"> if you want 3 extra midi in/out ports on the axo, the simplest and cheapest would probably be a teensy 3.2, it's got 3 hardware serial ports and the arduino library will allow you to use a pair of pins for software serial any of which could be used to connect to the axoloti, leaving 3 midi in/outs + the onboard ports.  If you want 7 ports then 2 mega boards + onboard would do that and you wouldn't really need any host shields or to involve usb at all.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-24</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mnskll Måns Kärnekull]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mnskll">@mnskll</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>axoloti has 3 ways of getting midi in as fara as I understand, regular midi, usb midi through host connection and attached via usb to a hostcomputer, but the latter connection would work connected to an arduino with a usb host shield, wouldn't it?<br>to get 7 midi connections, use 2 arduino mega's, one with a usb host shield, and connect the axo's usb to that and get 3 midi that way, use the other mega with flashed usb-chip to make it into a usb-midi-device and get 3 more midi ports that way, and lastly the regular midi port is another, so that makes 7. if you manage to use another hw-serial on the axo for midi, use another mega and that's 3 more ports and 10 total. it should work, shouldn't it?<br>there is also a small clone of the mega called the meduino mega2560 (check eBay) if you are worried about the size of the thing.<br>also, the usb host shield supports usb hubs, so that is a way to get loads of usb-midi connections (I'm away for holiday, so I can't check this myself right now, but it's supposed to work), there is a mini version of the host shield that works with teensy and the regular for arduino</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/23</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 17:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-23</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>yeah, understandably the focus has been on how...<br>but as i mentioned in the first post:<br></p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="2037"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/thetechnobear/40/6_1.png" class="avatar">thetechnobear:</div>
<blockquote><p>what sparked this idea was a review on sonicstate of the Sipario. see here, which is basically an intelligent midi router</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>the primary purpose is intelligent routing of midi, using the axoloti to store CC mappings, program changes and routing to various devices.</p>

<p>the midithru only covers output, where as ideally, Id like both input and output, so that the axoloti acts as a 'intelligent hub'.</p>

<p>I think some interesting options have come up here. I need to consider each, and determine the amount of software development on each... then I can order some parts <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> <br>thanks all for your suggestions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 23:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-22</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mongrol]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mongrol">@mongrol</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I'm missing the point here. Using a Teensy or some other device just ends up with a Midi splitter. For that purpose why not just get a MidiThru from Midisizer? Send Midi-Out to it from the Axo UART. You can power it from the Axo and also put it in the same enclosure so it looks like an all in one unit.</p>

<p>On the bandwith question. I have a Midi-Thru, which has 1 Midi-In and 6 Midi-Out and I drive all those Out's from a MidiboxSEQ simulatenously and it never drops a note or loses clock.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 23:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-21</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrBim Bim ]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mrbim">@MrBim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>i have a mega2560 connected via rx/rx3 (arduino) and PA2/3( axoloti) running midi. <br>I used the extra midi I/o object in Paul's Comunity patch folder.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/20</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 17:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-20</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>atmega 168 chips @ 16mhz can handle upto 1Mbps over uart, I think you're good to go on this one.  The teensy 3.2 is a 96Mhz cortex chip...</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/19</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 11:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-19</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>never looked at the Teensy world...</p>

<p>so a Teensy 3, appears to have 3 uarts, so if you use one for communicating with axoloti, thats means only 2 additional midi ports. <br>I guess like connecting to an arduino and option would be to use, so you then get 3 more midi ports.</p>

<p>I like the uart idea, as it seems simpler to code (though im sure there are tricky bits still)...<br>but what are the maximum data rates?  if your servicing say 2 extra midi din, then between axo and teensy/arduino, you need to be at 2*31k so ~62k, for 3, is going to be ~94k,  is this reliable over serial?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 09:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-18</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mongrol]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mongrol">@mongrol</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Axo UART -&gt; Teensy UART then logically split based on channel to more MIDI-Outs hanging off the teensy.</p>

<p>Of course, this needs some code (not much) and your using the Teensy as a splitter. Which essentially is the same thing as building a <a href="https://midisizer.com/midithru/" rel="nofollow">MidiThru</a>. The benefit is the channel from Axo to Teensy is UART so shouldn't need any of the extra's (opto etc)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/17</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 02:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-17</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>thanks guys... as i said was naive hope, nothing more... <br>theres enough IO on axoloti for dedicated midi in and out... and now Ive learnt a little more about optocouplers , thanks <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-16</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@johannes johannes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/johannes">@johannes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Making a bidirectional midi port?<br>A regular optocoupler only works one way. Adding output functionality to a DIN midi port, without destroying the properties of the (opto)isolated input requires an isolated output too, but a MIDI output needs a bit of power, so then needs an isolated power supply. Something like ADuM5241 provides bidirectional data isolation and isolated power in a single chip, but I don't care enough for bidirectional midi ports to do the design work..</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 15:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-15</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mnskll Måns Kärnekull]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mnskll">@mnskll</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/users/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> I don't think it will work, but I'm really not sure here.</p>

<p>You can't send anything out through the optocoupler, it's one-way, and as far as I understand midi is communicating byis sinking the +5v signal, so the connection is normally high when nothing is being sent. when no midi cable is connected the input is null meaning the optocoupler is giving 0V sinking the signal on the input pin. If you want the same pin to work as an midi output, it is already low from the optocoupler, so you can't use the pin for communication. if you set it to high it will probably create a shortcut.</p>

<p>Please correct me if I'm wrong, I am just guessing here..</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-14</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>All of the arduino/teensy boards support midi via serial, so you're not stuck with using usb-midi if you don't need it, in that respect you just pick the arduino with the right number of uarts to give you the midi IO you need <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-13</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>yeah, I'm trying to avoid usb, as the arduino only has 1 usb port, and the axoloti only has one usb host port... <br>so if I use this for comms, then Ive no USB hosting ability, which Id like to keep <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/users/johannes">@johannes</a> that actually was kind of what I was wondering initially... i was assuming to dedicate an axoloti to the task, so the achieved performance, would lead to how many ports it could support. <br>a very naive questions... if you did this as a software uart , and put an optocoupler on both ports, could you have each port then configurable as input or output? <br>(I'm assuming we use the digital io ports on the axo board, and I think this are bi-directional )</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/12</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-12</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@johannes johannes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/johannes">@johannes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One extra DIN MIDI in/out pair is easy, via uart on GPIO. For midi input, I strongly recommend not skipping an optocoupler, and 6N137 rather than 6N138. There is no optocoupler on MIDI output, the input is supposed to have it. <br>Use separate 220 ohm resistors for each output, and two per output like here <a href="https://www.arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/Midi" rel="nofollow">https://www.arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/Midi</a><br>Some sources suggest using a single 220 ohm resistor between TX and the midi out socket, I don't recommend that.</p>

<p>(Many) more extra <em>outputs</em> could also be created with just Axoloti with a "software uart", driven by a high priority timer interrupt at 31.25kHz, scanning out start, stop and data bits in firmware to regular gpio pins. This adds a lot of context switching to firmware, which is not really nice, and time spent in the interrupt service routine should be minimized.<br>In a similar way, inputs could be done in a "software-uart", but need to sample the input at at least triple speed, align to the start bit etc, way more fiddly than output.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-11</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Reggie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/reggie">@Reggie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/users/mnskll">@mnskll</a> that's what we needed, an expert <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=2" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:">  If you want usb-midi + 3 uarts and no messing around, a teensy 3.2 will do the job very well, without needing an extra programmer, teensyduino is also an excellent collection of libraries addons that compliment the arduino IDE, with midi (normal and usb) libs and a raft of others.  </p>

<p>I'm trying to remember if I needed an extra programmer for the mega2560, I'm pretty sure I didn't, I just needed to do a vulcan death grip on the ISP pins to flip it into dfu mode and program via usb.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-10</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mnskll Måns Kärnekull]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mnskll">@mnskll</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>you should use a resistor to every contact, don't be cheap <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/smiley.png?v=2" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"></p>

<p>as <a class="mention" href="/users/reggie">@Reggie</a> says you can use the usb port and you can flash the usb-chip to act as usbmidi device, (you ned a programmer like a usbasp or just another arduino acting as a programmer to flash the chip) and then connect it to the usbhost jack, that is absolutely the simplest way to connect it if you don't use that for anything else, BUT the arduino USB still uses the serial port so you only get 3 ports left on the mega</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-2037-9</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/adding-additional-midi-dins-i-o/2037.rss">Adding additional MIDI DINs (I/O)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
