<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365</link>
    <description>**IMPORTANT :**
**Please note that despite the title, this thread was originally part of another thread and was not intended to be an Analogue versus Digital debate, but rather my opinion as to why digitally modeled instruments will always be restricted to the quantized nature of a digital system.**

Regards the talk about modeled instruments Vs real ones etc, I&#39;ve held off talking about that for a very good reason, but in the end I feel I need to say my bit about it.  It&#39;s gonna be long one, so maybe grab a coffee for this one if you fancy listening to my ramblings!

Being an Axoloti user I can imagine I come across as one who is generally ok about digital instruments.  Fact is though, I went through a period where I pretty much hated &quot;digital&quot; instruments of any description.  It wasn&#39;t due to any specific synthesizer though, it was simply due to playing music on a cassette deck (analogue of course) - and realising that digital audio is never going to sound and behave like that.

I was wise enough to hang on to my analogue gear and have been buying even more lately.  Digital will never better the real thing.  Nothing that is quantized (digital) can be more natural than something that is not quantized (analogue).  People argue that it&#39;s not as simple as that, well _**yes it is**_ as simple as that.  The only reason they argue it&#39;s not as simple as that is because they have no argument.  They lose each time because digital audio is quantized no matter what resolution it is, that&#39;s what digital is.  It&#39;s a stream of digital levels played back at high enough speed to fool you.

Analogue isn&#39;t out to fool anyone, analogue is the real deal.  Analogue is not quantized fakery, and we all know what digital means don&#39;t we?  That&#39;s right chaps, it means it&#39;s fake.  They might as well call the technology &quot;Fake&quot;, because it means exactly the same thing as &quot;Digital&quot; when it comes to audio - or in fact anything.

Digital = Fake = Fact

So when it comes to modeled instruments (digital), I&#39;m going to be the first to agree that no matter how far it advances, it will always suffer the same misfortune of **_being_** fake, just like the technology that powers it.  This is a fact given that no matter how hard you try, something fake is never going to be real; a modeled violin is never going to be **_a_** violin.

But it&#39;s not all bad, cause while I laugh at people who don&#39;t understand why Analogue technology is superior to Digital, I have gathered quite a fondness for Digital technology lately.  My fondness for it though (and you&#39;re not going to like this), is based upon the premise that digital should be used for what it&#39;s actually good at - (low fidelity).

The LinnDrum is a perfect example of this.  It&#39;s blatantly digital and low-fidelity, but I love it, and here is where digital interests me, cause for me, digital is best placed being blatantly digital.  As long as it&#39;s not trying to be analogue (which is never gonna happen), then I&#39;m generally fine with digital for certain things.  So I love digital when it falls into that sweet-spot of being crunchy and low-fidelity, but no so much as to render it with blatant artefacts.

My only other love for digital is recording it in analogue.  Recording stuff like a LinnDrum and some of those early low-fi samplers like the Fairlight, in analogue, is one of the best combinations ever (it&#39;s why most music recorded in the 80s blows the socks of the stuff recorded today).  So what I&#39;m saying is, just like a violin is best suited to being played in the way it is, and a piano is best suited to being played in the way it is, digital is best suited at being _**what**_ it is (quantized).  It&#39;s only when it&#39;s trying to be something it will never be, that I generally hate it. 

Take the vinyl record.  The format was around long before I was born and it will still be around long after every one of us are dead.  It&#39;s an analogue format, and the reason it will survive is because it&#39;s good, honest technology.  You can make your own turntable out of houshold goods if you wanted to, and now, people are developing their own portable record cutting machines to bring to market - all analogue.

Digital technology has never been that accessible.  Axoloti is a dream come true for doing things digitally, but you won&#39;t be making an Axoloti out of household goods as you could a turntable.  Which brings me to the final reason why real (analogue) will always win over fake (digital) ... it&#39;s because it&#39;s _**real**_, simple as that.

Well I hope the coffee lasted, and that all had the priviledge of drinking _**real**_ coffee, not digital coffee :grin:</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:39:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Lounge</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/dolphinwolf">@Dolphinwolf</a><br>What you describe sounds like a DAC, something like demonstrated in this video, basically a bunch of resistors, but I'm not sure you'd be able to build one for Axoloti as there's a DAC already fitted to the board, situated before the audio out.  Axoloti is already doing what you describe as part of the hardware spec, unless I'm misunderstanding you.  There might be a way to bypass it and use your own, but that's a bit beyond me at the moment <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="bXUfDLF4MVc" data-youtube-title="DAC Methods R2R Ladder" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/chaocrator">@chaocrator</a><br>My hearing is not digital, nor is yours, cause digital is a man-made system (it's computer speak) whereas your hearing system is both organic in nature, and analogue in operation.  I sometimes wonder whether it's just the names used in Digital technology that draw people to it.</p>

<p>Fact is though, Analogue technology has much cooler terms, such as 'Electron Gun' <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sunglasses.png?v=5" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p>

<p>I mean come on, <em><strong>"Electron Gun"</strong></em>, how <strong><em>bloody</em></strong> cool does that sound?  And they're real, not science fiction, Electron Guns were used to display the image on the screen of analogue display equipment like this:</p>

<p>Ladies and Gentlemen, I give you a box with an actual Electron Gun inside of it.  Make no mistake, if you were to remove the back panel and touch one, you'd be looking at 'Death by Electron Gun' ... but still ... <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/star_struck.png?v=5" title=":star_struck:" class="emoji" alt=":star_struck:"></p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="vjfdljReeac" data-youtube-title="1985 - Sony" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/93">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/93</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 11:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-93</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chaocrator a.k.a. Vimanastaffel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/chaocrator">@chaocrator</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>by the way. <br>human hearing is <strong>digital</strong>.<br>because sound is transmitted to the eardrum via very large, but <strong>finite</strong> number of <strong>discrete</strong> air molecules. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sunglasses.png?v=5" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/92">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/92</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 21:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-92</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dolphinwolf Jeffrey David Anderson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dolphinwolf">@Dolphinwolf</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Would it be possible to build a machine that senses the seperate quantized digital states of the analog audio output of the Axoloti? Lets also give as a caveat to this audio Turing Test that the output is coupled acoustically to the air via speaker.   A reverse Axoloti, able to recreate the exact digital code of the now acoustic waveform (without give aways as to the sample rate and bit depth).  I would guess no, that the jaggedness of the waveform would be sufficiently filtered, but I am a bicycle mechanic and not an engineer.  </p>

<p>I love analog cause you can touch it and twist it and find the sweet spot.  I love digital because of state saving, bit crushing insane manipulations you can do to a signal through time.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/91">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/91</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 16:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-91</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You're explaining in a similar fashion to Sputnki, and just like Sputnki, you continue to dismiss the main fact that is pointed out time and time again.  You cannot take an analogue signal, convert it into computer speak, then convert it back to analogue and expect that it would be superior in any way whatsoever, to keeping it analogue in the first place and avoiding two conversion stages in the process.</p>

<p>The stuff Sputnki and yourself speak of also dismisses the fact that analogue is a completely different thing to digital.  Trying to lump analogue under the "quantized" hammer is completely pointless.  Digital is a man-made quantization system, analogue is not.  Humans do not listen in Digital, they listen in Analogue.  The cheap DIY turntable video I posted earlier demonstrates this perfectly.  You ain't listening to any CD or MP3 in such a "direct" no-nonsense fashion.</p>

<p>So that's it in a nutshell (for me anyway).  Analogue sound reproduction is better primarily because it is the purest way to store and replay sound.  That's the main aspect.  The second aspect, is that is simply sounds better.  Components, choice of media etc, it all makes a difference, and the beauty of it all is that every component in the sytem is reacting to the way it's designed, giving any analogue device it's characteristic sound.  Poor design gives poor performance, good design gives good performance, exceptional design gives exceptional performance - which is why NEVE and SSL consoles cost what they do - it's expertise in analogue design.</p>

<p>The attempts to lump analogue under the quantization hammer will not work*<br>Analogue is analogue, digital is digital - very different systems.</p>

<p>*That's not to suggest I don't appreciate the interesting stuff I read here, I love it actually.  But you're never going to convince anyone with any common sense that conversion is better than no conversion, or that analogue is a quantized system.  Like I said, that seemingly innocent video of the DIY-turntable using cardboard, either it will trigger something in people, maybe help them understand all they need to understand, or it won't.</p>

<p>And if it doesn't, then I really feel for those who don't get it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/89">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/89</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 09:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-89</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rsdio Brian Willoughby]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/rsdio">@rsdio</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="87" data-topic="3365"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/a/848f3c/40.png" class="avatar">axoman:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>You're talking about a different thing there.   Sure, an analogue recording of an instrument is going to be inferior to the sound you heared live, but the same is true of digital.  The point is that sound travels, and causes vibration, completely in the analogue domain, so obviously it's better to capture those vibrations directly to an anlogue format than it is to quantize it, process it, then convert it back to analogue so you can actually hear it.</p>
<p>As I said earlier, it would go against physics to suggest that converting something from analogue to digital and then back to analogue is better than just letting it remain analogue in the first place.  With analogue tape the vibrations are stored magnetically, and with analogue vinyl, through the groove cut by a vibrating stylus.</p>
<p>Analogue is the daddy - as pure and direct as it gets.</p>
</blockquote></aside>

<p>Except that it's not direct. Air, electrons, and magnetic particles can each be described using multiple terms - "analog" is only one part of the description. You're making the mistake of thinking that Voltage is the same thing as air pressure just because they're both analog. You've oversimplified the comparison, and then convinced yourself that they're the same when they're not.</p>

<p>You're not literally recording air. There is a transducer that converts air movement into Voltage fluctuations. Another transducer converts Voltage fluctuations into magnetic fields for tape, but slower tape speeds end up having fewer magnetic particles. Tape is even "digital" in some sense, because there's a threshold below which it doesn't work, due to hysteresis. Below the threshold, tape records and plays a "0" - above the threshold it's basically analog. Tape bias works around this semi-digital limitation of tape by mixing in an ultrasonic frequency. But if you think about it, this means that tape is sort of sampled in time, because every time the bias frequency crosses zero, there's a chance that the analog input signal is not getting recorded because the tape stores a zero. Some of the time, the signal without the bias will be strong enough on its own to exceed the threshold, but that is not true all of the time. So, between the problems of tape speed and tape bias, analog recording is neither pure nor direct. It's manipulated in many ways, some of which could be called digital or binary.</p>

<p>You've chosen to ignore all of the details that make electricity or magnetics unique, and decided that calling them analog makes them the same. Unfortunately, they're not. Conversions are needed between every analog medium, and these conversions are neither completely better nor completely worse than digital conversions. Maybe a wax cylinder recording is direct, but that doesn't allow any processing and I'm sure none of us would prefer a wax cylinder recording to a digital recording.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that everything is quantized. Air vibrations involve a finite number of molecules. Voltage fluctuations involve a finite number of electrons. Tape recordings involve a finite number of magnetic particles. Time may be continuous (the theory that time is discrete was shot down, I believe), but some of these "analog" media involve discrete time. Saying that analog is better than digital is just saying that the quantization is finer with analog, if you can detect it in the presence of noise.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/88">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/88</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 06:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-88</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/strum">@strum</a><br>I've read a few times that 48 is the sweet spot before deminishing returns.  I'm inclined to agree with it as well cause I had an external Steinberg audio interface where it actually had better noise performance and sounded better running at 48 than it did at 96.  I could tell the difference in the audio quality when feeding it with audio and switching back and forth between the two.  I definitely preferred it at 48.</p>

<p>Regards the "placebo" thing, nope, definitely not.  It's not just about how it sounds, it's about how it behaves.  I don't just mean physically in response to knobs been tweaked, I mean how it behaves when levels are pushed, and when it's being coloured by components and recording media.  That's not plecebo, it's very real, sounds different (analogue characteristics), much nicer, more solid, more width, more balls.</p>

<p>The amount of 'sound satisfaction' I get from my old 80s Hi-Fi system playing Tape or Vinyl is leaps and bounds above anything I get out of CD or MP3 or whatever - there's no comparison.  The all analogue Hi-Fi sounds big, lush, thick, soft, totally gorgeous in comparison.</p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/rsdio">@rsdio</a><br>You're talking about a different thing there.   Sure, an analogue recording of an instrument is going to be inferior to the sound you heared live, but the same is true of digital.  The point is that sound travels, and causes vibration, completely in the analogue domain, so obviously it's better to capture those vibrations directly to an anlogue format than it is to quantize it, process it, then convert it back to analogue so you can actually hear it.</p>

<p>As I said earlier, it would go against physics to suggest that converting something from analogue to digital and then back to analogue is better than just letting it remain analogue in the first place.  With analogue tape the vibrations are stored magnetically, and with analogue vinyl, through the groove cut by a vibrating stylus.</p>

<p>Analogue is the daddy - as pure and direct as it gets.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/87">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/87</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 17:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-87</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rsdio Brian Willoughby]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/rsdio">@rsdio</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Imagine for a moment that digital did not exist as a technology…</p>

<p>We could have spent this entire thread arguing about whether air or electrons are superior. One side would be arguing that air "is the daddy" and is superior. Any conversion of sound - which we hear only through the medium of air - into another format like electrons (Voltage) is inferior to "the real thing."</p>

<p>In other words, any electronic representation of sound is fake, and is inferior to the real thing. Embrace the air, fellow humans, because it is the only way we can hear sound. Every other medium must be translated into movement of air before we can hear anything.</p>

<p>Anyone with experience in electronics will understand why analog electronics are inferior. There is noise, there are unwanted radio waves that are picked up and mixed in with the audio. A reference, usually a ground voltage, is always needed to interpret any electronic waveform, and yet analog electronics suffer from ground loops and many other destructions of that reference, putting hum and other noise into our audio. I could go on for days about how electronics are inferior to acoustics, even conceding the various improvements like balanced audio, and still would be convinced that acoustic "air" is the daddy.</p>

<p>Everything else (everything that is not acoustic movement of air) is a pale, inferior copy, and is not real.</p>

<p>Now imagine that we include digital in the discussion…</p>

<p>Forget for a moment that digital is quantized and sampled. Forget what you see on the screen when you edit a digital recording. None of that matters because you can't hear it. All that you can hear is the result of those digital numbers first being converted into electronic signals, and then those resulting electronic signals being converted into acoustic vibrations of air. My point here is that the quantization no longer exists in a proper conversion with an appropriate reconstruction filter. The reconstruction filter that is required after a Digital-to-Analog converter is analog, and it fills in the gaps of the digital steps. There is no longer any instantaneous jump from one sample value to the next, and there is no longer any evidence that the time domain has been sampled, except for the lack of frequency content above a certain point, but that is equivalent to an analog low-pass filter.</p>

<p>Here I say that digital and analog are equally inferior to acoustic. Each has problems and advantages, but as time goes on, analog electronics have fewer and fewer advantages. Ideally, only a very small part of the non-acoustic representation would be analog, with the vast majority being handling in the digital domain. That would allow us to dispense with nearly all of the shortcomings of analog.</p>

<p>In the real world, where acoustics are superior to both electrons and digital numbers, there is no definitive superiority between analog electronics and digital electronics. Both are vastly inferior to the real sounds made and heard in the air. However, as many in this thread have pointed out, we humans are not all happy being limited to the sounds that can be produced acoustically. Since we desire to hear sounds that can only be produced electronically, then we must put up with the shortcomings of both analog and digital electronics.</p>

<p>If you want to understand more about digital, then I recommend reading Audio Engineering Society papers from Stanley P. Lipshitz and John Vanderkooy. Until you can understand their research on quantization and sampling, then the crude criticisms of digital waveforms that you see on your computer screens will continue to be grossly misguided.</p>

<p>Brian Willoughby<br>Sound Consulting</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/86">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/86</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 19:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-86</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@strum]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/strum">@strum</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>blind listening tests show that beyond 48k sample rate most people can't hear any difference between digital and analog.</p>

<p>Your point is valid but it's largely based on mythology and placebo effect I'm afraid.</p>

<p>You have probably never heard a truly analog recording anyway.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/85">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/85</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 02:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-85</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree, but the problem a lot of the time (and you'll notice it in this thread), is that people often dismiss the fact that the one arguing the side for analogue is <em>not</em> against digital.</p>

<p>I <em>love</em> digital every bit as much as everyone else here does.  I wouldn't want to be without digital wavetables and sampling technology either.  I plan to design and market a sample-based instrument myself, so it would be majorly hypocritical of me to be against digital.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/84">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/84</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 14:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-84</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaffasplaffa Mr. Grimm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/jaffasplaffa">@jaffasplaffa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One reason why I dont write too much in this post, cause I think it is semi-pointless.... AND it is a debate that have been discussed thousands of times on every audio forum around. And ALWAYS end up in the same place; everyone is disagreeing and putting their personal thoughts in and ends up semi fighting over somthing that is a personal choice........ And I think that is actually the REAL point here...... Do what YOU prefer to do... And dont puts limits on your creativity because of made up rules.</p>

<p>If it works for you, use it. If not, then don't. But I would like to point out that eliminating digital circuits from a studio is impossible. I mean a lot of analog synths use digital circuits to control the analog oscillators. Digital is everywhere also in analog synths. I think there are very few analog synths that are truely 100% analog these days. I couldnt live with out granular synths and wavetables.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/83">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/83</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 13:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-83</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Well I've nothing more to say, I've exhausted all explanation so I'm out of the thread from this point onward.<br>Hopefully future readers will learn something interesting from it no matter what their take on the topic.</p>

<p>Both sides have been put forward, but only one is correct.<br>I'm stickin' to real-world physics and common sense <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/grin.png?v=3" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/82">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/82</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 22:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-82</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sorry, this is driving me ever so slightly nuts now ...</p>

<p><em><strong>How on earth</strong></em> can any of what you just said be true?  I've never seen a digital scope in my life that behaves anywhere near as well as an analogue scope does!</p>

<p>And the really annoying thing, the most unbearable thing of all is that you still don't get it - but why?</p>

<p>Everything you just said can be blown-down like a matchstick house quite easily.  All I have to do is remind you that the "digital" scope you think is superior and the "digital" audio you think is superior is based on analogue technology.  Those digital systems you love so much are built from analogue components, therefore, digital is just a subset of analogue technology - and cannot exist without it.</p>

<p>So there you have it, analogue not only has the benefits unique to analogue, it also has the razor-sharp precision of digital if you want all that precision control you talk about.  Just lay-out the analogue circuit in such a way as to create a digital system - cause that's all digital is.</p>

<p>So I don't get it, what part of that are you peeps not understanding here?<br>Seriously, what part?</p>

<p><strong><em>Analogue is the daddy, it's Digital's daddy too!</em></strong><br><strong><em>Digital is an offspring of daddy, and daddy is analogue!</em></strong></p>

<p><em><strong>Analogue is the daddy!</strong></em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/81">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/81</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 21:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-81</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SteveAbx Steve McKewen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/steveabx">@SteveAbx</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I prefer a digital scope any day.<br>Analogue scopes are not accurate enough.   They give a nice smooth waveform because that is what they are designed to do.<br>A digital scope has a very clearly defined performance that makes the results much more realistic.  An analog scope doesn't show when it is distorting the signal because it can't show more detail.<br>A digital scope can react much faster than an analog scope and much more smoothly.<br>It depends on what you set it to show, and how good each one is for the measurement you are trying to take.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/80">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/80</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 20:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-80</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SteveAbx Steve McKewen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/steveabx">@SteveAbx</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Speaking for myself (someone who designs analogue microphones for sound analysis) I can tell you that analogue microphones do not capture the pure pressure waves that we hear, and those pressure waves are not transferred to vinyl to be purely replayed to us.<br>Analog is just like digital - its distortion, delay, intermodulation interference, bandwidth limiting, dynamic range loss.<br>Everything you accuse digital of doing.<br>Digital lets us make lower fidelity more easily.  We can do it with analogue but there is more control with digital.<br>We can make a specific low fidelity that we like with digital.<br>We can all make hi fidelity and we can make it adjustable.<br>You cant do that with analogue.<br>You can make hi fidelity with analogue, or any other fidelity - but not with the control and low cost that you get with digital.<br>Either way - don't think either of them is pure.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/79">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/79</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 20:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-79</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/users/ersatzplanet">@Ersatzplanet</a></p>

<p>That was the most enjoyable YouTube video I've watched in ages.  And while I'm still not convinced, watching him made me more aware of why the digital and math guys love the digital thing.</p>

<p>Now be honest, you saw first-hand a side-by-side demonstration of two instrumets in that video.  You saw how the analogue oscilloscope behaved and how the digital one behaved.  Is there anyone here who can honestly say they prefer the feedback of that "modern" digital display to the smoothness of the analogue scope?</p>

<p>And is there anyone here who can honestly say they prefer the laggy performance of the "modern" digital oscilloscope over the immediate, silky-smooth performance of the analogue scope?</p>

<p>Give me a break - I'll take the analogue scope any day (especially for working with audio).  I'd rather pay ten times the price for the analogue scope than the digital one.  You can see, right there, the difference in performance between something that is using real-world physics as opposed to something that's using a man-made quantization system.  It's a perfect example of how analogue shines!</p>

<p>I really don't know how many times I have to point this out, but analogue <em>does not</em> need to go through that conversion of A-D and D-A in the first place.  So you see, he's basically just waffling-on about a technology the analogue purists couldn't care less about.  Analogue purists couldn't care less about that stuff, they have <em>no need</em> to care about it because they <em>know</em> analogue equipment does not need <em>any</em> involvement with digital technology whatsoever.</p>

<p>People are free to listen to guys like him and be mislead by it, but I won't be.  Common sense should tell you all that if analogue has no need for digital, but digital <em>cannot</em> exist without analogue, then analogue absolutely <em>must</em> be the daddy!</p>

<p>It's like in that video I posted earlier about the Arturia MiniBrute.  There's a part where he says <em><strong>"I've got a few other synths which I won't mention.  They're supposed to be analogue and they don't sound it.  You can tell streight away that they're digital."</strong></em>.  The MiniBrute on the other hand has no chance of sounding digital, because it isn't digital, it has a 100% analogue signal path, you can tell it has just from the sound of it.</p>

<p><strong><em>"This sounds analogue ... it is, exactly ... that's exactly why it is!"</em></strong></p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="X614aeTzq7k" data-youtube-title="Portishead's Adrian Utley on Arturia MiniBrute Analog Synth" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>

<p><strong><em>Analogue is the daddy!</em></strong> <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/grin.png?v=3" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/78">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/78</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 20:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-78</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ersatzplanet James Husted]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/ersatzplanet">@Ersatzplanet</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I love how analog purist always compare an analog waveform drawing against a VERY crude stair stepped drawing of a digital waveform, a waveform than NEVER comes out of a digital device's D/A converter. Stair stepping does not exist. People just tend to draw it that way. Watch this video. It explains what I mean. Analog signal and analog scopes. - <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIQ9IXSUzuM" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIQ9IXSUzuM</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/77">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/77</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-77</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Duh, I get it now - this is an elaborate joke you're all playing on axoman!</p>

<p>I'm expecting the whole lot of you to come bursting through my door any moment, shouting <em>"surprise</em>" and  waving banners with <em>"Analogue is the daddy!"</em> written across them!</p>

<p>You peeps are just awesome, you certainly had me fooled <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/blush.png?v=3" title=":blush:" class="emoji" alt=":blush:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/76">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/76</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 11:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-76</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Analog back to front is golana..<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/grin.png?v=3" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/75">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/75</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 10:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-75</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tsturm Thomas Sturm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tsturm">@tsturm</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Nothing in this world is analog. Analog is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maya_(illusion)" rel="nofollow noopener">Maya.</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/74">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/74</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 10:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-74</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="71" data-topic="3365"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/t/8baadc/40.png" class="avatar">tsturm:</div>
<blockquote><p>If you want sense, read SteveAbx</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>If you want sense, listen to what axoman is telling you.  Everything you just wrote completely ignores the fact that something that is man-made and intentionally quantized, is no match for the real-world sound system.</p>

<p>That's what analogue is, it's the real-world sound system!</p>

<p>Ok, I'm really off now, I only just saw your post after making my last one.  Just be realistic about it, lads, that is all I am saying.  And you are not being realistic if you think conversion to computer speak followed by conversion back to analogue is better than simply keeping it analogue in the first place.</p>

<p>There is no way you are ever going to convince anyone who truly has common sense!<br>What you're claiming is completely ridiculous and physically impossible.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/73">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/73</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 09:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-73</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="66" data-topic="3365"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>Bollocks...<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/stuck_out_tongue_closed_eyes.png?v=3" title=":stuck_out_tongue_closed_eyes:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_closed_eyes:"></p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Not bollocks, fact, one you cannot change no matter how hard you try.</p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="66" data-topic="3365"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>Vibrations are vibrations, Air is just one of many mediums it can pass through.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>You poor thing, I was demonstrating the fact that the same vibration that pushes the air that vibrates your eardrum, is the same vibration that is vibrating the cutting stylus on an analogue record.  Technology does not get any more direct and purer than that.</p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="66" data-topic="3365"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>I'd love to be a robot, wouldn't have to put up with all this emotional crap... <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/sunglasses.png?v=3" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Using the word crap doesn't make you look correct, it makes you look desperate.  There's nothing emotional about what I'm saying.  Analogue is smoother because it is.  Not because of some emotional belief.</p>

<p>I would love for you to be a robot too, then at least I could switch the crap off <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/sunglasses.png?v=3" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p>

<p>You can talk rough, you can use as many smiley faces as you wish.  You can get all of your friends the web over to come here and give you a like for being misinformed, but you cannot change the facts.</p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/users/steveabx">@SteveAbx</a>  and <a class="mention" href="/users/lokki">@lokki</a><br>I don't disagree with what you're trying to say, but you're missing the point.  What you're describing is that what we hear is the result of the things around us, what's in the room etc.  Yes, absolutely, I agree 100%, but what I was pointing out is the way to capture that result.  In other words, regardless of what effect the surroundings have, an analogue microphone and cutting stylus will capture that result in analogue.  Analogue being the perfect way to do it because the world around you is analogue, and the sound traveled in the analogue domain.  That analogue cutting stylus hears what you hear using 'the way of analogue' - using vibration.</p>

<p>Makes no difference what the vibration travels through, it's still done the same way.</p>

<p>It is physically impossible for any other method to be purer than that.  You <em>cannot</em> take a real-world (analogue) sound, convert it into computer speak, cut it into tiny peices, convert it back to analogue, <em>then</em> expect that the result will be purer than simply capturing analogue vibrations (in analogue) in the first place!</p>

<p>This is something our robot wannabe, Gavin, will learn eventually.</p>

<p><strong><em>Peace, my children - love your analogue for it is what you are.</em></strong><br><em><strong>It is your life, and it is your soul</strong></em> <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/sunglasses.png?v=3" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p>

<p>Anyway, I sense the great wall of attack coming on, and there are far too many people agreeing with nonsense or irrelevance, and not enough people agreeing with facts.  This is a forum dedicated to a digital product so I'm not surprised about that.  Nevertheless, I'll have to drop out at least for a while.  I was supposed to have my Linux box up and running two days ago and haven't even gotten started on the installation yet.</p>

<p>I will leave you all with one simple fact: <em><strong>Analogue is the daddy!</strong></em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/72">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/72</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 09:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-72</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tsturm Thomas Sturm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tsturm">@tsturm</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I just love this discussion! - anytime!<br>let me pour some oil into the fire, then. Because, if you're gonna be purist and get right down to it, you'll have to eventually face one fact: <strong>nothing</strong> is "analog". We live in a universe where energy is quantized. As energy is transmitted to your eardrums, there is a discrete minimum amount by which this energy may differ between two pressure peaks. Around that minimum, it will either cause a reaction or not. Binary. And even if you had ears with infinite sensitivity: whether or not they would react to that minimum change would be left to chance - because it would be chance in the first place which decides whether something they could react upon would actually reach them. Once it does, the "holy ear" would still have to produce an electric impulse of a certain strength and duration (and hence: a certain amount of energy) in response. Only, it could never do so in a continual (analog) way. The result would be evenly divisible by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planck_constant" rel="nofollow noopener">Planck constant</a>: two, fifty-thousand, 340331-fold...but never smaller than 1 (in which case even our perfect ears would not create a "signal") - or, even more to the point: there couldn't be fractions of a quantum in difference. Even god's ears are digital! <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=3" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>

<p>Of course, this is all rubbish. While fundamentally true, it will be of no consequence whatsoever to us mere humans listening to music. If you want sense, read SteveAbx:</p>

<blockquote><p>That is why some theatres are known as great rooms - they have good acoustics, and a good vibe. It is not just the acoustics.</p></blockquote>

<p>When listening to music, we're all in for the vibes. Go unpack your battered acoustic next to a campfire you're sitting around with friends. It will sound terrible. But get it right and everyone will be convinced they heard nothing more touching in their lives...</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/71">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/71</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 09:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-71</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>i completely agree! cool. and i have nothing against digital at all. after all, i own 4 axolotis by now <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/70">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/70</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 08:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-70</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SteveAbx Steve McKewen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/steveabx">@SteveAbx</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The digital synth will work as programmed.<br>But air is a very poor transmission medium.  It is lossy, and inconsistent.<br>In a room it is normal to have variations in temperature of more than 5 degrees C from one spot to another.<br>That means you get signal velocity variations, that means you get phase shifts.<br>Your sound source is a point source (or maybe a tricky speaker that pretends to make planar sound waves).<br>That gives you multiple signal paths, varying with frequency.  That gives you more phasing problems, signal cancellation, and reflections.<br>Another person in the room will be a non-uniform attenuator.<br>A vase will be a non-uniform resonator.<br>It is all easy to measure and correct if you are using a single frequency source to scan the room from multiple sources to multiple destinations and all relevant frequencies.<br>If you just use music to evaluate it, then you just get a warm, cold or flat sound, and varying levels of resonance, and damping.  That is all that ambience effects do on amplifiers.<br>But if you look at the effects on multiple tones, rather than a single tone you see what the effect on a musical note is - because musical notes are a collection of frequencies.  The more notes in a chord the harder it is to render from a signal (record or CD) and the harder it is to amplify accurately (class A, class D, whatever) and the harder it is to deliver to a listener (someone with ears) and the more variation the listener will have in experiencing the chord (because ears and heads don't work very consistently across the range of humans that currently exist).<br>In short - it is way more complicated than analog vs digital.<br>Analog processing has just as many distortion and corruption sources as digital processing.  There is good and bad analogue and good and bad digital.  If you have ever heard anything good on radio or tv, then it has almost certainly been digital at some stage and analogue at some stage.<br>Any sound source will sound different in a different room.  We tend to adjust our hearing interpretation to suit our environment.  We ignore sound differences when we are not listening for a particular sound.  When we are listening it is easy to hear what we want to, because we cant swap back and forth between environments.<br>There are physical and mental obstacles to evaluating performance spaces.  That is why some theatres are known as great rooms - they have good acoustics, and a good vibe.  It is not just the acoustics.</p>

<p></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/69">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/69</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 07:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-69</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Analogue Versus Digital</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>i'm sorry i don't quite follow.</p>

<p>i agree that all instruments will sound differently depending on room (all sorts of absorption, echo, phase cancellation etc.) and amplification (speaker, mixing desk, amplifier, microphone etc...) i can imagine an analog synth reacting to temperature and humidity in a room, so to a small degree an analog synth may also react to the room. but a digital instrument behaving differently in different rooms? (not because you programmed it to be that way) i would be very happy to own such an instrument.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/68">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365/68</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 06:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3365-68</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/analogue-versus-digital/3365.rss">Analogue Versus Digital</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
