<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154</link>
    <description>Hello, i use Axoloti with PC but wondered- can I patch on eg Ipad or Android tablet and upload to the board? 

I ask as I want to give a board to a friend who does not have a computer. Just a tablet. 

Thanks</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 18:47:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Lol at Tele for failing to answer, but liking your post <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>

<p>Dude, I had just narrowly escaped becoming homeless (by around £14 to be exact), and was then put in a position where it looked like it might happen again.  Being the profound hater I am of modern head-in-phone, social-media-poisoned, weed-puffing society, I figured that if I were to survive, I needed to avoid living on the streets among them at all costs, and camp out in the wild.  This meant I needed a waterproof, reliable piece of hardware for a phone, and something bigger to act as a computer.</p>

<p>I had the choice of submitting my privacy to Apple or Google.  They are equally abusive, but I went with Apple simply because providing I kept it mint, it would have a reasonable resale value when I come to ditch it.</p>

<p>Luckily, I won that battle and now have a very nice flat to live in, so I've been saving to buy a proper computer again, something with Linux on it that I actually have control over.  Until that happens, I'm stuck with Apple's prison, so do forgive me for thinking it appropriate that I should be able to do the sort of stuff I pointed out.</p>

<p>I think my expectations are perfectly valid, and I know for a fact that sandboxing being an option from day one, means that Apple should be hit with an epic lawsuit, and so should the American government.  The job of a government is to protect it's people, and that includes protecting them from Orwellian monopolies.</p>

<p>I don't even have furniture in this flat.  I have water and electricity, sure, but I sit and sleep on the floor, and have been doing for over a year now.  I have the cash now, and I'm currently debating with myself on whether I should buy the powerful Linux-compatible laptop I've researched, or furniture, or even a synth, because frankly, I'm finding it difficult to justify another computing device when I already have one, but don't have a synth (and I really miss having a physical synth to mess around with).</p>

<p>And before you say it, yes, I'm the sort of guy who would buy a synth even though almost everyone else would chose furniture as a priority.  I need something to keep me sane, and as good as the music apps are for the iPad, I'm afraid touch-screen interaction is not something I'm a fan of, it has to be the worst form of interaction ever devised.</p>

<p>Either way, whatever I do regards this thing, or rather, <em>whenever</em> I do it, I already pointed out to you that I will be getting rid of it, so your post does not make sense, it merely avoids answering what I put to Tele!</p>

<p>Brilliant, and you want more good news on the Apple front?  I can no longer play YouTube videos full-screen since the iPad update.  Bloody fantastic that is!  It's exactly what you need when you fancy watching a film and you naturally assume you could at the very least do something you could do before the <em>"irreversible without a computer"</em> update screwed it up.</p>

<p>No music, and no films without distraction now, bloody hell, what next?  I'd better buy a synth before I go stark raving mad, either that, or get back to the luxury of a computer I have control over ASAP!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/13</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 22:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-13</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@alanennis Alan Ennis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/alanennis">@alanennis</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Why are you holding on to it then. Apple didn't make you buy it, the government didn't either. <br>Either build something that does what you want or get rid of it then and buy something that does what you want,</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/12</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 13:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-12</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hasn't switched gears at all, the rant is there in the first place due to the outrageous restrictions Apple have in place for manipulative reasons.  I put it to you that none of these restrictions need exist, and never did need to exist due to sandboxing.</p>

<p>I brought up the limitation of importing the music to really drive-home the fact.  Believe it or not, the "rant" isn't for my benefit, it's for the benefit of anyone who might have been on the fence about buying into Apple's prison.  My personal opinion after wasting precious cash on this Orwellian piece of garbage, is quite simple, and it is this ...</p>

<p>It is both the people behind Apple, and the American Government which allows monsters like Apple to operate, that should be put in prison - not the buyers of their products.</p>

<p>I'll only feel like I've served my time for being dumb enough to buy this thing, when I've sold it to some other poor b@stard, because buying one of these things means a person deserves everything they get <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/joy.png?v=5" title=":joy:" class="emoji" alt=":joy:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 19:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-11</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Your rant has now switched gears, from programming, about which I care and am very familiar, to some complaint about music on iPad, about which I don’t care.</p>

<p>So, no, I won’t get into this, except to repeat that I too have issues with Apple, I just disagree with your assessment of Apple’s support for learning programming in C, and with the practicality and desirability of Apple providing a development system based on iPad in addition to Xcode on Mac.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/10</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 17:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-10</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You know what, I can't even transfer my own songs and audio files from a USB stick into the iTunes area of my iPad even after them supposedly opening-up the file system!</p>

<p>Why the heck not?</p>

<p>I remember years ago in one of their conferences that they said they 'cut the cord' of iOS, freeing it from the need for a computer.  What a load of nonsense, they have done nothing of the sort.  If they have then I demand the ability to now transfer a .WAV file from my USB stick into the iTunes area of my iPad.  When I heard about the new file system I thoroughly expected, at long last, to be able to use the native media player of the iPad (iTunes), to play my bloody music, but no, what they are doing is grounds for a major lawsuit.</p>

<p>Let me explain ...</p>

<p>You see Apple are quite prepared to allow you to put your own audio files into iTunes providing you do it on a computer.  So what's their bloody excuse now then, eh?</p>

<p>With the file restriction lifted, why can't I transfer a .WAV file from a USB stick and put it into the iTunes area of my iPad so that I can use the native player and make playlists etc?  It has nothing to do with prevention of malware, because surely all they would need to do is use the same detection system as they put in iTunes on the computer.</p>

<p>There is no longer an excuse for this, and as far as I'm concerned, there never was a valid excuse right from the start.  They should be hit with an epic lawsuit over it!  I hope I'm wrong and that such a restriction no longer exists, that perhaps I'm doing it all wrong and that actually, I can do whatever I want (it's my iPad after all).</p>

<p>So thumbs-up to you for the fanboy self-confession, but perhaps make some use of it and tell me how I can play my own files in the iTunes player of my iPad without needing a computer.  This is supposed to be a self-contained computer, with it's cord cut from the big computers, and now an open file system to boot, so it is perfectly understandable that as a user of iOS, I expect to be able to play my bloody music in the media player that is native to it!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/9</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 16:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-9</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would counter that the Mac is proof that Apple doesn't object to people  learning C, or any other programming language. And an iPad Pro costs about the same as a Macbook, though even the cheapest Macbook is a superior platform for actual code development.</p>

<p>It's also worth noting that knowing how to program C, and knowing how to create an iPad app which can be published on the App Store, are two very different things. To make an iPad app, you need to understand some tricky (complex) frameworks, and you'd be using Swift and Objective-C.</p>

<p>You can also learn C using an iPad, via online C interpreters. But, correct, Apple doesn't want to make it too easy to get native code running on the iPad, and while they may have multiple reasons, security is one of them.</p>

<p>Yes, Apple isn't up to Stallman's standards for free and open - but nothing else is, either.</p>

<p>PS - I am something of an Apple fanboy (despite my age). However, I don't blindly agree with all of their actions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/8</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 17:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-8</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Tele, they market this thing as "Desktop Class" this and "Desktop Class" that, it also now has a larger screen available and even keyboard and mouse support!</p>

<p>I've got an app called hyperPad, it's perfectly usable although I have no idea how a person would actually go about publishing something to the app store with it (I just play with it out of curiosity).  In addition, there is an app called Pythonista, a complete Python Coding environment that is apparently so damn good that people keep raving it's the best Python development environment they have used on any platform!</p>

<p>So I'm not feeling that same air of it being an unsuitable environment.</p>

<p>There is no reason why C compiling, an Arduino IDE, or whatever else cannot just be sandboxed like anything else.  The only reason Apple fanboys are fainting with over-excitement lately is because they were finally given the ability to copy a .WAV file to their iPad from a USB stick.  The only reason they can do this now and not before, is because their lord and master, Apple, have finally decided to let them do so, and I'm sure we can expect to see a whole new wave of Jobs look-alikes with jeans up to their elbows and rounded glasses as a result of it.</p>

<p>The reason you cannot compile C on an iPad is simply because they don't want people learning C, they want people learning Apple's programming languages.  They cannot exercise such a limitation over Python, because they no longer have the "compilation of code" excuse to fall back on with Python (which must surely be burning them up inside out of sheer frustration).</p>

<p>So take this as a friendly warning to parents if any are reading this; if your child is a creative type, a "maker", then you absolutely need to keep completely away from Apple and their products.</p>

<p>The iPad is exactly what Richard Stallman said it is; it is a prison, hence the term "Jailbreak" being used to represent the act of escaping from it.  I understand why, despite everything, people love their iPads, but nevertheless, mine will be going on ebay as soon soon as my situation allows it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-7</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/axoman">@axoman</a>: while Apple is certainly responsible for some creepy behavior, the fact that iOS development isn’t done on an iPad isn’t as sinister as you make out. The development system evolved on top of the existing Xcode system which was already in place for Mac. And a real computer, with big CPU, storage and screen are very useful.</p>

<p>In addition, it would be a drag trying to develop apps on an iPad, and far from the best way to learn ‘C’.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/6</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 17:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-6</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Chambers79]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/chambers79">@Chambers79</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks, good suggestion, but it was to be a gift so i can’t put them to added expence. Thanks though!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 14:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-5</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Not sure if this will help any, but without being able to go the tablet route, I reckon the best bet for your friend might be to go on ebay, search for "Linux Laptop", then use the sort by lowest price function from the drop-down menu.  You'd be surprised how cheaply you can pick-up something small like an old laptop that has Linux installed and therefore would likely run the patcher.</p>

<p>Some of those computers are actually smaller then a tablet when folded.</p>

<p>Anyway, best of luck finding something suitable.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 13:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-4</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Chambers79]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/chambers79">@Chambers79</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>thanks. I thought it might be the case! </p>

<p>I feel your pain- all the best</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 12:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-3</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Unfortunately not, there is no editor for Android or iOS.  I'm in the most unfortunate position myself right now of having to rely on an iPad to do all of my computing, and I can say with all honesty that Apple should be hit with a lawsuit over the clearly manipulative restrictions they have imposed.</p>

<p>I have a lot of time on my hands lately, was even going to take the advice of some members on this forum and learn C programming, but you cannot compile code on an iOS device.</p>

<p>Despite the "Tool of Creatives" dribble Apple misleadingly put out there, it is actually the most restrictive, anti-maker-frendly platform out there, so I'm guessing that even if someone was prepared to port the patcher over to iOS, it would not be allowed to run anyway.  The sooner Apple fall, the better, you can't even compile to work with an Arduino on this crap-heap platform.</p>

<p>Android is potentially a better bet, and the Axoloti patcher would run if ported and run on a reasonably powerful bit of hardware, but sadly there is no patcher for Android.</p>

<p>Sorry to be the bearer of bad news, I really wish the situation were different, but sadly not <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/disappointed.png?v=5" title=":disappointed:" class="emoji" alt=":disappointed:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 11:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-2</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Ipads and tablets</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Chambers79]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/chambers79">@Chambers79</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello, i use Axoloti with PC but wondered- can I patch on eg Ipad or Android tablet and upload to the board? </p>

<p>I ask as I want to give a board to a friend who does not have a computer. Just a tablet. </p>

<p>Thanks</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-6154-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/ipads-and-tablets/6154.rss">Ipads and tablets</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
