<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
    <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976</link>
    <description>Hi guys,


Want to own a real Yamaha CS80, that classic everybody drools on about?

Well don&#39;t! I own one and I constantly live in mortal fear of it breaking down.

I have however learned an awful lot from the beast and it is still my personal benchmark for what a good analog polyphonic synthesizer should be capable of.

So is it any wonder my main Axoloti project (see Holy Grail) contains quite a few CS 80 genes? And since I started the project with working out how to build an analog version first the similarities became even bigger (see Poly Power User Tips). So much so that creating a functional CS80 copy (sort of) became an almost unavoidable next (side)step.

Here are the screenshots:

&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/default/original/2X/a/ad4592033f03b83f94e2fbabb999a63ab0cecbdf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;431&quot;&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/default/original/2X/8/8f4f832b1b3c5181002d2c7bd8eb2dc44936d436.jpg&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;431&quot;&gt;

And here&#39;s the file:

&lt;a class=&quot;attachment&quot; href=&quot;/uploads/default/original/2X/8/83dc978a80679ad3bba304a7a7d17f41718090aa.axp&quot;&gt;CS80ish.axp&lt;/a&gt; (18.9 KB)

I hope you like it.

Some remarks:

Since the Axoloti has not enough internal processor power it can alas not be a totally integral polyphonic CS80 (see points below) but it is close enough for most purposes. 

The biggest differences when compared to the original are:

- 10 paraphonic oscillators (so 2 more voices to play with then on the original. Hurray!)
- Because of the paraphonic approach there are however some triggering issues. Axoloti&#39;s option to provide non-retriggering when playing legato (binding notes) however goes far in compensating this.
- Only 2 filters in series per channel so no full filter treatment per voice (It&#39;s paraphonic you know!).
- Only 1 oscillator mix per channel (on the CS80 each channel has it&#39;s own independent oscillator mix. In stead you get detuning per oscillator / waveform (so you do at least not need a second set for that) and full level-mixing in stead of only switching waveforms on and off.
- For true CS80 fans: This instrument also provides poly aftertouch on oscillator volume. Since playing the aftertouch will also monophonically open the filters at the same time the difference to real poly aftertouch is remarkably small (thanks to @SmashedTransistors for his help with implementing this!).
- To avoid the oscillator subpatch surface becoming too cluttered I have left some controls hidden within the subpatch itself. These are:
      + Oscillator detuning
      + Initial pitch (swoop) attack time
      + Pitch bend range
- I have consciously decided against sending everything through a stereo chorus as on the original because one then still has the option to treat the “channels” individually after they leave the Axoloti (One of the few things the CS70M really did better then the CS80) but even without extra effects it can be used for some interesting true stereo spreading.
 
The sound that is set up on the downlaod is rather typical for a CS80. There is the “Emersonesque” attack swoop per note but also listen to the more subtle speed changing modulations created by the ring mod when a note is held longer, proving that a ring mod can be used for much more then screaming wails.

By the way: the ring mod envelope is full ADSR in stead of an AR only as on the real thing. In other words: Some you loose. Some you win.

Have fun and feel free to mess around with it as much as you like. Since it &#39;s a quite reasonable polyphonic compromise anyway it should also be a good starting point for other projects. So knock yourself out if you want to use it to build your own Axoloti Prophet 5 on in stead.

Finally: Since the Axoloti&#39;s output signals are not that strong because of technical limitations I have added 2 output gain modules. In the download they are set to factor 1.0. Treat these with care if you do not want to end up with bleeding ears!
  
Marc

(Remark: To keep this post up to date but at the same time avoid unnecesarry confusion for people who see this for the first time I have updated it, including the download, on 08 December 2017 and 13 December 2017)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 22:30:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Patching</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ott]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/ott">@Ott</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>And a proper modern PolyAT keyboard/ribbon to go with!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/40</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 22:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-40</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I wonder how Brasse is coming along with his physical build?</p>

<p>Was just reading about this project and immediately thought of Brasso!<br><a href="https://www.deckardsdream.com/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.deckardsdream.com/</a></p>

<p>Looks like a nice project, but damn, it suffers from the same problem as the vintage one (too bloody expensive).  They only want $1,199.00 for the kit, or if you're feeling flush and a bit lazy, you can have them build it for you, but that would bring it to $2,550.00.</p>

<p>Would definitely love one in my rack though, no doubt about it, so now I'm pinning my hopes on Behringer coming-up with a CS80 clone for about £400 <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/yum.png?v=5" title=":yum:" class="emoji" alt=":yum:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/39</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-39</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Exactly! Through this we also come to the very central point my intentions:</p>

<p>It is one thing to keep quoting or even deforming the past just for the sake of it. It is another to actually learn from it.</p>

<p>By knowing all these sources I prove that I have studied the subject in detail. That is however not the same as getting access to all that information and then still insisting that my CS80ish EXPERIMENT is worth nothing because it does not slavishly reproduce every detail of the original or even complaining that no active code writing to imitate the original circuits has been taking place. </p>

<p>As so many other fine old inventions the CS80 was in the end just another station on the route to even more interesting instruments. It is however not some Golden Calf that people should dance around while scalding anybody who does not share their blind belief.</p>

<p>That is namely the exact opposite of what I am trying to do here. One can thus look at my output and remarks as downgrading and say I treat people like troglodyte's (no need to put the blame on those poor bastards for my faults anyway <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grinning.png?v=5" title=":grinning:" class="emoji" alt=":grinning:"> ) but by taking my explanations as such people are actually defeating themselves.</p>

<p>So take it in as far as you want to go but do not deform facts into gleaming alternative realities that never existed! At the same time the CS80 was/is one of the best instruments ever built on the other side it was/is an over expensive, by now over-hyped, piece of instable shit. Both description are actually correct at the same time, in the same reality.</p>

<p>That reality is already interesting enough without people adding all sorts of incongruous noise. That is the only thing I wanted to say here: Beware of the noise and be critical of it. If only to avoid to be put into the Lounge for such crimes.  </p>

<p>In the same vein: Please stop putting salt on every word I use and actually start reading.<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/upside_down_face.png?v=5" title=":upside_down_face:" class="emoji" alt=":upside_down_face:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/38</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-38</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>at 20:30, the knee controller.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/37</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 21:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-37</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Funny Brasso should mention ABBA, I saw a fairly recent video the other week featuring ABBA's GX-1.<br>I do love ABBA, but sometimes I hate them cause they own a Yamaha GX-1, while Axoman does not.</p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="kM8726SKSvo" data-youtube-title="Benny's Riksmixningsverket Studio" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>

<p>Brasso, time to start work on a GX-1 clone (but actually finish the bloody thing this time) <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/36</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 20:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-36</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It is not sterile nostalgia memorabilia, <br>it is exploring the synthesis legacy to understand what specifics of the CS80 are important in some landmark sounds.<br>This way anybody interested can pick what specifics (s)he likes and implement it in the Axoloti.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/35</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 18:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-35</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Part of the problem when dicussing the "great olds" is that one has to wade through such popular lore. Conjecture and philosphizing become accepted "fact" before you know it. It could in this case be that the Moog filter was used but the GX1 does not actually need such stuff to sound this stringy.</p>

<p>Other good sources to check it out are:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The In Through The Outdoor album by Led Zeppelin. Not that it is a totally awesome keyboard oriented album but hardly anyhthing else was used keybaordwise so there is little doubt about what is GX1 or not. It was Abba's GX1 by the way!<br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afEipftwkn4&amp;list=PL5G_3XAxDvS04vwCFc9JcvO0wLceWF2ud" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afEipftwkn4&amp;list=PL5G_3XAxDvS04vwCFc9JcvO0wLceWF2ud</a><br>Here is a studio session version of All Of My Love: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-NoMn5tRlAg" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-NoMn5tRlAg</a></p></li>
<li><p>Rick van der Linden albums like GX1 and the colaborative Wild Connections album with one Lyricon playing Mr. Jack Lancaster. Again both are not awe inspiring but rather clear GX1 showcases.<br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dsoVhMvg6r4" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dsoVhMvg6r4</a><br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O8DW3kmPCBo" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O8DW3kmPCBo</a></p></li>
<li><p>Lastly there are a lot of Japanese Yamaha Electone competition recordings. Many of them might make your hair stand up because of thier cheesyness but a few are actually quite good, like Shooting Stars. And they are all played in one go on a "bog standard" GX1. Now if only my coördination was comparable<br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9HjQpdDgcsM" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9HjQpdDgcsM</a></p></li>
</ul>

<p>One additional remark though: In spite of being suggested earlier the GX1 is velocity sensitive (on the upper manual) but does NOT have polyphonic aftertouch (although the mono synth of course has monophonic aftertouch and even side to side touch).</p>

<p>And a word of warning: If you guys keep dragging this into the nonstalgia direction too much our pointy eyed web host Technobear might dump this in the lounge section (again). <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sweat.png?v=5" title=":sweat:" class="emoji" alt=":sweat:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-34</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="26" data-topic="3976"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/smashedtransistors/40/3147_1.png" class="avatar">SmashedTransistors:</div>
<blockquote><p>About that Village Ghetto Land example however no such doubt exist.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I must add that many people suggest that this string sound is a combination of the GX-1 and of the Moog CE String Filter. The Moog CE String Filter is a static bank of 30 or 40 high resonance filters. (CE stands for Custom Engineering, a particular division of Moog that produced very rare modules).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-33</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/blaerg">@blaerg</a> <br>Yup, must be a troglodyte thing, I'm sure ol'brasso thinks I'm a troglodyte anyway <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/brasso">@brasso</a><br>Well, in all honesty it did feel a bit tongue-in-cheek daring to make my post, but as I said, it was not meant as negative in any way.  It's actually a relief to hear your reply, cause at least I feel comfortable about wanting a CS80 again.  I should point out though, that my reasons for thinking what I thought are actually your own doing.  First I saw the title of this thread and assumed you had recreated a CS80 on your Axo.  A reply from you then pointed out you hadn't gone to the length of modelling the filter etc.  At that point I still thought, well, cool stuff anyway, at least I get to play around with the CS80 in a control sense.</p>

<p>I had no idea you had not done that either, therefore I assumed I was playing with a CS80.  I could have looked into it to re-familiarise myself, but as it was you who created it I didn't feel the need to do that, assuming it would be all 'present and correct' so to speak.</p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a><br>Nice to know how the sound was achieved.  I pretty much assumed that already apart from the aftertouch, I just assumed it was done with an LFO.  Again though, the only reason I mentioned that sound is because Marc (I think it was Marc) once posted about getting that sound.  After seeing that, and him announcing a CS80, it just seemed logical that he'd use that sound as the default sound to demonstrate his CS80.</p>

<p>I got that wrong too, I guess it's one of the hazards of me being a troglodyte <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/31</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 20:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-31</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote><p>should do some reading on the CS80 - do you mean that it is essentially like 2 separate Poly's with a discreet path (osc&gt;filter&gt;vca etc) for both channels? And you have condensed these back down a bit to save power? Makes sense. Very interesting. &lt;</p></blockquote>

<p>Exactly!</p>

<blockquote><p>Next step is to borrow a controller that transmits poly aftertouch to get properly expressive. &gt;</p></blockquote>

<p>You won't regret it!</p>

<blockquote><p>I definitely struggle with understanding the complexities of the Axoloti overall - while I understand most of the normal objects, anything too complex or code-y just goes over my head. &gt;</p></blockquote>

<p>Welcome to the club. I consider myself to be rather synth savy but working through the Axoloti's particulars is already quite a task in itself. The info one needs is all over the place! If only somebody would write a better user guide.</p>

<p>Besides that aspect though: Getting the best out of a system is often a matter of working your way around its shortcomings in a creative way. As it stands the Axoloti can actually not deliver a full CS80. But it can get awfully close!</p>

<p>I just made the updates to post 1. No more inconsistent labeling (I hope!) <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/30</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-30</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mlbstrd]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mlbstrd">@mlbstrd</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>hahaha yep you nailed me with most of it <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/joy.png?v=5" title=":joy:" class="emoji" alt=":joy:"></p>

<p>I should do some reading on the CS80 - do you mean that it is essentially like 2 separate Poly's with a discreet path (osc&gt;filter&gt;vca etc) for both channels? And you have condensed these back down a bit to save power? Makes sense. Very interesting.</p>

<p>I WAS cranking the fifth pot of the ADSR, expecting it to be like the "contour" of a usual filter/env routing. Good advice on the filters too - I've dug through most of the filters trying to find one that I really bond with. That said I usually use a Sherman so I'm a little spoilt for filters...!</p>

<p>Great tip on reducing polyphony (or paraphony, I suppose) to squeeze in a filter. I reckon I could get away with 6 voices and still be happy with it. Next step is to borrow a controller that transmits poly aftertouch to get properly expressive.</p>

<p>I definitely struggle with understanding the complexities of the Axoloti overall - while I understand most of the normal objects, anything too complex or code-y just goes over my head. I think this will either happen in time or it won't - I'm pretty adverse to things that delve me too far into the technical sphere and away from the creative (one of the reasons I closed my engineering business), so I try and stay in the creative zone as much as I can. That said, I'm getting lots of mileage out of the pre-made objects, which is a bonus as I only really bought the Ax as a USB host device for my OP1.</p>

<p>Thanks for the help!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/29</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-29</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Now that is more like it: Specific questions! <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>

<p>Most stuff you ask does however still fall into 3 catagories:</p>

<ul>
<li>Understanding the functionality of synthesis component in general</li>
<li>Understaning the Axoloti</li>
<li>Understanding the CS80 itself.</li>
</ul>

<p>I have basically given you all the info you need in the previous posts so my best advice would be to revisit post 1 and 18 and (re)do the homework.</p>

<p>As far as your specific questions go though:</p>

<p>Firstly: Just to make sure we talk about exactly the same version. Did you upload the latest version (see the ammendment remark at the end of post 1)</p>

<blockquote><p>The only thing that seems a little strange is the two banks of filters seem to act for the left or right channel independently, whereas they are labelled as if it's two types of filters? this confused me.&lt;</p></blockquote>

<p>The CS80 has 2 fully independent channels with a their own oscillator mix. To save processing power ( again: re-read the earlier stuff) I decided on a paraphonic approach AND on feeding one (more flexible!) oscillator mix into both channels.</p>

<p>You are however right about the labeling. That is a bit of residue from my main The Holy Grail project (which see). I'll correct it and place a new version under the downlod link in post 1. Thanks for the remark.</p>

<blockquote><p>Also mucking around with the filter env's really didn't seem to actually do anything to the filters. Maybe I need to experiment a little more...&lt;</p></blockquote>

<p>Now let me gues: You cranked the 5th pot in the envelopes fully open. Understand that this is no real CS-type 5 stage envelope. It is a regular ADSR with the 5th pot acting as a reversed depth control. If youy leave pot 5 on zero the ADSR will work full tilt. If you put it on 10 the ADSR will however have NO effect at all. So first put pot 5 on zero and then try again.</p>

<p>Furhtermore the Axoloti filters seem to have quite narrow "'sweet spots". If this was still a real analog one could say they could have chosen thier pots with more care. So do not jank them from one side to the other too much but take your time trying out the inbetween settings.     </p>

<blockquote><p>The ring mod (with the env) sounds awesome, but really mucks with the left/right balance when engaged. &lt;</p></blockquote>

<p>I actually love that kind of stuff and there are enough level and alternative routing controls to get to a good balance. But you can of course also mix all signals into one single end-mixer.</p>

<blockquote><p>Any thoughts on how to get the CPU down a little so that a verb or chorus can be added to the end of it? Anything I put in there pushed it to 100%! &lt;</p></blockquote>

<p>Basic Axoloti 1: Put the instrument on a low polyphony count first, maybe even 1 voice only. Then make the the changes you want to make. Only try how far you can go up with the polyphony count again after you've got the path working. I expect the instrument to still be able to be 8-voice paraphonic after adding an effect. Do however understand that the longer the delay time the effect can provide is (and thus the amount of memory it needs) is the more processor-hungry the module will be. So a chorus needs only a bit of processing power but a reverb will set you back a lot further. </p>

<p>Basic Axoloti 2: Do ALWAYS press the UPDATE button on the subpatch module in the main screen after you change something in the subpatch. Otherwise nothing will actually change!</p>

<p>Gulp! Just sending you another version would  have been a lot quiker then explaining all this but this way you will actually learn stuff. So put your hands together for our (equally free) Axoloti / CS80 course. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sweat.png?v=5" title=":sweat:" class="emoji" alt=":sweat:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/28</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-28</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mlbstrd]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/mlbstrd">@mlbstrd</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/brasso">@brasso</a> I like the patch - I think at it's core it sounds good. The only thing that seems a little strange is the two banks of filters seem to act for the left or right channel independently, whereas they are labelled as if it's two types of filters? this confused me. Also mucking around with the filter env's really didn't seem to actually do anything to the filters. Maybe I need to experiment a little more...</p>

<p>The ring mod (with the env) sounds awesome, but really mucks with the left/right balance when engaged.</p>

<p>Any thoughts on how to get the CPU down a little so that a verb or chorus can be added to the end of it? Anything I put in there pushed it to 100%!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 01:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-27</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You re right, the GX1 has a pedal board, but i don't think it is pressure sensitive !<br></p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="25" data-topic="3976"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/b/3da27b/40.png" class="avatar">brasso:</div>
<blockquote><p>About that Village Ghetto Land example however no such doubt exist.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Much less effects and an almost raw sound, but few people know this one.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 22:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-26</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If you assume that the rumbling background bass was played on the same instrument in one go you are of course right. Not sure myself though. About that Village Ghetto Land example however no such doubt exist.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 22:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-25</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I simply wanted to show something else that the BladeRunner sound.<br></p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="23" data-topic="3976"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/b/3da27b/40.png" class="avatar">brasso:</div>
<blockquote><p>particular line is monophonic</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>It is played polyphonically, there is the line and other stuff played together.</p>

<p>There is also the darker "Village Ghetto Land", for nice polyphonic strings :</p>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="B5xCZyIRCVM" data-youtube-title="Stevie Wonder - Village Ghetto Land" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 22:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-24</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Er, since that, often imitated, particular line is monophonic you do not need polyphonic aftertouch for it. Not even monophonic aftertouch if you have a hand to spare. One can actually add almost all needed expression by simply tweaking the filter control live!</p>

<p>More in general your remark is however spot on. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 22:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-23</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Put aside the other specifics of the CS80, two import features of the "Blade Runner" sounds are the <strong>polyphonic aftertouch</strong> as delicately played by Vangelis and the Lexicon 224 reverb (long and slow modulated chorusing reverb). The interaction between the finger shaped tones and the infinite reverberation is one of the key for this lush sound.</p>

<hr>

<p>The CS80 and the GX1 (Stevie Wonder's Dream Machine) are capable of doing many other sounds (strings à la "Pastime Paradise for example) thanks to the specifics <a class="mention" href="/u/brasso">@brasso</a> pointed out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 22:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-22</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="19" data-topic="3976"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/blaerg/40/4481_1.png" class="avatar">blaerg:</div>
<blockquote><p>I think the problem may be that the layout/knob/toggle access is what makes a huge difference?</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>YES!</p>

<p>but to make the thing work as it does taking a few liberties with the layout was unavoidable.</p>

<p>A real obvious example is that the "VCA's" are in front of the filters. But I've explained that decission thoroughly enough elsewhere.</p>

<p>One other example though: The placement of a modules in a subpatch determines the position of a parented controller in the list on the suppatch object's surface (Excuse me?) so I actually had to reshuffle things a bit in that subpatch screen to get the oscillator control listing that is now visible in the main screen.</p>

<p>User tip: Just follow the patchcords! Are you for instance aware that you can switch of specific types of patchcords in the upper right corner of the screen. So why not only leave the audiopaths visible? <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 21:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-21</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>As far as I am concerned there is no right or wrong here. This has been discussed before and wil be discussed many times more again: It's not a matter of being troglodytes or not. Sorry of that is the impression one might get from my explanations.</p>

<p>Everybody has to do music his own way. Getting into the deeper side of Axoloti however means that one starts to conceptualize what a synth does and getting the best out of these insights. Some people here go a lot deeper then I do (for instance into coding and the arithmatic behind sound). They in their turn humble me.</p>

<p>I do however dare to say that if you are not prepared to go rather deep there is not that much sense in "going Axoloti". You might find loosing interest quite quickly after the novelty aspect wears away. Better buy yourself the next VST, a hardware synth or even a "real" modular then and start turning knobs and stuff at random. Many a fine sound has been created that way.</p>

<p>What I have merely been trying (again: as a sidepath) is to set up something that can make convincing CS80 sounds. Using the name of one of the synths with the most overblown reputations (even if rightly so) might however have been a mistake. I probably should have called this post "Free Quite A Bit Yamaha CS-family Sounding Axoloti Patch If You Are Not Too Particular About It" but people nowadays simply need hyperboles to become interested at all.</p>

<p>As far as a comparison to VST's is concerned. You can take it from me that my thingy sounds much more like the real deal then any VST I've heard. I wil however not make a whole set of presets to prove it. That would actually be defeating the whole point. Troglodyte or not, in one respect Axoman is right. If you do not get this on your own strengths you'll probably also not get the original.</p>

<p>What about something like this however?: "Hey, you forgot the modulation generator but I just added one myself by linking a thingemajig module with a whatzitcalled invertor. Here's my download in return!" or "Man, I just found a way to add polyphonic portamento (Oops, just gave away another "glaring" ommision!)".</p>

<p>Now that sort of stuff would really warm my heart. As far as the "It's not the real thang, dude!" part of the discussion is concerned I would however like to quote the big bad computer in Tron:</p>

<p>END OF LINE</p>

<p><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sweat.png?v=5" title=":sweat:" class="emoji" alt=":sweat:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 21:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-20</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@blaerg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blaerg">@blaerg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="16" data-topic="3976"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/a/848f3c/40.png" class="avatar">axoman:</div>
<blockquote><p>So your CS80 didn't inspire me</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I thought it would be more interesting, inherently, as well. But then again, we lowly troglodytes <em>just don't get it</em>.</p>

<p>There was a VST emulation I had at one point that seemed to produce a huge variety of different sounds, I think the problem may be that the layout/knob/toggle access is what makes a huge difference?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 20:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-19</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brasso Marc Brassé]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/brasso">@brasso</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sorry, Axoman but you really do not get it.</p>

<p>This is no perfect replica of a CS80. I did not call it CS80ish for nothing. It is a model that can help you to create typical CS80 sounds on an Axoloti. I could go on trying to get even closer to the real thing and clutter up the user interface and deminish the voice count in th emean time but like I said in my introduciton: This is more of a sidepath then the main stream.</p>

<p>Some specific remarks though:<br>- The CS80 has a dedicated LFO. A very flexible one actually. So intall one if you want one.<br>-  More imporant though: Typical for the CS80 is that it actully already has a dedicated LFO for about every worthwhile function. So there is a LFO for PWM, and there is one for the Ring modulator in this model so yu can already modulate the hell out of this thing without an extra routable LFO. Crank open the PWM LFO and the thning even moves into FM, something the real thing never could! Understand the Ring MOD's LFO/Env. generator combi and you wil already modulate to Nirvanna without ever feelling the need for anyhting else.<br>- The layout of a CS80 is very logical but in this Axoloti "recreation" other things where more important. If you do get the whole Paraphonic approach I talked about you might actually understand why the "VCA's" are actually in front of the Filter.<br>- One of the most important features on the CS80 are its velocity and polyphonic aftertouch facilities. As long as you cannot try out the real thing the best way to get a inkling of the CS80's potential is to first get an understaning of what polyphonic aftertouch can do for you in general.<br>- More importantly: Even when owning the real thing one could still circle around it for years without getting to grips with it's real potential. Playing around with synths is more then pressign one single key and tweaking the filter control and LFO speed to death, in th emena time constantly ignoring the ADSR's in the process (I'm basically describing about 80% of all Youtube "demo's" with that, Grrr!). </p>

<p>I could go on for quite a while only talking about such stuff but I think the CS80's reputation is deformed anyway. When you talk about certain "classic" instruments people immediately start building their own personal myths around them. The fact that you ask for THAT BLADE RUNNER SOUND is already a very bad sign. people running after THAT sound has already created an Internet vortex in itself.</p>

<p>You know what. THAT sound is basically a very simple sawtooth construction. The special thing is how expressive something like that can get when you play it well on a CS80. Scoop: If you know what you are doing you actually do not need a CS80 for it!</p>

<p>Again: I could go on like this for hours;</p>

<p>Here's some dedicated information though.<br>- Understanding my paraphonic approach: <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/polyphony-power-user-tips/3957">https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/polyphony-power-user-tips/3957</a><br>- To get a better impression of the real things layout: <a href="https://www.manualslib.com/manual/778093/Yamaha-Cs-80.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.manualslib.com/manual/778093/Yamaha-Cs-80.html</a><br>- Taking a deeper look at what makes the CS80 tick: <a href="http://www.brassee.com/writing.html#cs80" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.brassee.com/writing.html#cs80</a> <br>- If you still insist on THAT sound: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fne0oIEv-WI" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fne0oIEv-WI</a></p>

<p>Please work through that first and then come back again, providing you are stil interested. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 11:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-18</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Androoclops]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/androoclops">@Androoclops</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sweeet, gunna try this out tonight!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 01:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-17</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Now then, Mr Brasse ... opinion time!</p>

<p>Had a play with your CS80, and honestly I wanted to praise it, but I can't.  I hope that doesn't sound negative, cause actually, it's quite the opposite.  I've drooled over the CS80 many a time, and had it not been for the price of the thing, I would already have one.  But your CS80 has made me aware that I wouldn't enjoy that synth even if I had one.  Certainly not as much as I thought I would.  It's one thing reading about it, but it's another when the functions are there in front of you, it makes you realise certain things.</p>

<p>I had not noticed the lack of LFO, nor had I realised how cumbersome it feels to go from oscillator to output.  CS80 sounds awesome, but if I had a CS80, honestly, I think I would get tired of it's structure or 'architecture' pretty quick.</p>

<p>As for your specific version, I'm surprised you didn't set it to the classic Vangelis Bladerunner sound by default, so that was a bit of a bummer, but all that aside, my opinion after experiencing it is that it's an interesting architecture but not for me, it's not a synth I would get along with if I had one.</p>

<p>So your CS80 didn't inspire me, but it definitely did help me out in other ways, only thing is, I'm not sure whether I like the idea of no longer wanting a CS80, lol, it feels <em>very</em> wrong somehow <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/open_mouth.png?v=5" title=":open_mouth:" class="emoji" alt=":open_mouth:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/16</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 18:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-16</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Free Yamaha CS80</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="12" data-topic="3976"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/b/3da27b/40.png" class="avatar">brasso:</div>
<blockquote><p>Next: A Brassé built Axoloti enclosure that is as big as a desk. In other words: I know exactly where mine is! <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p></blockquote></aside>

<p>So do I, cause I just found my Axo but I need to rig-up my keys again first so I'll leave it until tomorrow now, but looking forward to it.  I assume from the <em>"big as a desk"</em> comment that you plan to make a full-size MIDI controlled version with Axoloti inside?</p>

<p>Well I hope you're a good carpenter, Brasse, cause such a thing would look amazing if it were craftsman-built from wood <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 20:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3976-15</guid>
        <source url="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/free-yamaha-cs80/3976.rss">Free Yamaha CS80</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
