<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489</link>
    <description>Hey Axo-Peeps!

I&#39;m suffering a nightmare right now, and when I say nightmare, I really _do_ mean nightmare!

If anyone reading this uses Windows XP or a Raspberry Pi3, then please read this as you might be able to help me.  I&#39;m currently preparing for a change of habitat.  I&#39;m going to be living mobile, and therefore, off grid.  The problem is there&#39;s not much space for solar panels, and that&#39;s proving to be a real problem for me due to my computing requirements.

I have two desktop PC boxes.  Unfortunately, the Windows 7 box is far too power-hungry for me to even consider taking it, but thankfully my Windows XP box is within acceptable power usage.  So I decided on taking the XP box with me, that was until I downloaded the Axoloti Patcher and found that it doesn&#39;t run on my XP box.

So I decided to use a Raspberry Pi3.  It&#39;s ideal as far as energy consumption goes, and it uses a linux-based OS as default, so this will be perfect for running the Axo Patcher I thought.  But no, again I&#39;m hit with disappointment cause it won&#39;t work!  I&#39;m running the latest Ubuntu MATE, and it&#39;s been fine with everything I&#39;ve thrown at it so far, using it as a main PC.  in fact, I&#39;m even using it right now to browse the forum and post this message!

Everything I need runs on it, but again, everything except for the Axoloti Patcher :disappointed:

Out of the two, I would _much_ rather use my 32-bit XP box for Axoloti because I already have a bunch of other software I use on that system.  So if anyone knows how to get it running on XP, via some hack or whatever, then please post a step-by-step for me so that I can give it a try.

If I can&#39;t get the patcher running on my XP box (or the RPi3 as a last resort) it looks like I&#39;ll have to sell my Axo, cause without the patcher, I can&#39;t use it.  If anyone knows anything, please help as soon as possible as I&#39;ve literally spent the last two months of my life trying to get a suitable system prepared.  I cannot afford to be buying any more computers, so it needs to work on one of those machines, or that&#39;s it, I can&#39;t use Axoloti.

Any help appreciated!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 16:10:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Lounge</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yup, all drives are working perfectly in the machines they belong in, and there's nothing wrong with the IDE connectors on the board otherwise the drives that belong it wouldn't work.</p>

<p>I'm convinced this is a BIOS setting issue, and have looked at the documentation and even other forums, but still have no idea what I've got set wrong.  Anyway, weekend has arrived again, the lid goes back on and it gets forgotten about if I can't fix it by the weeks end.  That would be it, end of XP box.  The amount of time and effort I've spent trying to get this thing working is completely insane.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/51</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 18:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-51</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@strum]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/strum">@strum</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Are you sure the drive itself works?</p>

<p>Have you tested it on another machine with a known working IDE drive controller?</p>

<p>That's what I would do.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/50</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 17:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-50</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can't see a PCI or PCIe card working cause it won't even detect drives indirectly connected to the IDE sockets, so I doubt it will look for drives attached through PCI or PCIe.  I suppose that's my last option but I'm sick of buying cards for this damn thing, so I was hoping it was just a BIOS setting I had wrong.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/49</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 12:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-49</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@strum]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/strum">@strum</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Couple of suggestions or thoughts.</p>

<p>There might be better places to ask for this sort of help, it's not really Axo related.</p>

<p>Have you tried updating the bios?</p>

<p>How old is the machine? it's USB controller might not work with a newer standard device.</p>

<p>Have you tried getting a PCI or PCIe card with a PATA adaptor?</p>

<p>Any help to you?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/48</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 12:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-48</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just a last attempt to get some info on this before I put the lid back on and forget about it - had enough.<br>Anyone any ideas why it won't recognise any of these adapters?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/47</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 09:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-47</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Does anyone here know anything about SATA, IDE, and their related BIOS settings?</p>

<p>I've been trying to get an internal SATA Blu-ray drive to work on the XP machine.  I don't expect to be able to play Blu-ray on the XP machine, I'm just trying to get the drive to work on it.</p>

<p>First I purchased one of these:<br><aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
    <a href="http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/New-3-5-PATA-IDE-to-SATA-Hard-HDD-Optical-Drive-Converter-Adapter-/221012878864" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">ebay.co.uk</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="http://i.ebayimg.com/images/i/221012878864-0-1/s-l1000.jpg" width="" height="" class="thumbnail">

<h3><a href="http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/New-3-5-PATA-IDE-to-SATA-Hard-HDD-Optical-Drive-Converter-Adapter-/221012878864" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">New 3.5 PATA IDE to SATA Hard HDD Optical Drive Converter Adapter  | eBay</a></h3>

<p>Hook up your old PATA drive to your new SATA computer or your new SATA drive to your old PATA computer with this easy to use adapter. You can connect hard drives, CD-ROMs, DVD-RW drives etc which have a SATA connector and convert them for use in...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>

<p>Did not work, so then I purchased one of these:<br><a href="http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/Bi-Directional-IDE-to-SATA-Converter-Hard-Drive-Adapter-Dynamode-/172555816701" rel="nofollow noopener">www.ebay.co.uk/itm/Bi-Directional-IDE-to-SATA-Converter-Hard-Drive-Adapter-Dynamode-/172555816701</a></p>

<p>And it <em>still</em> didn't work!</p>

<p>I thought the second one was guaranteed to work as it doesn't require drivers and is bi-directional, but no, still won't work.  The BIOS doesn't seem to detect the drive when using either of these products, so I'm wondering if it's some setting I have to change in the BIOS.</p>

<p>So, any help appreciated, and bear in mind the motherboard I'm connecting the drive to is in an old Windows XP box, so it uses an older type of BIOS (American Megatrends).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/46</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 10:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-46</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Well ... I've been trying to bring the XP box's Hard Disk back to life for the last four days, but it's had it.  It failed not long after I got chance to finally play with the Axoloti again, damn thing.  I've got an identical spare hard disk but at this point I'm completely tired of keeping the damn thing running and getting it to run stuff.</p>

<p>It's lucky I got that shield really, cause it looks like I'm gonna need it.</p>

<p>Currently looking into <em>under</em>-clocking my Windows 7 machine cause I read it can save energy, which makes perfect sense really.  Not sure how much difference it will make on my system but I intend to give that a go, and if it works, be done with the XP box.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/45</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 12:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-45</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Mine only come with one of those blue Parallel-based boxes and some software.  I've always hated the fact that it came with Parallel instead of USB, but I bought mine back when they were just starting to become popular on ebay and were almost twice the price they are now.</p>

<p>But at least with the Arduino/GRBL shield I'll finally have a USB-based CNC (I hope so anyway).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/44</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 22:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-44</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DragonSF Claus Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dragonsf">@DragonSF</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Actually, the device came free with my CNC machine.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/43</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 22:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-43</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the link, Dragon, I thought you were talking about some special cable or something, I didn't realise it was something that pricey.  Looks tidy and sounds neat, but well out of my range!</p>

<p>BTW, this is the one I purchased, you get an Arduino with GRBL firmware preloaded, a CNC shield, and even the full set of stepper motor drivers with heat-sincs - All for £15.</p>

<p>I've not actually tried it yet, so I'm hesitant to say anything about it for now, other than it's looking good cause I believe both the hardware and the software are open source.  I don't know if it does that feedback thing, but if you check the specs at the link, it sounds quite capable and they're always adding stuff to the firmware.</p>

<p>Anyway, if it turns out to be crap, I'll just blame Gav' even though I'd bought it before he mentioned it to me.  Sometimes it's just handy and fun to have someone to blame other than myself <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>

<p><a href="http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/CNC-Shield-V3-0-UNO-R3-4pcs-A4988-Driver-GRBL-Arduino-3D-Printer-TE623-UK/112453694250" rel="nofollow noopener">www.ebay.co.uk/itm/CNC-Shield-V3-0-UNO-R3-4pcs-A4988-Driver-GRBL-Arduino-3D-Printer-TE623-UK/112453694250</a></p>

<p>Seems pretty cool, although I doubt it does that fancy tones thing Johannes mentions, it's probably just beats, but as long as it works, that's cool.  I intend to CNC some prototype designs for completed products, and if I can create a nice repeatable, stable system that would work in a realistic time-frame, I might even be able to use it for small production runs.  It's CNC after all, it's designed to be accurate and repeatable - so we'll see.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/42</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 20:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-42</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@johannes johannes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/johannes">@johannes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ah, a "smart" USB-parallel controller made for CNC, not just a "dumb" usb-parallel adapter for printers. <br>Using the latter would limit CNC usable stepping speed to beats rather than tones. For a laptop, CardBus or ExpressCard parallel adapters may still work with similar performance as an old printer port on a PC motherboard. But not all, ExpressCard also has a USB mode, printerport cards that use this would have no different performance than dumb usb-parallel adapters.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/41</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 13:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-41</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DragonSF Claus Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dragonsf">@DragonSF</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="http://cnc-plus.de/en/CNC-Software/WinPC-NC-USB--CNC-controlling-software-Win-PCNC-with-4-axis-USB-controller-.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://cnc-plus.de/en/CNC-Software/WinPC-NC-USB--CNC-controlling-software-Win-PCNC-with-4-axis-USB-controller-.html</a><br>works like a charm.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/40</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 13:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-40</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/dragonsf">@DragonSF</a><br>Have you got a link to the USB converter you're using, I'm very curious to see what you're talking about!<br>I always thought feedback stuff needed special sensors etc.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/39</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 12:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-39</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DragonSF Claus Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dragonsf">@DragonSF</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My USB/parallel converter also has a feedback. So the CNC program always knows, where the mill is positioned.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/38</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-38</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think maybe it's cause you're Australian, being upside-down all the time!<br>Cheers mate, will check that out <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/37</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 09:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-37</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sorry mate, appears I had a "too much space between the ears" moment... <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_closed_eyes.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_closed_eyes:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_closed_eyes:"></p>

<p>The software is called "Zapmaker" - <a href="http://zapmaker.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://zapmaker.org/</a><br>You should check out the site, its got some interesting info etc..</p>

<p>the download is on github - <a href="https://github.com/zapmaker/GrblHoming/releases" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/zapmaker/GrblHoming/releases</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/36</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 11:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-36</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sure, I'm aware of the CNC setup requirements, setting-up the machine etc, I just meant it seems a bit too good to be true to be able to just connect it to an Arduino/GRBL and completely avoid all that Parallel Port configuration crap.</p>

<p>This is great!</p>

<p>It's been a long time since I looked into actually setting it up from scratch again (never needed to due to having a working Windows XP setup).  But anyway, I searched for that software you mentioned, but cannot find it.  All I keep getting are results for a CNC machine-build project called ShapeOko, but I can't find any actual <em>software</em> called "ShapeOko" or "GRBL ShapeOko".</p>

<p>Gotta link Gav?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/35</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 10:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-35</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes indeed it is that simple.<br>But you are aware that there are setup parameters when using GRBL ? like how many steps to travel x number of millimeters etc.. and lots of other options.. Sure you can work it out, pretty standard where CNC is concerned.<br>The software I use is called "Shapeoko" if you google "GRBL Shapeoko" you will find it. I believe it is one of the more popular for GRBL. You then just load the gcode file, adjust to your start position and off you go.<br>I run mine on a really old pc that someone threw away, with a minimal version of XP, its all it does and runs fine.<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grinning.png?v=5" title=":grinning:" class="emoji" alt=":grinning:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 22:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-34</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/gavin">@Gavin</a><br>I've been looking into the GRBL thing, haven't set it up yet, but I found a program called G-Code Sender that was written in Java.  So just to be clear, you're saying that I could use that on Windows, via USB connected to the Arduino/GRBL, and that will directly control the CNC?</p>

<p>Really, it's that simple?</p>

<p>It seems a bit too good to be true, considering all the messing around that normally has to be done.  Reason I ask is because I've found an even lower power-consumption solution.  I could buy one of those Windows 8.1 Fanless Mini PCs that run on 12V.  Never thought of that before!  And if I'm understanding you correctly then I'd be able to use that to run both the Axo and the CNC.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-33</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks both, I didn't realise it was as simple as that actually, so that's good cause I just might have to fall back on it after todays discovery.  I just discovered my Axoloti has a mind of her own (see the XP thread), but with a bit of luck I'm about to remind her who's boss!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 08:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-32</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That's all GRBL is, a USB to Parallel converter, lots of free software options has been created to send the gcode to arduino, if you already have the shield, its just the parallel cable to your motor controller.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 04:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-31</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DragonSF Claus Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/dragonsf">@DragonSF</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I'm using an USB-&gt;Parallel converter in Windows 7/64 Bit on my CNC machine. Works like a charm.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/30</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 23:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-30</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="28" data-topic="3489"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>That's not torture !<br>Real torture would be letting you play them on one of those horrible home made manual cardboard record players you brag about so much... <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/weary.png?v=5" title=":weary:" class="emoji" alt=":weary:"><br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/rofl.png?v=5" title=":rofl:" class="emoji" alt=":rofl:"></p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Gav, dude, what you saw there was a very beautiful thing.  You saw a demonstration of man, machine, and audio reproduction in perfect harmony!</p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="28" data-topic="3489"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>Nice to hear everything worked out, forum support is priceless, Nightmare is over...<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" class="emoji" alt=":tada:"></p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Very true, this is a great community, and yes indeed, the nightmare is over <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" class="emoji" alt=":tada:"></p>

<p>Actually, there's even more good news as far as this whole going off-grid thing goes.  I mentioned the other day about how little energy the XP box was using, but I discovered yesterday, it's even less than I stated.  Among all the cables here, I noticed I had other stuff plugged into the adapter on the end of the cable I had attached to the energy monitor.  I said before it was drawing 90 to 105W, but actually it's only drawing around 65 to 70W - plus the monitor of course which is around 30W, so I have a full-size tower and pro monitor drawing around only 100W in total.  It's still more than a laptop draws, but not by much.</p>

<p>Very pleased about that <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/yum.png?v=5" title=":yum:" class="emoji" alt=":yum:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/29</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-29</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That's not torture !<br>Real torture would be letting you play them on one of those horrible home made manual cardboard record players you brag about so much... <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/weary.png?v=5" title=":weary:" class="emoji" alt=":weary:"><br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/rofl.png?v=5" title=":rofl:" class="emoji" alt=":rofl:"></p>

<p>Nice to hear everything worked out, forum support is priceless, Nightmare is over...<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" class="emoji" alt=":tada:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/28</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 22:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-28</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What a Nightmare!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>As in the other thread, water under the bridge, Marc, it was hopefully just a misuderstanding!</p>

<p>I do stress the word "Hopefully" though, cause if I find out you really was up to no good, I have plenty of room in my secret torture chamber, and plenty of Vinyl records that have been shaped into circular saws, ready to teach the digital-diehards a lesson in who the daddy is!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 20:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3489-27</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/what-a-nightmare/3489.rss">What a Nightmare!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
