<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Axoloti Community - Topics tagged challenge</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/tags/challenge</link>
    <description>Topics tagged challenge</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 16:13:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/tags/challenge.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Help with/How to approach patch (Asynchronous 4 Track Looper)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Brett.Gershon Lambsquarter]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Patching</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/brett.gershon">@Brett.Gershon</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Hello friends,</p>

<p>New to the Axoloti Platform, and while I have some limited experience with pure data and Max/MSP, I'm finding myself stumped on starting this patch I'm dreaming up. Any help or direction would be much appreciated.</p>

<p>What I'm looking to do, is create a 4 track looper with 4 independently dynamically manipulatable buffers. Ideally, each buffer would have controls to manipulate the length of the buffer as well as start/end position, and fine and coarse pitch/speed control i.e. tape speed. A button for recording and playback of each track, as well as an erase function on each track. These are the essentials of what I am trying to create here, but it would be even cooler if I could implement a switch which enables a sync between all four tracks so that length becomes fixed to what is set by track 1's parameters. Anyone give me any pointers on how to make this happen if any of it is even possible with this platform?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 5</p>
            <p>Participants: 3</p>
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/help-with-how-to-approach-patch-asynchronous-4-track-looper/7063">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/help-with-how-to-approach-patch-asynchronous-4-track-looper/7063</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 16:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-7063</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/help-with-how-to-approach-patch-asynchronous-4-track-looper/7063.rss">Help with/How to approach patch (Asynchronous 4 Track Looper)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Fellowship of Axo - Seeds of inspiration</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Challenges</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <h1>Fellowship of Axo - 1 of 2</h1>

<p><strong>Submission date: open ended, feel free to add more seeds at any time</strong></p>

<p>The "Fellowship of Axo" challenge centres on collaboration, exploring with others.<br>Part one is about providing seeds of inspiration to other musicians, which they can plant and grow to fruition in <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-reaping-the-fruits">part two</a>.</p>

<p>For this challenge, your task is to provide a seed of inspiration, something that can be used (and abused) in part two. To encourage participation, I'll keep it vague, but my ideas are</p>

<ul>
<li>an audio source  : a sound, part of a track, a melody </li>
<li>a patch :   an instrument, a sequencer</li>
</ul>

<p>the seed can be as simple or as complex as you like, sometimes, a tiny snippet of audio is all that's needed to take us off into a new direction.</p>

<p>In  <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-reaping-the-fruits">Part Two (reaping the fruits)</a> musicians can take one or more seeds, and use to create a piece. they will be free to use it in anyway they see fit, either in part or in full, recognisable or not <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=3" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>

<p>When creating the seed,  we are all restricted in time, so make it simple for your fellows, if your submitting a patch, consider an audio snippet too - perhaps your fellow might choose to use just the audio.</p>

<h2>Restrictions</h2>

<ul>
<li>Axoloti must be a major part the seed creation</li>
<li>Seed must not include any copyrighted material </li>
<li>To use the seed (in part 2) must not require anything other than Axoloti</li>
</ul>

<p>you can use any tools you wish alongside axoloti<br>e.g. its fine to use a synth, and use Axoloti as an FX (if the FX is the major part of the submission), or flipped around use Axoloti as the sound generator and use external effects.<br>again, samples ( in accordance with copyright) , synthesis, fx -  all is game for creation.</p>

<h2>Submission</h2>

<p>demonstration - either video or soundcloud link, demonstrating what your offering as a seed. embed a link here, the name of the game here, is make it simple for the fellowship to get a glimpse of the potential of your seed.</p>

<p>'The Seed'  - depending upon what your seeding, you can provide an audio file, or patch or both.</p>

<p>Audio File - which can be used directly as the seed for part two.<br>post link here - WAV format, hosted on a site that does not require registration.  (Id recommend dropbox, via a shared link) , try to keep the size 'reasonable'... I personally don't want to be downloading GBs of samples <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p>Patch - you can post here and/or you can upload to community library and provide details here</p>

<p>lets get sowing .... the more seeds we sow, the more fruit we will reap.</p>

<p><strong>note:</strong> it looks like everyone is busy, so Ive decided to make this an 'open ended' challenge, with no end date, so please feel free to add new seeds at any time... and hopefully someone will pick it up to develop it.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 8</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-seeds-of-inspiration/3150">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-seeds-of-inspiration/3150</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-3150</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-seeds-of-inspiration/3150.rss">Fellowship of Axo - Seeds of inspiration</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Fellowship of Axo - Reaping the fruits</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Challenges</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <h1>Fellowship of Axo - 2 of 2</h1>

<p>This is the second part of the Fellowship of Axo challenge.</p>

<p>In this part we take 'seeds' from part one of this challenge , and tend and nurture them, and the reap the fruits ... or in plain speak simply take one or more seeds from <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-seeds-of-inspiration-challenge">Seeds of inspiration</a> and use it as inspiration for a track <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p><strong>submission date : open ended, feel free to pick a seed and develop it, and put the post the results here.</strong> </p>

<h2>Restrictions</h2>

<p>only rule is you have to use at least one seed, detail here which seed(s) you used.</p>

<p>apart from that no rules. you can use the seed 'as is' ,or mangle/edit/change the seed beyond the point of recognition. you can use whatever you want to produce the track, e.g. daws/synths/fx - as long as Axoloti plays some part in the track.</p>

<h2>Submissions</h2>

<p>post entries in this thread - either as soundcloud or youtube links.<br>include a reference to the seed(s) you used in the track</p>

<p><strong>note:</strong> it looks like everyone is busy, so Ive decided to make this an 'open ended' challenge, with no end date, so you are free to add new seeds or new fruits at any time. the more seeds added, the more fruit we can grow <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-reaping-the-fruits/3216">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-reaping-the-fruits/3216</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 17:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-3216</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/fellowship-of-axo-reaping-the-fruits/3216.rss">Fellowship of Axo - Reaping the fruits</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Its all about the music (challenge)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Challenges</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>lots of tech talk on the forum, anyone fancy a simple challenge to tip the balance the  other way a little ?</p>

<p><strong>Challenge</strong>: make a 'piece' of music using Axoloti </p>

<p>any style, any duration... any definition of the term music <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=3" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> <br>submit as many as you have time for, but must be made between now and end date (15th March and 29th March) - no previously released stuff.</p>

<p>no votes this time, its all about sitting down and making some music, here and now with Axoloti.</p>

<p><strong>End date:</strong> 29th March (two weeks from now)</p>

<p><strong>Restrictions:</strong> just one, all sound generated and effects used must come from Axoloti, so you cannot use external synths or effects (software or hardware) - thats it.</p>

<p>to keep it as open as possible:</p>

<ul>
<li>you can use daws or other hardware for multi-tracking/loop/sequence/mixing or whatever</li>
<li>you can use samples in axoloti</li>
<li>as you can multi track, you can of course use as many axoloti patches as you wish</li>
</ul>

<p>mixing, I guess we can allow some subtle eq/compression, but lets keep it subtle, unless its done in Axoloti, then it can be as wild as you like <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/emoji_one/wink.png?v=3" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> </p>

<p>this means no clever patching/programming is required, some simple axoloti patches are all you need, and you can glue it together with other tools you have.</p>

<p>of course, this is fully inclusive... if your thing is detailed patching/sound design/generative music, thats welcome too, whatever floats your boat.</p>

<p><strong>Submission:</strong> post a link to soundcloud, you tube etc  in this thread.<br>please make sure its an embedded link, people are unlikely to want to start downloading, and visiting other sites.</p>

<p>if you wish, you can also share any patch or patches in the community library, but <strong>this is not a requirement</strong> for this challenge.</p>

<p><strong>Tips:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>for those just starting out, the tutorial and demo patches give the basics for all you need for this challenge</li>
<li>for those who may not have been keeping up with axoloti development, 1.0.12 introduced some new oscillators (brds) and effects (clds,rngs,lmnts)  - with these you can easily create nice effects and instruments e.g. a brds oscillator into a rngs/reverb, is simple but really effective, that anyone can patch in minutes</li>
<li>the community library has a lot of objects covering many areas, just don't get overwhelmed in the choice.</li>
</ul>

<p>Hopefully wherever you are on your Axoloti journey, you can join in and have some fun, and use it as an excuse to 'focus on the music'</p>

<p>(any thoughts/suggestions, feel free to post below)</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 23</p>
            <p>Participants: 7</p>
            <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/its-all-about-the-music-challenge/3062">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/its-all-about-the-music-challenge/3062</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 15:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-3062</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/its-all-about-the-music-challenge/3062.rss">Its all about the music (challenge)</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
