<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Axoloti Community - Topics tagged troubleshooting</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/tags/troubleshooting</link>
    <description>Topics tagged troubleshooting</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 20:09:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/tags/troubleshooting.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Getting started...patcher won&#39;t start up right</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DrGwon Steve Fernandez]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Helpdesk</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/drgwon">@DrGwon</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Hello im brand new with axoloti and I can't start the patcher. I download the runtime and then installed it and then download the app and doble click the app package and installed into applications folder (I just follow the instructions on installing post).<br>  all looks good and in the right folder to me. BUT when I open the APP the only window I can see its the "console" no patcher and no file or preference or any option just AXOLOTI appears at the top bar.<br>console doesn't advice any ERROR message(connected its on red) <br>im running Mac OS 10.13.<br>what can't I do to open the patcher?           <br>im pretty sure there is something really obvious im missing but can't find the problem.<br>(Please excuse my poor English ,,I hope you can understand it).</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 27</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/getting-started-patcher-wont-start-up-right/6173">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/getting-started-patcher-wont-start-up-right/6173</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 20:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-6173</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/getting-started-patcher-wont-start-up-right/6173.rss">Getting started...patcher won&#39;t start up right</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Windows 7 Install ... once more :/</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@alt]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Helpdesk</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/alt">@alt</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Hello together,</p>

<p>First post here, but reading since I got my Axo in February -- I really like your community <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> </p>

<p>I just setup a Windows 7 64 System on my Laptop, since some driver issues with other hardware didn't really work out under Linux (I'd prefer that, but well..). </p>

<p>So I happily saw release 1.0.12-2, downloaded and installed as usual;  <code>no matching PID/VID</code>. Bummer.</p>

<p>I read thoroughly existing threads with similar topics, but the suggested methods do not work. I can further rule out a faulty cable or faulty Axo, since both work on the linux partition of the very same machine without a hitch. </p>

<p>The actual problem:</p>

<p>Windows will recognize both Axo-Devices, but the axo-patcher still won't find the unit.</p>

<p>I tried:</p>

<ul>
<li>replacing the driver for Axo Bulk IF with Zadig (Zadigversion from Axo_Runtime and newer version from Website)<br>=&gt; no change. Substituting libusb-drivers works "for windows", since it will show in the device manager under "libusb**-devices", but still PID/VID-error in axo-patcher.</li>
<li>Installing the compatible drivers mentioned before (winusbcompat) for the Bulk IF<br>=&gt; no change. Recognized by windows as "WinUsb 1.0", but PID/VID-error in axo-patcher.</li>
<li>Booting to Flashrescue.<br>That one is interesting since it works as described <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/installing-on-windows/36">here</a> up to the point where the axo-patcher will not detect any DFU-device. (Windows recognizes the ST*-device and lets me change drivers accordingly.)</li>
<li>Booting with s2 held down to remove any sdcard-weirdness (I understood that this could help, but can't find the thread right now).</li>
</ul>

<p>I tried all of the above also with release 1.0.12 to no avail. </p>

<p>The laptop is a Lenovo Thinkpad (e535), the chipset from AMD; I removed the Lenovodrivers and let Windows-Update get its generic driver for the USB-Host, still nothing. </p>

<p>To me this reeks of a weird cornercase of driverfu**ckups under win, but I am out of my wits. Any of you guys got some idea? </p>

<p>Thanks &amp; Keep up the good work, <br>-alt</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 17</p>
            <p>Participants: 6</p>
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/windows-7-install-once-more/4463">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/windows-7-install-once-more/4463</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 10:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-4463</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/windows-7-install-once-more/4463.rss">Windows 7 Install ... once more :/</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Tb cycle ad bug</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@hyena giona vinti]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Community Library</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/hyena">@hyena</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>hello people!<br>i found a bug in the "cycle ad" module by tb in the community library.<br>the inlets for modulating attack and decay are disconnected from the actual parameters.<br>i corrected it because i needed the module in a patch and here's my corrected version:<br><a class="attachment" href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/original/2X/9/908561e08d1a2c3a035296e7531d92d88f0ebc70.axo">cyclingADmod.axo</a> (1.5 KB)</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/tb-cycle-ad-bug/5019">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/tb-cycle-ad-bug/5019</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 06:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-5019</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/tb-cycle-ad-bug/5019.rss">Tb cycle ad bug</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Troubleshooting Guide</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
          <category>User Guide</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <h1>Overview</h1>

<p>This guide is intended to help users troubleshoot problems with Axoloti hardware and software, this is an attempt to collect together common issues that we have seen since Axoloti has been released. <br>I hope that the community can extend this guide with relevant links to thread for common issues.<br>Note: It is <strong>intended</strong> to cover patching</p>

<p><strong>important note:</strong> this is a wiki post so regular users can edit/update it, e.g. to link to other relevant topics.<br>please keep this post concise, and rather link to other relevant posts where necessary, as users do/will not read a massive 20 page post <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> </p>

<p>If you have an issue when first installing Axoloti , it is assumed you have read, and re-read the relevant installation guide, seriously go read it again <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> </p>

<p>please also remember many users are running Axoloti on the latest version of all operating systems, so if its not working on your system... something is 'different' about your system, so our task here is to work out what.</p>

<h1>Guidelines</h1>

<p>aka, before you report an issue... <br>I know these all seem 'obvious' but you will be amazed at the number of times we see posts that miss off these items</p>

<ul>
<li>check that you are running on a 'supported platform' (see installation guide)</li>
<li>check that you are running the latest update for your operating system</li>
<li>check that you are running the latest version of java for your operating system (Java 1.8)</li>
<li>check you have the latest version of the Axoloti runtime AND patcher...   (yes there are two things to install)</li>
<li>gather all information about your setup, operating system version, java version , you need to include this in your post!</li>
<li>search the forum for similar issues, the forums now has years worth of posts from new and experienced users, installing on various platforms... its unlikely you are the first to experience a problem.</li>
<li>try to be clear on where the problem lies, and be specific</li>
<li>gather any logs, or console messages - include everything, something you may think is irrelevant , may be.<br>seriously, reading posts like 'axoloti crashes' , axoloti does not start... gives the community zero information to help them help you... the more effort you put in describing your setup, what you have tried, what you see. Also people are generally more helpful, when they see you have already done some 'legwork'</li>
<li>check your virus/firewall software, in particular has it quarantined any files</li>
<li>java can allow users to have multiple runtimes installed (common for developers in particular), check your default is set to the latest 1.8 release</li>
</ul>

<h1>Next...</h1>

<p><strong>once you have done all of the above</strong></p>

<p>Issues tend to lie in a couple of areas, and you need to narrow down where the issue is, and be able to report some simple facts.. most importantly we need to narrow down if its hardware or software issue.</p>

<h2>Axoloti Patcher</h2>

<p>If there is an issue with the patcher be clear where the issue lies</p>

<h3>Patcher not starting up/hanging</h3>

<ul>
<li>does axolotl patcher start at all, does it bring up the console window?</li>
<li>try to start patcher without Axoloti connected, does this work ?</li>
<li>try to start axoloti from command line, this gives a bunch more messages?</li>
<li>trying deleting the axoloti.pref in documents directory</li>
</ul>

<h3>Patcher does not see/will not connect to hardware</h3>

<ul>
<li>try different usb cables, one that you know carries data not just power</li>
<li>can you see any device listed in 'Select device ' in axoloti</li>
<li>use the operating system tools , to see if it can see the device</li>
<li>try to boot put Axoloti into DFU mode and use rescue flash (details in install guide) </li>
<li>see <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-hardware/59">'Axoloti Hardware'</a> section for more </li>
</ul>

<h3>Issues taking patches live / compilation</h3>

<ul>
<li>90% of issues here are caused by incorrect installation of the axoloti runtime, check it again <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> </li>
<li>temporarily disable your virus checker</li>
<li>check your virus software has not quarantined any files</li>
</ul>

<h3>Issues with library synchronisation, including not seeing factory objects</h3>

<ul>
<li>if you don't see any factory objects, its because Axoloti has not been able to download the Factory library.</li>
<li>you need an active internet connection during initial installation to get the libraries, see relevant posts if you want to use 'offline'</li>
<li>if you have an issue with 'synchronisation', the recommend first step, is to use File-&gt;Preferences-&gt; Libraries/Reset All. </li>
</ul>

<h2>Axoloti Hardware</h2>

<h3>Patcher runs patch, but then disconnects from hardware</h3>

<p>This can have many causes, but the key thing to determine here is... is the patch still running? i.e. has the axoloti hardware crashed whilst running your patch <strong>or</strong> has the patch just disconnected?<br>the best way to determine this is to have the patch do something that you can 'detect' even without the patch running e.g. add an oscillator, that sends a constant tone to the output , </p>

<p>some patches/functionality requires an SD card</p>

<h2>Midi Controllers</h2>

<p>There are a huge number of controllers reported working with Axoloti, see this <a>thread</a><br>the most likely reason for a controller not to work is:<br>- its not USB MIDI class compliant <br>- it has an integrated usb hub (axoloti does not currently support USB hubs)</p>

<ul>
<li>check the compatible list to see if your device is listed </li>
<li>check that its class compliant</li>
<li>connect your device when axoloti is running and connected, axoloti will report details of the device to the console.</li>
<li>if your device has a power inlet, test to see if it works when using it powered (rather than usb powered)</li>
</ul>

<h1>operating system versions</h1>

<p>The best support is always going to be on the operating system that the developers use, and they will tend to use the OS that most users are on, or are likely to be moving to soon... this typically means the latest OS but <strong>not immediatly on release</strong>   </p>

<p>new versions of operating systems, dont upgrade immediately... this is generally a bad idea, developers only have a limited number of machines to test on, and often after a new release some other (music) software is not working... so its not a great music platform.</p>

<p>old versions of operating systems, again... at some point developers have to move machines forward to support what the majority of users are on.</p>

<p>beta versions of operating systems/java etc - whilst its great getting feedback from users that axoloti is working or not, but dont expect support/fixes... there are only a few of us, and we cannot necessarily spare a machine to upgrade to the beta OS.</p>

<p>developers please take particular care, often development tools change the environment, or we run beta versions of software. this cannot reasonably be supported.</p>

<p>example: I (thetechnobear) will usually have my machines on the latest release, until a new release is made then I will upgrade one machine... then later once its obviously stable move my others e.g. on macs, I currently have all on 10.12.6... but will be upgrading one to 10.13 probably when it hits 10.13.1 or 10.13.2... then if thats successful, after a few weeks/months. I'll move the other. <br>(sometimes I might upgrade one machine earlier if I know there is an issue which needs to be fixed, but dont count on it <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> ) </p>

<h1>Links</h1>

<p>this section should contain links to useful post regarding troubleshooting particular issues.<br>(to do)</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/troubleshooting-guide/3914">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/troubleshooting-guide/3914</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 13:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-3914</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/troubleshooting-guide/3914.rss">Troubleshooting Guide</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Normalize Samples</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Nippon]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Software</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/nippon">@Nippon</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Hi,<br>i want to normalize samples I recorded and stored with table read. how is this possible.<br>some sound sources are really quite for my sampler and I want to compress the recordings and to normalize them, so that they are loud too.<br>is there a possibility?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/normalize-samples/4065">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/normalize-samples/4065</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 17:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-4065</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/normalize-samples/4065.rss">Normalize Samples</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Is a TDM input on Axoloti possible?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@arvid Arvid Jense]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hardware</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/arvid">@arvid</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I'm designing a system with 8 microphones coming through a TDM codec into a DSP with 2 analog outputs. </p>

<p>I see that Axoloti's STM32F427 should be able to receive this through its SAI port. However I cannot seem to find whether or not the SAI port is free in some way, or if it is in use. </p>

<p>And even  if I could somehow get access to the SAI port, it would mean I would have to write my own TDM object right?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/is-a-tdm-input-on-axoloti-possible/3943">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/is-a-tdm-input-on-axoloti-possible/3943</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 12:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-topic-3943</guid>
          <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/is-a-tdm-input-on-axoloti-possible/3943.rss">Is a TDM input on Axoloti possible?</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
