<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834</link>
    <description>This is relocating a reply to a question from @Gavin in [this post](http://community.axoloti.com/t/starting-points-for-guitarists/3809/8?u=kat).  

For a while I have been in pursuit of &quot;expression control for everything&quot; with guitar pedals.  One solution that I have been experimenting with is digipots controlled by a Teensy.  In reply to @Gavin&#39;s question, yeah, this totally works.  In my opinion, it doesn&#39;t make a lot of sense to use Axoloti for control, because Axoloti has so many other more powerful things it can do it seems a bit &quot;wasteful&quot; to me.  Teensy is cheaper and smaller and can be built into a little self-contained controller or even fit within a standard guitar pedal enclosure.

I did write up a little how-to on getting the digipots to work [here](http://www.kathrynschaffer.com/unpro.php#teensyDigipotModal).  What I haven&#39;t written up yet is the part of connecting this to MIDI control, which is also pretty easy with the Teensy, and then makes it possible to use an off-the-shelf MIDI foot pedal/expression pedal to control analog pedal parameters.  

None of this is all that novel.  Someone who does a much more sophisticated version is [this guy](http://roaldvandillewijn.nl/), whom I have not seen live but have heard about from others.  

My challenge, now that I have something that does what I thought I wanted, is figuring out what I can do with it that is actually musically interesting.  Some of my initial experiments are pretty underwhelming, but I haven&#39;t pushed it very far yet.  Would love to hear if anyone else has explored similar projects.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 01:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Lounge</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ambitious Yes, expect to achieve highly unlikely but who cares, I am giving myself alot of time to chip away at it, not too fused if I don't get their, but it will be cool to learn about it along the way.<br>Yes, vactorals are controlled with PWM.</p>

<p>Pedal Side..<br>For outputs, what I see is, you have your base signal per per pedal, split the signal into two with a buffer splitter, control both levels with Vactrols, one signal goes to the pedal, the other signal bypasses the pedal, and then both signals are mixed back togethether befor the next  pedal.</p>

<p>Matrix side.. (not like to matrix's I have seen on line)<br>For each chanel of the matrix mixer, there is cascading buffer splitter,in the case of 5 pedals, 5 buffers, first split to 5 out puts, next 4 and so on. I have found with this setup, pedals can be sequenced in series and or parallel as prefered, but unlike the matrix mixers I have seen on line, you can't feedback onto a pedal already being used in an earlier sequence. Vactrols will be at each buffer output to be able to select the desiredpedal sequence.</p>

<p>The reason for all this is because I think current pedal loopers are severely overpriced and very limited with what they can do, and in additionj with this setup, adding the vactrols allows it to be controlled by midi. And I have also seen realy awkward attempts to retro fit midi systems to guitar pedals, and convinced there has to be an easier way. On paper, the idea is cool, and happy to share as may be someone esle may get enspired and be better at doing it.</p>

<p><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/31</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 01:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-31</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That sounds very ambitious! Could be a great system in the end though!</p>

<p>So you will use pwm in order to control the vactrols right? How do you get that many outputs?</p>

<p>For matrix like aplications I'm very happy with my fireface ucx, I figured out how to controll it via midi in standalone from axoloti so I will use it to mix different instruments and then send them to multiple axolotis either as send fx, routing through the axo, or for sending channels to a looper.<br>The big advantage of this is that it's mainly an audio interface so I can record all the layers seperetaley.<br>And I get eq+compressor per channel.<br>In your use case it might be too much ad/da conversions though maybe.</p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="29" data-topic="3834"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/gavin/40/5153_1.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>Regarding the 4066.. to get bipolar voltage from the 3.3volts on the Axo, you will need to create a virtual ground. I don't have a lot of experience in this area, but check online, there are lots.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I've been trying to built a mixer with opamps, there is plenty of examples that require virtual ground, but somehow I never got that to work properly.</p>

<p>I've made good experience with these kind of boards for powering a rolang gk preamp with +-9v from axo 5V<br><aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
    <a href="https://www.ebay.de/itm/DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Down-Converter-5V-24V-Positive-Negative-Dual-Mini-Amplifier-/113236210368?var=&amp;amp;hash=item0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">ebay.de</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://i.ebayimg.com/images/i/113236210368-0-1/s-l1000.jpg" width="" height="" class="thumbnail">

<h3><a href="https://www.ebay.de/itm/DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Down-Converter-5V-24V-Positive-Negative-Dual-Mini-Amplifier-/113236210368?var=&amp;amp;hash=item0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">DC-DC Voltage Step Down Converter ±5V-±24V Positive&amp;Negative Dual Mini Amplifier...</a></h3>

<p>DC-DC Voltage Step Down Converter ±5V-±24V Positive&amp;Negative Dual Mini Amplifier | Business &amp; Industrie, Elektronik &amp; Messtechnik, Elektronische Bauelemente | eBay!</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/30</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 20:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-30</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The reason why I chose not to go with the digipot solution which could still eventuate if this doesn't work, is I was looking into something that way down the track on a larger scale. Not just a way of controlling guitar pedals, but also a matrix mixer type setup per pedal.<br>So to begin with, for each pedal, 2 buffered signals split and controlled by the vactrol pairs, one to the pedal, one bypassing the pedal, then at least 4 more vactrol pairs retro fitted in place of the pedal pots, this would chain about 5 pedals, all routed via matrix mixer for 5 pedals would require at least 15 more vactrol pairs to assemble.<br>I know I am way ahead of myself on this, but who knows how far I will get..</p>

<p>Regarding the 4066.. to get bipolar voltage from the 3.3volts on the Axo, you will need to create a virtual ground. I don't have a lot of experience in this area, but check online, there are lots.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/29</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 01:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-29</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="3834"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/gavin/40/5153_1.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>I tried the 4066, couldn't get it to work either, its my understanding is if you are routing audio through it, VDD to VSS has to cover your full peak to peak swing. So in the case of the Axo, minimum - vdd = +1.65, vss = -1.65. But I never got that far.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>So that means you would need to a bipolar voltage for fo vdd vss? <br>It should be possible to get that from the 3.3V of axo right? </p>

<p>I Heard that VDD should be the same voltage as the switching voltage.</p>

<aside class="quote" data-post="27" data-topic="3834"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/gavin/40/5153_1.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>The approach is to have two vactorals operating like a pot, using PWM for switching, so one is controlled by NPN trany and the other by a sister PNP trany. That way they should function opposite to each other, like the turning of the pot.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Ah that is clever. Yes a pot is indeed two resistors when you turn it so when the one goes up the other goes down. </p>

<p>I'm really interested in this option too. I initially wanted to switch channels on a preamp, to switch between clean, crunch and drive, but I could also just replace the gain and volume by this vactrol system you describe and then just switch between different settings of the two. </p>

<p>Or I give the digipots a try, since Kat already got them to work succesfully <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/thinking.png?v=5" title=":thinking:" class="emoji" alt=":thinking:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 16:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-28</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I tried the 4066, couldn't get it to work either, its my understanding is if you are routing audio through it, VDD to VSS has to cover your full peak to peak swing. So in the case of the Axo, minimum - vdd = +1.65, vss = -1.65. But I never got that far.</p>

<p>As for the vactorals, I still feel as though its the best approach, plenty to test with, I drew up a basic circuit, and even taught myself to etch a circuit board to mount it all on, hack out an old overdrive pedal to test it with, but didn't work, I think I expected better results with less testing, so I need to do more breadboard testing. Its not high priority, but I do slowly chip away at it.</p>

<p>The approach is to have two vactorals operating like a pot, using PWM for switching, so one is controlled by NPN trany and the other by a sister PNP trany. That way they should function opposite to each other, like the turning of the pot.</p>

<p><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 02:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-27</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>He <a class="mention" href="/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> how is it going with the vactrols?</p>

<p>I've been trying to use the 4066 for switching between different preamp channels but I don't get it to work with axoloti.</p>

<p>Is this right?<br><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a data-download-href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/a3fd55eb03a04a7f461beb3eecf704dad049969f" href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/original/2X/a/a3fd55eb03a04a7f461beb3eecf704dad049969f.png" class="lightbox" title="Bildschirmfoto 2019-01-29 um 18.04.18.png"><img src="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/optimized/2X/a/a3fd55eb03a04a7f461beb3eecf704dad049969f_1_690x298.png" width="690" height="298"><div class="meta">
<span class="filename">Bildschirmfoto 2019-01-29 um 18.04.18.png</span><span class="informations">1030x446 58.6 KB</span><span class="expand"></span>
</div></a></div><br>EDIT:<br>Just found this, so my logic seems to be right. I tried VDD both with a 9v battery and 3.3VDD and it didnt work <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/frowning.png?v=5" title=":frowning:" class="emoji" alt=":frowning:"> </p>

<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a data-download-href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/277a7602cafcfa44c3cf3f45898a3e2d464c622b" href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/original/2X/2/277a7602cafcfa44c3cf3f45898a3e2d464c622b.jpg" class="lightbox" title="Bildschirmfoto 2019-01-29 um 18.21.45.jpg"><img src="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/optimized/2X/2/277a7602cafcfa44c3cf3f45898a3e2d464c622b_1_690x497.jpg" width="690" height="497"><div class="meta">
<span class="filename">Bildschirmfoto 2019-01-29 um 18.21.45.jpg</span><span class="informations">1666x1202 233 KB</span><span class="expand"></span>
</div></a></div></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-26</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Still doing a few other things first before I dive in the deep end, but I have started tinkering,, they are far too expensive to buy, so yes its DIY Vactrols.<br>Because I intend to build quite a few, I have ordered 50 LED's, 50 LDR's, next was to find an acceptable build, I have gone with and led with end sanded flat, glued to an LDR with a tiny bit of clear silicon, then into clear heat shrink, then positioned into black plastic tube (outer casing of a cable) just big enough to fit, then both ends sealed with molten black wax. No testing done yet.<br>Plan is as follows.. Axo will send midi data to an arduino nano, which will interpret and send instructions via I2C to a PWM module, the PWM will then be filtered into a voltage, then connected to the LED of the vactrol. I ma waiting for the PWM module to arrive, as well as a simple midi shield for the nano.<br>The following are the challenges of concern.. 1 being of most concern.<br>1. The PWM to voltage filter, there are so many online, many will need to be tested to find out which is the best.<br>2. Vactrol as voltage divider, getting the correct circuit for this is essential to control the Audio.<br>3. Vactrol as adjustable resister, this is straight forward but as it is likely to be used to replace pots in an effect pedal, I am thinking of easy way to just unplug a pot and plug in the vactrol.</p>

<p>The reason why I chose this over digipots, cheaper, and it seams a lot easier to do large volumes. The PWM module will have 16 PWM outs, and as many as 96 pwm modules can be connected together, but I won't need that much.</p>

<p>I will start slowly, first with just on / off type control, then adding in parameter like control.</p>

<p>A lot of work to get through..<br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/tired_face.png?v=5" title=":tired_face:" class="emoji" alt=":tired_face:"><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/25</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 21:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-25</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="3834"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar">Gavin:</div>
<blockquote><p>VACTROLS, VACTROLS, VACTROLS.....</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>Sounds promising! Can you post a link of wich vactrol you've been using? Or have you built it yourself?</p>

<p><a class="mention" href="/u/kat">@kat</a><br>that is some pretty rough but nice sounds!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/24</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 20:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-24</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Some nice sounds..<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/23</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 02:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-23</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@kat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/kat">@kat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi all,</p>

<p>As promised, here are some sound clips of weird things that I was able to do with a digipot that I liked. These are not attempts to use a digipot for presets or to control commercial pedals.  I have a modified clone of a Lovetone Big Cheese that I made and I set it up specifically for this purpose, putting in a switching jack that I can use to swap a digipot in for the fuzz control.  So far this is the only pedal I have tried this with (but I have some others waiting ...)</p>

<p>I ended up discovering two things that I found musically interesting:<br>1) modulating the fuzz tone with weird patterns to create an unusual rhythmic shift (which, given this pedal, also seems to create some sound that is reminiscent of some large beam of wood creaking... I have no idea what that is from, but I like it).  A demo of this effect is in this little sound clip:<br>          <audio controls="">
            <source src="http://kathrynschaffer.com/audio/clip_digipot_disassembly.mp3"></source>
            <a href="http://kathrynschaffer.com/audio/clip_digipot_disassembly.mp3" rel="nofollow noopener">http://kathrynschaffer.com/audio/clip_digipot_disassembly.mp3</a>
          </audio>
</p>

<p>In the clip, which is extracted from a full song, I am playing rapid chords at first and then I just let the guitar/pedal ring out and feed back.  </p>

<p>2) modulating the fuzz "knob" at audio frequencies seems to send this circuit into oscillation in ways I do not totally understand. In this little clip (which was recorded straight with my laptop, so the audio quality is especially poor), I am first just letting the pedal do its thing, and then I layer some guitar stuff over it.  </p>

          <audio controls="">
            <source src="http://kathrynschaffer.com/audio/poorly_recorded_cool_synthy_thing.mp3"></source>
            <a href="http://kathrynschaffer.com/audio/poorly_recorded_cool_synthy_thing.mp3" rel="nofollow noopener">http://kathrynschaffer.com/audio/poorly_recorded_cool_synthy_thing.mp3</a>
          </audio>


<p>In both cases, I am using a Teensy to control the digipot.  In the first case, the pattern is a partial sine-wave sweep with some glitches (zeroed-out spots) in a particular sequence.  In the second case, it is a sine wave with a steadily progressing frequency.  I have no idea why the pedal clearly jumps from one note to the next in the 2nd case... I expected it to be a straight tone sweep, so something is clearly going on that I don't understand (but I like it).</p>

<p>So anyway, the lesson here is that digipots may not solve all your conundrums in building the perfect guitar system, but you might discover some weird things if you hack a pedal to use one and play around with it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 01:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-22</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>VACTROLS, VACTROLS, VACTROLS.....<br>Have been learning about them today, don't see why they can't solve all the issues and passive at that. And can connect them up to PWM signal, filtered to a regular signal as voltage control for the vactrol, done, problem solved, wallah, bobs your uncle, not mine..<br>Control volume, cross fade signals, even substitute pots in pedals..<br>Exactly what I need... I hope... !!<br>Now just need to find the right parts to buy in bulk..<br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/weary.png?v=5" title=":weary:" class="emoji" alt=":weary:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/21</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 09:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-21</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Correction, operates at 5 volts and up, and has 4 fixed address options.<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/sob.png?v=5" title=":sob:" class="emoji" alt=":sob:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 05:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-20</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>4066 solution is a little week for my goals, and the ready made audio patch bays seem to a bit of overkill.<br>Further reading I have found IC PT2258, 6 ins, 6 outs, runs off as little as 3 volts, communicates via I2C. Although I think it has 2 fixed address options, I can run two chips which will allow for audio volume level routed either to a stomp or bypass, this should allow for 5 stomps to be controlled. Should be able to control with Arduino receiving Midi signals. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/thinking.png?v=5" title=":thinking:" class="emoji" alt=":thinking:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 04:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-19</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="17" data-topic="3834"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/lokki/40/2882_1.png" class="avatar">lokki:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>if you replace a switch, a relay works, but is expensive and often a simple 4066 solution can work:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thetonegod.com/tech/switches/switches.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.thetonegod.com/tech/switches/switches.html</a></p>
</blockquote></aside>

<p>cool thanks for the article! 4066 sounds indeed good and is cheap. Would be awesome if I could hack my pocket amp into a pseudeo 3 channel amp, digitally controlled. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>

<p>All these matrix solutions look very capable but are waaay to big and heavy for the 21.century imho. </p>

<p>In that sense I'm really happy about using the RME UCX. It's software even looks like a digital matrix mixer and it can be controlled via midi. It does have eq+compression on each channel and I can record each channel either on my laptop or my phone (when it's in class compliant mode). Only downside is that each loop runs through dac/adc, allthough that one is really high quality in that case.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 01:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-18</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>these pop up infrequently on eBay:</p>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
    <a href="http://synthnl.blogspot.nl/2011/11/anatek-smp-16-manual.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">synthnl.blogspot.nl</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5Os3AfScSeQ/Tr-pY-LrNqI/AAAAAAAADg4/EjYEQSgvypY/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Anatek+SMP-16.jpg" width="" height="" class="thumbnail">

<h3><a href="http://synthnl.blogspot.nl/2011/11/anatek-smp-16-manual.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Anatek SMP-16 Manual</a></h3>

<p>The Anatek SMP-16 is a very versatile automated Midi and Audio patch bay. I have two of them in my studio and I love them. They are noise fr...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>


<p>the shit if you want to mix audio/midi.</p>

<p>or:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.deepsonic.ch/deep/htm/360_systems_audio_matrix_am16.php" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.deepsonic.ch/deep/htm/360_systems_audio_matrix_am16.php</a></p>

<p>also there was a schematic online for a matrix chip solution with osc control, but i cannot find it right now.</p>

<p>as for controlling pedals digitally there are multiple ways, depending on the use case:</p>

<p>if you replace a switch, a relay works, but is expensive and often a simple 4066 solution can work:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetonegod.com/tech/switches/switches.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.thetonegod.com/tech/switches/switches.html</a></p>

<p>for pots the situation is more complex.</p>

<p>as soon as audio passes through the pot (which happens a lot in guitar pedals) you have to be very careful. digipots can usually only control signals in the supply voltage range, so you have to make sure your signals stays within bounds. sometimes a vactrol based approach is better suited than. basically a led and a phototransistor acting as a variable resistance... this was and is used in a lot of tremolos and compressors.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 08:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-17</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The main idea comes from what I think would be an improvement on what we call at the moment, pedal loopers / switches / routers etc.. they are quite pricy, you can setup presets of what pedals are on or off etc.. but to me this is just a convenience, not something that improves what you are doing. Then when I discovered matrix mixers, I thought this would be pretty cool for pedals, some people have already done this, but there would be an awful lot of adjustments for every setup. So then it dawned on me, something in between both systems, a pedal looper like setup, with digipots or some other IC like the PT2257 that can split the audio by % to the effect and or away from the effect, controlled by midi from the Axo. The PT2257 IC could actually be the icing on the cake for this sort of setup. If possible to add the ability to switch the effect to either serial or parallel would also be a target.<br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/16</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 01:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-16</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>He folks really interesting topic! I use the axoloti very often as guitar effects unit, usualy in combination with some kind of preamp and other pedals.<br>I would love to have some axoloti based digital controll over my palmer pocket amp (and maybe more pedals). More concrete I would love to change the drive setting switch (wich has 3 different settings) and the on/off from my axoloti. Since this is all a combination of on/offs I think I could do this with a relais.</p>

<p>Do any of you have recomendations for a relais that I could use for this kind of purpose? Preferably it shouldn't be too pricey.</p>

<p>Also this matrix mixer Idea of <a class="mention" href="/u/gavin">@Gavin</a>  sounds really intriguing. At the moment I am using my rme ucx in standalone and midi controlled by axoloti for this kind of purpose but having several chains always involves going through the dac/adc so I would love to outsource part of the routing process into the analog world.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/15</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-15</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@orbitbot Patrik Johnson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/orbitbot">@orbitbot</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/kat">@kat</a> That sounds interesting, do you have a recording setup to share what it sounds like?</p>

<p>Wrt to the other things, I'm probably going to completely separate the control of my axoloti with an ESP-32-based board firing MIDI controls at the patches and hook most things up to the ESP-32 (mainly to try to have access through wifi/bluetooth to see if it's actually possible...) Got most of the parts, but need to get cracking on soldering and programming at some point.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 23:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-14</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@kat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/kat">@kat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/timeorspace">@timeorspace</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> ... glad this continues to be an active area of development for you both.  I will share that I ended up going in a rather different direction with my digipot explorations, but one that turned out to be exciting (to me anyway).  I have an analog fuzz pedal that I made that is built with switching jacks so that I can swap in a digipot instead of the fuzz knob.  What I discovered after playing with it for a while was (1) modulating it with choppy rhythm sequences made something really interesting and new to my ears, and (2) modulating it at audio rates makes the circuit do some strange synthy stuff that was a complete surprise.  So rather than using the digipot for saving settings, I am using it to push an analog fuzz circuit into weirder behaviors that for me have musical qualities.  </p>

<p>I am going crazy at the moment with a big project at work that will be done March 1.  But after that, I am planning to pull together some audio clips and post some updates to the little write-up I have on my website.  The digipot stuff has turned out to be more interesting than I was expecting, and I hope to keep experimenting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/13</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-13</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yep, I thought about similar as well, in my setup, I have 64 preset values for each patch managed through and Arduino, but as I have access to 127 of these, I was thinking of adding extra to control level on the pots of the effect pedal, not only this however, to also incorporate how much of the effect to apply to the audio signal, so the signal will split, one portion to the effect, the other without, by controlling the % split, I control the amount of the effect.<br>Controlling the amount of effect seems very workable, controlling the pot level on the pedal is different because my preference would be a kind of retro fit system, so it could easily be adapted to other pedals. Although I am always thinking about it, it is low priority at the moment, heavily absorbed in making expression pedals, hope to have some pictures soon.<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/12</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 03:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-12</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@timeorspace Tim]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/timeorspace">@timeorspace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The beauty I see with digipots inline with regular pots and an arduino is the ability to save parameters into groups of presets that can later be recalled and used or tweaked with the manual knobs. <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> I've worked on a mock up of this approach which I plan to take further incorporating an lcd screen and LEDs on each knob so you know whether the current setting is above below or on the preset value. Also, no change to the preset value until you go past its set value. I hope I explained this in a way so it is understandable.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 23:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-11</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I've done the splitter blender thing before, well before my Axo adventures, I actually had 3 parallel effects loops of pedals chained together, I had a case as big as a bass guitar case to hold it all together, quite cumbersome. I know as a bass player it definitely turned heads, I had far more effects then the guitarist but there was something about it that worked well. But it was difficult to use, having to change levels in loops, I tried different setups with volume pedals etc. I think it can still be achieved effectively, but would want it setup in a matrix mixer controlled by a microcontroller of sorts.<br>I never chase specific model or pedal types, too expensive for me, I just by cheap second hand ones from pawn shops, its like a lucky dip, you never know quite what you are going to end up with. I did specifically buy a new zoom B3 though.<img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/10</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 21:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-10</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@orbitbot Patrik Johnson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/orbitbot">@orbitbot</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="8" data-topic="3834"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/kat/40/4283_1.png" class="avatar">kat:</div>
<blockquote><p>If you have ever tried the Chase Bliss pedals, I'd be curious to hear reactions.  I've never played one but I've been impressed by what I could tell from the standard youtube demo videos and whatnot.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I haven't had the pleasure, and though I think they're cool, for that money (at least herewards) I'm more looking towards even more comprehensive effects . Likely the Source Audio Nemesis and upcoming Ventris as of today, probably buying these within a few months since they seem like definite keepers and value for money.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/9</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 19:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-9</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@kat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/kat">@kat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the links to add to the discussion, <a class="mention" href="/u/orbitbot">@orbitbot</a>.  That gain scaling discussion is a useful reference and I suspect I'll be back to look at it again in the future also.</p>

<p>If you have ever tried the Chase Bliss pedals, I'd be curious to hear reactions.  I've never played one but I've been impressed by what I could tell from the standard youtube demo videos and whatnot.  </p>

<p>And <a class="mention" href="/u/gavin">@Gavin</a>, keep us posted on your project... I also have an op-amp "splitter-blender" (routes guitar signal to two separate loops with independent gain control) sitting on a breadboard semi-abandoned because I didn't end up creating any sounds with it that were all that exciting.  I liked the <em>idea</em> of blending together two effects in a weird way, but then everything I initially tried just sounded like audio mush.  I have somewhat the same experience trying blending together various processing paths with Axoloti.  The ear (or at least my ear) does not seem to be as responsive to the complexities of sound processing that my brain finds appealing!  But maybe I just have not been creative or smart enough to come up with the right ideas yet...</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/8</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 11:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-8</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Digipots and guitar pedals</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gavin Gavin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/gavin">@Gavin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks All, yes indeed, I need to plunge into the deep end with a small test, being able to control at least two pedals at a time is imperative. I think I will start very simple with only controlling the amount of Audio passing into the pedals in the pedal chain, this will only require 2 digipots, 1 for each pedal, but may also require an op-amp setup of sorts, but I will work all that out as I go along.<br><img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/grin.png?v=5" title=":grin:" class="emoji" alt=":grin:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834/7</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-3834-7</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/digipots-and-guitar-pedals/3834.rss">Digipots and guitar pedals</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
