<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866</link>
    <description>In the past I hinted at the fact that I&#39;ve been developing some technology built around field-programmable analog arrays and several of you expressed interest in the project. As of today it&#39;s officially launched: https://zrna.org/

The site goes into much more depth, but to summarize briefly you can think of it as sort of conceptually similar to Axoloti except that the signal processing all happens on an FPAA. I recommend taking a look at some of the [demos]( https://zrna.org/demos) and the [object library](https://zrna.org/docs/modules). I think it will be clear why this is such an exciting technology!

I&#39;d appreciate your support. Contact me if you have questions.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 21:48:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Lounge</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks very much for that, and actually I think I've confused you as to what I am getting at so first of all I absolutely must stress that when it comes to 'business' I am absolutely understanding your needs and you have my sympathy really, cause it's a real mine-field.</p>

<p>It's not being infected by GPL that concerns me, I'm all for GPL.  What concerns me software-wise is really only the uncertainty as to whether I would have to give-out the Axoloti sketch for my product.  On the one hand, things I have read here and there accross the web, seems to suggest I might have to do that if I were to release my product commercially.  On the other hand, frankly I think it might be complete and utter nonsense because if that were the case, then surely an artist would have to release the unflattened file if they were to commercially release an image created in GIMP or Inkscape, and a blender user would have to release their model if they decided to sell 3D prints of them.</p>

<p>So for that reason it all sounds a bit unlikely to me and I'm banking on the hope that I would not have to release my Axoloti patch just because the end product is released commercially.  Releasing an Axoloti patch in software would be akin to what you are concerned about in hardware, so I am not surprised you don't plan to release manufacture-ready files of the board, Johannes never either, no doubt for the same reason - makes perfect sense.</p>

<p>So my only concern then with your own board is that you explicitly state the correct licence for it on release.  If what you're hoping turns out to be true, and you are able GPL all of it, that's great, but whatever it is, you will have to be <em>very</em> careful and <em>absolutely</em> sure before you explicitly state its licence.</p>

<p>I would do more than speak to a lawyer, I would ensure that the advice given by them is in writing, to include they are accountable for any errors in their advice.  Don't forget that one, it's a biggie and is often omited by slippery lawyers in order to escape accountability for the specialist advice you paid them for.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/24</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 21:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-24</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The issue of Axoloti patch licensing is a separate issue. I think if you wanted to be very literal about it all the objects are GPL (I need to check this, they might be unlicensed. EDIT: the factory object library is indeed GPL, so your patches that use them technically need to comply with the GPL. The contrib objects are not globally licensed but may be licensed by the individual author.). So technically every patch that uses them is probably infected by the GPL so a commerical product would need to release its patches.</p>

<p>You want the API client or patcher layer to be MIT/Apache rather than GPL so it can be used in proprietary products. Like right now you could write something that calls the Zrna API and make a proprietary product out of it, and I would have no way to stop that with licensing (and I wouldn't want to stop it!). With Axoloti that may not be possible technically because of the possible GPL infection.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 20:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-22</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Are you talking more about the hardware or the software? On the hardware, I'm fine to go to the same level as Axoloti which is schematics etc but not full layouts. That's simply to prevent someone from just printing clones directly.</p>

<p>On the software: there's a subtle issue with how the firmware works. It depends indirectly on information derived from a proprietary manufacturer toolchain even though it was all hand optimized and changed. The only thing preventing me from open sourcing everything is the possibility of that manufacturer coming after me for violating the original license of their toolchain. Basically if a lawyer can tell me that I can legally relicense everything GPL without risk, then I will. I suspect that this is the case but I'm taking the paranoid approach for the time being. The firmware is really the most valuable and original part of the project, what ties the entire thing together. </p>

<p>The idea that someone would be somehow be "infected" by just using the device in its current state doesn't make sense to me. The hardware and really any hardware is not explicitly licensed. You can always reverse engineer something from the available information. The firmware is currently just a binary blob with no attached license. So again it could just be taken and used wherever. The rest of the software is all Apache licensed which is more permissive than GPL.</p>

<p>EDIT: reading this again I think that you're confusing the hardware and software licensing. There's also some subtlety with different open source licenses. The GPL is the one that may cause you to have to release your code derived from it. Other open source licenses like MIT and Apache allow code to be used in proprietary products. None of the hardware is actually licensed under anything. You're free to do whatever you want with the information about it that is available, including whatever information you derive from studying the hardware itself.</p>

<blockquote><p>the end user is using part-proprietory stuff</p></blockquote>

<p>This isn't clearly a problem unless you specify more information about what licenses are in use. You could argue that both Raspberry Pi and Arduino result in the user using "part-proprietory stuff." The Pi has some binary blob aspects of the firmware that are not available in source code form. Neither device has complete layout assets available officially. Some of the schematics are not actually complete as well. None of this prevents people from building commercial products around the devices and also cloning them as long as they respect the software licenses of the software that is available in source code form.</p>

<p>Another way to think about this: you could buy an Axoloti Core but load entirely different firmware on it. In that case you wouldn't be affected by the GPL at all. It's like buying a PC that comes with Windows but then loading a differently licensed OS on it instead.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 20:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-21</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@axoman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/axoman">@axoman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="17" data-topic="5866"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/urklang/40/2326_1.png" class="avatar">urklang:</div>
<blockquote><p>My intent is to open source as much as the project as possible ...</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>I hope you don't mind me asking this, but isn't it a requirement that it would all have to be open source?</p>

<p>To be clear, I totally understand you wanting to protect your time invested in order to see a worthy return (and I sincerely hope you do), but wouldn't making only some of it open source mean that the end user is using part-proprietory stuff?</p>

<p>If I were to make a commercially viable product with the current Axo for example, and decided that the physical aspect of the board simply is not viable for my product, then if I'm understanding correctly, I could, if I had the know-how, use Johannes' schematic as a guide to 'roll my own' purpose-made boards as long as I open source my own version of the board.</p>

<p>But if your own board was part-proprietory, I would not be able to do that if I had prototyped my product based on your board.  If that is the case then your board would be no use to me, cause while I'm quite sure I come accross as the village idiot around here, there is actually a very serious businessman inside of me and I'm a lot more savvy in that area than people would ever suspect, and I can tell you without any reservation whatsoever that I totally intended to roll my own boards, guided by Johannes schematic, for use in my own products.</p>

<p>I was under the impression that would be fine as long as I open source my own boards in return, which I am perfectly happy to do.  I'll be honest, it's not just your comment that puzzles me, I see similar statements a heck of a lot in this world of open source, and it always baffles me.</p>

<p>With the best of intentions, we all want to protect our time invested especially if we plan to make a business out of what we produce, but can we really protect it without breaking the rules?</p>

<p>I mean crikey, I am even under the impression that if asked for it, I would be forecd to offer-up the Axoloti sketch of any commercial product I create because it had been created using open source software and hardware.  That to me is much more of a threat to having any chance of selling my product, than open sourcing my own board layout would be.</p>

<p>My own board layout would be purpose made for my own products, basically just a different layout sans the stuff Johannes put on there that I don't need, replaced with the stuff that I do - for use in my own products.</p>

<p>No intention of putting my own boards on the market as Axoloti boards, I only intend them as my own supply for my own products.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 19:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-20</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I did actually. I have a prototype design with four AN231E04 chips and substantially more IO in a "vertical" format like the standard Thonk-style Eurorack jacks (for mounting flat behind a panel). It adds a bit of complexity and expense though. The intent with version 1 is to be a bit more general purpose and standalone, like Arduino or Pi, rather than being specifically bound to Eurorack. There are users that don't have Eurorack systems or are interested in engineering applications outside of music completely. If there's substantial interest in a more Eurorack-specific version, it's something we definitely can do.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 02:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-19</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I wonder if you considered making a Eurorack VCF  module with AN231E04 ?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/18</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 14:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-18</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My intent is to open source as much as the project as possible, hardware and software, while still being able to survive and set myself up to be able to build more projects like this. The right balance there is not always obvious. I'm comfortable releasing schematics, but probably not complete layout files, similar to Axoloti Core's approach. If there are other aspects of the documentation that you'd like to see expanded, let me know.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/17</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 03:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-17</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Will the hardware be open-source? Absent highly detailed documentation, schematics are very useful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/16</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 02:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-16</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Regarding Lokki's question about serial baud rate: by default a serial interface is configured for accepting incoming API calls. We can easily include an option to disable that and switch it to an appropriate configuration for MIDI DIN input. If you take a look at the right half of the board, you'll see the MCU IO that is available (and if you're interested you can look up exactly what MCU feature can be assigned to each pin). Again by default most of that IO configured to accept incoming API calls on the various interfaces. All of those pins can easily be reassigned as needed.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/15</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 23:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-15</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the feedback everyone. I think it will be useful to add a section on resource usage for each module in the module library documentation, so it's more intuitive to get a sense of how complex running circuits can be. Currently this is something that is visible at runtime while you're developing a circuit.</p>

<p>This is sort of analogous to how Axoloti keeps track of DSP load except that each running module on Zrna, like a gain stage or a lowpass filter section, etc. uses a discrete amount of hardware resources. An inverting gain stage uses a single opamp for example (1 out of the 8 available). There is no direct concept of DSP load because everything is happening in the analog domain. If you need more headroom for a more complicated design, you can simply chain the devices together.</p>

<p>My sense is that building a simple analog mastering device is well within the realm of possibility. It depends on how complex each part in the FX chain is.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/14</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 23:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-14</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>from the Zrna Quickstart:</p>

<p>Unsurprisingly, the Zrna board has finite hardware resources. The analog array section consists of four comparators, eight opamps, switched-capacitors and some auxiliary hardware.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/13</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 16:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-13</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blindsmyth Simon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/blindsmyth">@Blindsmyth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This looks very intriguing, great work! </p>

<p>I've always wanted to have an analog "mastering" device after my axoloti setup, with eq, multibandcompressor and limiter. Would this be possible to make with your board?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/12</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 14:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-12</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>thinking further, you write that there is a serial in on the board. if this can be configured for 31250 baud rate, then i can build the optocoupler midi input myself (done that multiple times for arduino) so the serial input/output baudrate can be run at midi baud rate?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 12:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-11</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote" data-post="9" data-topic="5866"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/urklang/40/2326_1.png" class="avatar">urklang:</div>
<blockquote><p>Technically MIDI DIN could be supported directly on the board itself directly into a serial port with a breakout board and if there is enough demand, we can add that feature.</p></blockquote></aside>

<p>i think this would be a very important addendum indeed. for me midi input would suffice but i would guess midi out for a cv to midi converter could also be very handy. being able to use the device standalone (without an axoloti or computer or PI) is a must for me since i would use this on a stage and i don't want to carry a pc there or use an axoloti just for midi rerouting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/10</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 11:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-10</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The board works as a normal class compliant USB MIDI device, so any means of moving between old school MIDI DIN and USB MIDI is just fine. For example it could be plugged into Axoloti's USB host port and you could use Axoloti's DIN ports or into a host computer that has an audio interface with MIDI DIN. Technically MIDI DIN could be supported directly on the board itself directly into a serial port with a breakout board and if there is enough demand, we can add that feature. Some of my users are outside of the audio domain completely so it made sense to not encumber the design with full size din ports or a separate host port.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/9</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 07:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-9</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>really nice!<br>how would one add an old-school midi din input (or output) or an usb-host plug? arduino?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/8</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-8</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I appreciate the kind words everybody. Regarding dimensions: I'll add this to the site but the board is 77mm x 30mm which for comparison is about half the length of an Axoloti and about 60% of the width. Axo core is 160 x 50 mm. Will clarify power requirements there as well: the short answer is that it is designed to run off of standard USB bus power and supplies; the rough worst case current consumption is about 125mA.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 23:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-7</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@weasel79 blender]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/weasel79">@weasel79</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh you're right. i somehow managed to ignore the giant shop button...</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 20:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-6</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Website suggests they’re ready to sell now.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-5</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@weasel79 blender]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/weasel79">@weasel79</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Man i just glanced over it and this looks really promising! Incredible work on your part for sure, hats off. From what i understood it now mainly comes down to how you actualy analogg components/modules sound? audio demos are great already.</p>

<p>whats happens in these circuits if i overdrive a signal? if i go into one of the opamp with a voltage higher than expected?</p>

<p>very curious to see some more applications for it. do you plan to make units available to others anytime soon?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 17:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-4</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tele_player]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/tele_player">@tele_player</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Very interesting gadget!<br>Suggestions: specs for power requirements, physical dimensions.<br>Some idea of limitations: how complex a circuit can the chip implement?</p>

<p>Edit: I found the Quickstart section on Hardware Resources.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 14:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-3</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MattilynMattroe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/mattilynmattroe">@MattilynMattroe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This looks really cool!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 13:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-2</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Zrna - Software-defined analog</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@urklang Nicolas Steven Miller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/urklang">@urklang</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In the past I hinted at the fact that I've been developing some technology built around field-programmable analog arrays and several of you expressed interest in the project. As of today it's officially launched: <a href="https://zrna.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://zrna.org/</a></p>

<p>The site goes into much more depth, but to summarize briefly you can think of it as sort of conceptually similar to Axoloti except that the signal processing all happens on an FPAA. I recommend taking a look at some of the <a href="https://zrna.org/demos" rel="nofollow noopener">demos</a> and the <a href="https://zrna.org/docs/modules" rel="nofollow noopener">object library</a>. I think it will be clear why this is such an exciting technology!</p>

<p>I'd appreciate your support. Contact me if you have questions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 13:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-5866-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/zrna-software-defined-analog/5866.rss">Zrna - Software-defined analog</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
