<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755</link>
    <description>Hi, since i found the push axoloti scripts, i got really excited to use it as a midi controller for my squarp pyramid instead of a master keyboard. my friend is using my push so cant try this right now, But in general, i want to use the axoloti as an interface for the push, just notes, velocity and at, but i also want to make a midi controller for the analog rytms &quot;performance control&quot; cc&#39;s with the axoloti and some potentiometers on the analog inputs. and then i also want to use the axo as a synth of some kind, so im gonna route midi back to the axoloti from the pyramid.

so i guess this is pretty much possible,i know the pyramid can do what it needs to do, but been i while since i messed around in the axo so just looking for some input/fedback. 

Could it be a bad idea to merge midi from the push and the analo in pots?

&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/default/original/2X/6/66e72e0140d44a8738467e9a1a856046eea98f63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;388&quot;&gt;</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:48:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hardware</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Mleysens Mari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/mleysens">@Mleysens</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Can someone post the link to the post with these scripts? My search did not find them and ai dont see one in this thread</p>

<p>Thx</p>

<p>.m</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4755-5</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755.rss">Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mah Måns Henriksson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/mah">@mah</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I Been reading the the thread about the push quite a few times <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> posted this mostly because of the back and forth midi routing and that midi thru was not optimal, but that was a misread from my side, so nvm. </p>

<p>But thx for the response, always reassuring. Can't wait to get my push back to do some more tests, the main reason to use the push is the the pads, gonna use it as a glorified keyboard for note input in the pyramid, much more compact than a regular keyboard, and nice to have the scale feature.</p>

<p>So the way it works now is perfect tbh, and the axo would have plenty of power left to make some  noise! And could be controlled by the push encoders, leaving all the analog ins to be used as a midi controller for the analog rytm.</p>

<p>The one problem I remember about the push object was that the encoders sent out note values when touched, Which I guess is not how it should behave. I probably set the internal midi wrong in some way. And I guess it's hard for you to test it, but if you have any idea what's causing it I would be grateful.</p>

<p>Btw, to bad that the update would break this, would be nice if someone would keep this alive as my coding does not go further then the most basic HTML..</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4755-4</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755.rss">Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>sure, this should work...</p>

<p>however:<br>please note, the Push stuff i did was never 100% completed, as during its development Ableton launched the Push 2, with a trade-in offer, so I took that... so I didn't have a push 1 to work with (and the Push2 does not work due to being usb 2.0) <br>I hoped one day to pick up a cheap push 1 again for axoloti (and other projects) , but unfortunately (for me!) they actually have retained their value pretty well - so its not happened yet.</p>

<p>anyway, as far as i remember it should work, just things like the parameter display are not as good as they could be.<br>(and Im pretty sure, when the next version of the Axoloti software comes out, it will break this!) </p>

<hr>

<p>Pyramid works nicely with it, you can even power the pyramid from the axoloti, if you use the usb port.<br>when i got the Pyramid initially, I did a few tests with this, as it seems like a great combo<br>not only, could you use the Axoloti for voices - but you could also use it to given you another midi din in and out.<br>(and as you have already noted, a USB host port) </p>

<p>unfortunately, I got distracted (*), and never got around to setting it up properly...</p>

<p>so if you create a patch, let me know... it would be an awesome partner to the pyramid.</p>

<p>(*) I started looking into writing a FM drum synth to use on Axoloti for the Pyramid, and that led to all sorts of other ideas, which... and I lost my focus   (not an uncommon thing for me <img src="//community.axoloti.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> )</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4755-3</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755.rss">Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lokki]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/lokki">@lokki</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>should all work! (from axoloti side, can't comment on the other two machines down the line)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 20:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4755-2</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755.rss">Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mah Måns Henriksson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/mah">@mah</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi, since i found the push axoloti scripts, i got really excited to use it as a midi controller for my squarp pyramid instead of a master keyboard. my friend is using my push so cant try this right now, But in general, i want to use the axoloti as an interface for the push, just notes, velocity and at, but i also want to make a midi controller for the analog rytms "performance control" cc's with the axoloti and some potentiometers on the analog inputs. and then i also want to use the axo as a synth of some kind, so im gonna route midi back to the axoloti from the pyramid.</p>

<p>so i guess this is pretty much possible,i know the pyramid can do what it needs to do, but been i while since i messed around in the axo so just looking for some input/fedback. </p>

<p>Could it be a bad idea to merge midi from the push and the analo in pots?</p>

<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a data-download-href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/66e72e0140d44a8738467e9a1a856046eea98f63" href="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/original/2X/6/66e72e0140d44a8738467e9a1a856046eea98f63.jpg" class="lightbox" title="midisheet.jpg"><img src="//community.axoloti.com/uploads/default/optimized/2X/6/66e72e0140d44a8738467e9a1a856046eea98f63_1_690x388.jpg" width="690" height="388"><div class="meta">
<span class="filename">midisheet.jpg</span><span class="informations">1920x1080 689 KB</span><span class="expand"></span>
</div></a></div></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 19:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4755-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/midi-routing-push-pyramid-analog-rytm/4755.rss">Midi routing (push, pyramid, analog rytm)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
