<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Axoloti Software Releases</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82</link>
    <description>#Current Version
**28 Aug 2016 - 1.0.11**
more details here : http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-release-1-0-11

https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases/latest

(runtime is unchanged since version 1.0.2)

#Pre-release 
current pre-release available for testing:  None
Note: if you are using a pre-release, please read the following post to understand what pre-releases are for, what to expect and what we expect.

#Obtaining software
All software is available from:  [https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases][1]

LATEST RELEASE, The latest supported and stable version is clearly labeled, this is the version most people should use.

PRE RELEASE versions are current development versions, usually these are NOT supported, unless we explicitly detail them there as &quot;release candidates&quot;, these are used when we want wider testing prior to a &quot;public release&quot;, or to allow some users to test a feature in development. They should not be used for performance or as the basis for review.
(of course, you are free to play with these versions, but recognise its &quot;work in progress&quot; ) 

A new release will always contain changes to the application software (Axoloti) including  UI / Firmware /Demo patches, and will need to be downloaded and installed on each new release. 

The axoloti runtime contains fairly static elements including the cross-compiler we use. This may not change form release to release. If axoloti runtime has changed, and needs to be downloaded and re-installed, the release notes will indicate this.


#Installation
Please read the following for information on installing on the supported platforms.

- [Installing on Windows](/t/installing-on-windows)
- [Installing on Mac OS X](t/installing-on-mac-os-x)
- [Installing on Linux](t/installing-on-linux)

#Support
If you have any issues downloading, installing or using the software, please make a post in the [Helpdesk](/c/helpdesk)

#Change History
[on the github releases page](https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases/)

  [1]: https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 10:55:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Software</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-software-releases/82.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti Software Releases</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-software-releases/82/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 10:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-82-6</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82.rss">Axoloti Software Releases</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti Software Releases</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h2>Pre-releases</h2>

<p>Occasionally pre-releases of the software may be released, these are released to the community for 'beta testing' and early feedback on features.</p>

<p>As the version is is still in active development it is quite likely it will have limitations, or features incomplete, or features that may not be released, or changed for release and possibly still known bugs, so should not be used for any thing other than testing.</p>

<p>Also it is <strong>possible</strong> that the preferences file and even objects/patches that it produces could be incompatible with the final release version. so please keep backups of these. <br>(we of course will try to limit this, and if it happens we will try to provide solutions)</p>

<p>We would advise users to use 'versioned home' directories, so that you are able to run pre-releaes alongside the production release, more details <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/running-multiple-versions-of-axoloti/2190">here</a></p>

<p>Any issues/feedback on these should be reported in posts, clearly labelled as 'beta' in the topic title, so that it is clear to others that this is not for the released software.<br>(its likely we will create a pre-release thread for general feedback) </p>

<p>Of course, we want as many users to try the pre-releases as possible this greatly helps our testing efforts and provides useful early feedback on new features.</p>

<h2>Building from directly from source in Github</h2>

<p>Our general expectation is that this is only done by users with some development experience, as we have limited resources to support users setting up development environments, or the oddities that may come from building software.</p>

<p>Therefore it is generally <strong>not</strong> recommend for non-developers to access new functionality, we would prefer you wait for pre-releases.<br>(of course we recognise for some non-supported platforms this may be a necessary evil, and will help as much as possible) </p>

<p>The source code in the github repository is active development code. In particular the master branch is the main line development (though sometimes we may make use of feature branches).</p>

<p>(yes, we are fully aware of how to use branching, and feature release branch to minimise this... and will do this where we think its appropriate)</p>

<p>This means it is highly likely that the code may contain experimental features, and existing features may not be currently working correctly (as they are in-flux due to new developments), and whilst we try to keep the development branch as stable as possible, at any point in time there may be major issues introduced, which we cannot guarantee a timeline for fixing (except it will be before release <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/slight_smile.png?v=2" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> )</p>

<p>It is also <strong>very</strong> possible that the preferences file created will be incompatible with the release versions, and also possibly patches and objects. <br>(we will not provide upgrade paths through development  to release versions only from release to release.)</p>

<p><strong>if you are using a development or pre-release and you encounter issues, its is vital if you find issue you provide detailed bug reports... this will help us deliver high quality 'official releases'</strong><br>please review our <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/reporting-issues-bugs/21">bug reporting guidelines</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-software-releases/82/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 10:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-82-5</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82.rss">Axoloti Software Releases</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Axoloti Software Releases</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h1>Current Version</h1>

<p><strong>28 Aug 2016 - 1.0.11</strong><br>more details here : <a href="//community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-release-1-0-11">http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-release-1-0-11</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases/latest" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases/latest</a></p>

<p>(runtime is unchanged since version 1.0.2)</p>

<h1>Pre-release</h1>

<p>current pre-release available for testing:  None<br>Note: if you are using a pre-release, please read the following post to understand what pre-releases are for, what to expect and what we expect.</p>

<h1>Obtaining software</h1>

<p>All software is available from:  <a href="https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases" rel="nofollow">https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases</a></p>

<p>LATEST RELEASE, The latest supported and stable version is clearly labeled, this is the version most people should use.</p>

<p>PRE RELEASE versions are current development versions, usually these are NOT supported, unless we explicitly detail them there as "release candidates", these are used when we want wider testing prior to a "public release", or to allow some users to test a feature in development. They should not be used for performance or as the basis for review.<br>(of course, you are free to play with these versions, but recognise its "work in progress" ) </p>

<p>A new release will always contain changes to the application software (Axoloti) including  UI / Firmware /Demo patches, and will need to be downloaded and installed on each new release. </p>

<p>The axoloti runtime contains fairly static elements including the cross-compiler we use. This may not change form release to release. If axoloti runtime has changed, and needs to be downloaded and re-installed, the release notes will indicate this.</p>

<h1>Installation</h1>

<p>Please read the following for information on installing on the supported platforms.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="/t/installing-on-windows">Installing on Windows</a></li>
<li><a>Installing on Mac OS X</a></li>
<li><a>Installing on Linux</a></li>
</ul>

<h1>Support</h1>

<p>If you have any issues downloading, installing or using the software, please make a post in the <a href="/c/helpdesk">Helpdesk</a></p>

<h1>Change History</h1>

<p><a href="https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases/" rel="nofollow">on the github releases page</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/axoloti-software-releases/82/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-82-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/axoloti-software-releases/82.rss">Axoloti Software Releases</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
