<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Patch analysis research</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979</link>
    <description>Hi folks,

For the last several years, I&#39;ve been working on theoretical computer science research in the context of a PhD thesis, and in particular in graph grammars and graph languages. It&#39;s very theoretical, and is mostly motivated by semantic graphs used in natural language processing (e.g. automated translation, semantic analyses and computer understanding of language etc.).

However, now that I&#39;m nearing the completion of the thesis, I&#39;ve been thinking of other ways to use my formalisms, and especially of ways to tie them to music, as that is quite a deep interest of mine.

Turns out, modular synth patches are a pretty good candidate for things to muck around with using graph formalisms, and Axoloti patches are both numerous, nicely contained, and relatively easy to analyse using my code.

Now for the tricky question: Can I publish results based on public data released through the Axoloti factory and contrib libraries? Now, the analyses I&#39;ve made so far are relatively simple and highly aggregated (I&#39;m checking how many of all the patches fulfil a certain property, essentially), and I&#39;m pretty sure I can construct my own minimal examples of any particularly interesting structures I encounter, and I&#39;ll not publish _anything_ i&#39;m not 100% clear should be OK not only legally, but ethically.

But I&#39;d also like _your_ input. What&#39;s your take on the above?

I&#39;m highly open to explaining what I&#39;m planning to do, and what I&#39;ve done, at any level you&#39;re comfortable with, from the basics of theoretical computer science and automata theory to the deep technicalities of the specific formalism, and obviously also including any analyses I&#39;ve done or plan to do on the patches.

Cheers

Petter Ericson
PhD Student at the Department of Computing Science, Umeå University</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 21:12:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Patching</category>
    <atom:link href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Patch analysis research</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SmashedTransistors]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/smashedtransistors">@SmashedTransistors</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You can use my patches (under /tiar/ in the library).</p>

<p>I think that one interest is that some patches have feedback loops (especially reverb and delay ones).<br>Short feedback are more common at small scale, inside the modules (phase accumulators, filter feedback loops).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 21:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4979-2</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979.rss">Patch analysis research</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Patch analysis research</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pettter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/u/pettter">@pettter</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi folks,</p>

<p>For the last several years, I've been working on theoretical computer science research in the context of a PhD thesis, and in particular in graph grammars and graph languages. It's very theoretical, and is mostly motivated by semantic graphs used in natural language processing (e.g. automated translation, semantic analyses and computer understanding of language etc.).</p>

<p>However, now that I'm nearing the completion of the thesis, I've been thinking of other ways to use my formalisms, and especially of ways to tie them to music, as that is quite a deep interest of mine.</p>

<p>Turns out, modular synth patches are a pretty good candidate for things to muck around with using graph formalisms, and Axoloti patches are both numerous, nicely contained, and relatively easy to analyse using my code.</p>

<p>Now for the tricky question: Can I publish results based on public data released through the Axoloti factory and contrib libraries? Now, the analyses I've made so far are relatively simple and highly aggregated (I'm checking how many of all the patches fulfil a certain property, essentially), and I'm pretty sure I can construct my own minimal examples of any particularly interesting structures I encounter, and I'll not publish <em>anything</em> i'm not 100% clear should be OK not only legally, but ethically.</p>

<p>But I'd also like <em>your</em> input. What's your take on the above?</p>

<p>I'm highly open to explaining what I'm planning to do, and what I've done, at any level you're comfortable with, from the basics of theoretical computer science and automata theory to the deep technicalities of the specific formalism, and obviously also including any analyses I've done or plan to do on the patches.</p>

<p>Cheers</p>

<p>Petter Ericson<br>PhD Student at the Department of Computing Science, Umeå University</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 16:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-4979-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/patch-analysis-research/4979.rss">Patch analysis research</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
