<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Common installation problems</title>
    <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/common-installation-problems/139</link>
    <description>So we are starting to get some experience of users installing Axoloti, this thread will detail some common issues and suggestions if you have issue.
(note: Im not going to include,  pre-release/prototype boards - only production boards with 1.0 firmware)


----------

1. **Read the relevant installation guide.**
I know, Im guilty of not reading installation/user guides -  but Axoloti is a little different it **IS** worth it. It will get you up and running faster, and if your turning to this thread, because you have an issue... go back and check the guide :) 
Im continually updating the installation guides to ensure they are correct, Ive also verified them on clean machines for all platforms. 
If you find a mistake in the user guide, let me know and I will correct it.

1. **Download and Install the axoloti runtime**
This  is the #1 mistake (it is covered in the installation guides) 
You just download and install the Axoloti App and your done, right? 
**Wrong!**  - Axoloti needs the runtime files, which are a separate install.
(I know we want a one click install too... but we have technical reasons for requiring axoloti_runtime to be installed separately)
If when you start the application you get the message (in the console)
&lt;code&gt; Runtime directory is invalid:C:\Program Files (x86)\axoloti_runtime, is the runtime installed? correctly?&lt;/code&gt;
(directory is different on each platform, check installation guide for details).
This means that the runtime has not been found in the location expected, so please refer to the relevant installation guide and ensure it is placed where it should be.

1. **Plugging in Axoloti via USB #1**
If Axoloti is not detected, try another USB port on the computer.
yes, this can be a problem... on an early iMac I have, on one of the USB ports Axoloti is not seen... and I know the USB port works (at least for some devices). Ive not worked out why yet, could be internal hub conflict/power requirements, but demonstrates the need to try other USB ports!

1. **Plugging in Axoloti via USB #2**
We don&#39;t have any reports of issues with Axoloti compatibility, but normal support advice.
If Axoloti is not being detected, or is acting unexpectedly... then please try plugging in Axoloti directly into the PC/Mac without using a USB hub, and remove all other USB devices.  (except keyboard and mouse :) ). If it starts working then introduce one device/hub at a time, to find the &#39;culprit&#39;
Its very unlikely to be the cause BUT its best to eliminate this as a possibility...
Of course, still report the issue in the [Helpdesk](/c/helpdesk) and let us know that you have tried this, and any device that seems to be causing a conflict.  (we may or may not be able to do something to fix, but its valuable information for all users)

1. **USB Cables**
Faulty USB cables are not uncommon, so if Axoloti appears not to connect try another cable first!
Also, take care... **many Micro USB cables are power only, no data!** so cannot be used to connect Axoloti to your PC/Mac.  (i.e. you will see Axoloti board has power, but you cannot connect to it)
This is because many phones use microUSB as a charging connection only, and its becoming increasingly common since the EU voted to force phone manufactures to use microUSB charging from 2016!

1. **Windows 7, XP, Vista  only**
May not have the necessary windows drivers installed or available via Windows Update, if when you connect the Axoloti Core it cannot find the drivers download here is a link to where you can download them.
(note: try first, its quite possible you will already have the WinUSB driver installed for other products etc, its a common driver)

http://community.axoloti.com/t/win-7-no-usb-found-with-matching-pid-vid/117/22


----------


thats its, other than that it seems the majority have no issues installing and getting going.
of course, if you do encounter issues please let us know, and then we can try to improve the installation process, or let new users know of things to be aware of.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 12:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Helpdesk</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/common-installation-problems/139.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Common installation problems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/common-installation-problems/139/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/common-installation-problems/139/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 09:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-139-5</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/common-installation-problems/139.rss">Common installation problems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Common installation problems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thetechnobear Mark Harris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/u/thetechnobear">@thetechnobear</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So we are starting to get some experience of users installing Axoloti, this thread will detail some common issues and suggestions if you have issue.<br>(note: Im not going to include,  pre-release/prototype boards - only production boards with 1.0 firmware)</p>

<hr>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Read the relevant installation guide.</strong><br>I know, Im guilty of not reading installation/user guides -  but Axoloti is a little different it <strong>IS</strong> worth it. It will get you up and running faster, and if your turning to this thread, because you have an issue... go back and check the guide <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/smile.png?v=0" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt="smile"> <br>Im continually updating the installation guides to ensure they are correct, Ive also verified them on clean machines for all platforms. <br>If you find a mistake in the user guide, let me know and I will correct it.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Download and Install the axoloti runtime</strong><br>This  is the #1 mistake (it is covered in the installation guides) <br>You just download and install the Axoloti App and your done, right? <br><strong>Wrong!</strong>  - Axoloti needs the runtime files, which are a separate install.<br>(I know we want a one click install too... but we have technical reasons for requiring axoloti_runtime to be installed separately)<br>If when you start the application you get the message (in the console)<br><code> Runtime directory is invalid:C:\Program Files (x86)\axoloti_runtime, is the runtime installed? correctly?</code><br>(directory is different on each platform, check installation guide for details).<br>This means that the runtime has not been found in the location expected, so please refer to the relevant installation guide and ensure it is placed where it should be.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Plugging in Axoloti via USB #1</strong><br>If Axoloti is not detected, try another USB port on the computer.<br>yes, this can be a problem... on an early iMac I have, on one of the USB ports Axoloti is not seen... and I know the USB port works (at least for some devices). Ive not worked out why yet, could be internal hub conflict/power requirements, but demonstrates the need to try other USB ports!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Plugging in Axoloti via USB #2</strong><br>We don't have any reports of issues with Axoloti compatibility, but normal support advice.<br>If Axoloti is not being detected, or is acting unexpectedly... then please try plugging in Axoloti directly into the PC/Mac without using a USB hub, and remove all other USB devices.  (except keyboard and mouse <img src="/images/emoji/emoji_one/smile.png?v=0" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt="smile"> ). If it starts working then introduce one device/hub at a time, to find the 'culprit'<br>Its very unlikely to be the cause BUT its best to eliminate this as a possibility...<br>Of course, still report the issue in the <a href="/c/helpdesk">Helpdesk</a> and let us know that you have tried this, and any device that seems to be causing a conflict.  (we may or may not be able to do something to fix, but its valuable information for all users)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>USB Cables</strong><br>Faulty USB cables are not uncommon, so if Axoloti appears not to connect try another cable first!<br>Also, take care... <strong>many Micro USB cables are power only, no data!</strong> so cannot be used to connect Axoloti to your PC/Mac.  (i.e. you will see Axoloti board has power, but you cannot connect to it)<br>This is because many phones use microUSB as a charging connection only, and its becoming increasingly common since the EU voted to force phone manufactures to use microUSB charging from 2016!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Windows 7, XP, Vista  only</strong><br>May not have the necessary windows drivers installed or available via Windows Update, if when you connect the Axoloti Core it cannot find the drivers download here is a link to where you can download them.<br>(note: try first, its quite possible you will already have the WinUSB driver installed for other products etc, its a common driver)</p></li>
</ol>

<aside class="quote" data-topic="117" data-slug="win-7-no-usb-found-with-matching-pid-vid" data-post="22"><div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//community.axoloti.com/user_avatar/community.axoloti.com/johannes/40/8_1.png" class="avatar">johannes:</div>
<blockquote><p>Apparently Windows Update does not provide the driver on XP, Vista and Windows 7. Use winusbcompat.zip, which I added here: <a href="https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases" rel="nofollow"></a><a href="https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases" rel="nofollow">https://github.com/axoloti/axoloti/releases</a> Extract, and point windows to the extracted location when it asks for a driver after plugging in.   Windows 8 and later do not need it.</p></blockquote></aside>

<hr>

<p>thats its, other than that it seems the majority have no issues installing and getting going.<br>of course, if you do encounter issues please let us know, and then we can try to improve the installation process, or let new users know of things to be aware of.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://sebiik.github.io/community.axoloti.com.backup/t/common-installation-problems/139/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://community.axoloti.com/t/common-installation-problems/139/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 12:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.axoloti.com-post-139-1</guid>
        <source url="http://community.axoloti.com/t/common-installation-problems/139.rss">Common installation problems</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
